We're going to look now at the greedy approach for optimization problems.
So we're going to take a locally optimal move.
In particular, we have a partial solution and we're going to take
the optimal move for the next step and the question is,
when does this approach lead to the global optimum?
Now, we saw earlier for the knapsack problem,
that this greedy approach doesn't work.
There are examples where the greedy does not lead to the optimal solution.
Nevertheless, we were able to use dynamic programming
to find the optimal solution for the knapsack problem.
What we're going to work on now,
is the minimum spanning tree problem and we're going to see that for this problem,
that the greedy approach does work,
as a particular algorithm that we're going to use for
the minimum spanning tree problem is the Kruskal's algorithm.
Many of you may have seen Kruskal's algorithm before,
but the important thing that we're going to stress in this lecture,
is the proof of correctness of Kruskal's algorithm for the minimum spanning tree problem.
Why exactly does the greedy approach work for this problem?
We're going to see a general lemma known as the cut property.
This lemma is going to imply that
Kruskal's algorithm works correctly for the minimum spanning tree problem.
And it's important that we understand the statement of
the cut property and also the proof has some useful ideas that I want you to understand.
And we're going to see is a nice byproduct of this general lemma.
We're also going to see that Prim's algorithm for
the minimum spanning tree problem also works correctly.
So, this general lemma implies that Kruskal's algorithm
works correctly and Prim's algorithm works correctly.
Let me remind you of the precise formulation of the minimum spanning
tree problem and then we'll look at the general formulation of the cut property,
its statement and its proof,
and then we'll see that it immediately implies that
Kruskal's algorithm works correctly and Prim's algorithm work.