The input to the minimum spanning tree problem,
also known as the MST problem,
is an undirected graph, G,
and each edge, E, has a weight w(e).
Our goal is to find the subgraph of minimal size which is still connected.
Now the connected subgraph of minimal size is of course a tree.
We call it a spanning tree to stress the fact that it's connected,
that it's a tree and not a forest.
And we want to find such a subgraph of minimum weight.
In summary, our goal is to find the minimum weight spanning tree of
G. And just to remind you what do we mean by minimum weight,
well, for a particular tree, T,
its weight is the sum of the weights of the edges in that tree.