Before we give the statement of the cut property,
let's do a little bit of terminology.
Here again is our running example of a graph.
In general, we have an undirected graph,
G and a cut of the graph is a set of edges which partition the vertices into two sets,
S and the complement of S. So for a particular set S,
the cut edges are those edges with one endpoint in S and the other endpoint in S bar.
In words, what are the cut edges?
The cut edges are the edges crossing between S and S bar.
Let's take a look at a particular cut in this graph.
So I partitioned it into S and S bar.
Now what are the cut edges?
The cut edges are the five edges which are crossing between S and S bar.
These five edges are the cut S, S bar.
Later in the course, we're going to look at various optimization problems involving cuts.
We're going to try to find a minimum cut.
So the fewest number of edges in order
to disconnect the graph into at least two components.
And we're also going to look at the max cut problem
where we're trying to find the cut of largest size.
But for now we're just looking at the general notion of what is a cut.
So to summarize, if I give you a set S and S bar,
then the cut S, S bar is a set of edges crossing between S and S bar.