Now let's first prove that T prime is a tree.
How do we construct T prime once again?
We took the tree T and we added it in this edge e* that created a cycle.
Now, along that cycle we removed any edge of that cycle.
In this case we removed, let's say,
this edge and let's call it e prime.
What we're going to show now is that we can remove any edge of
this cycle and this result in graph T prime will be a tree.
Now, how are we going to show that the prime is a tree?
Well, we're going to show that T prime is connected and it has exactly n-1 edges.
Now, if you recall from the beginning of the lecture,
we said that if a sub graph has
exactly n-1 edges and is connected then it must be a tree.
Now the fact that it has exactly n-1 edges is obvious.
Why? Because T is a tree so it has exactly n-1 edges,
we added one edge in and removed one edge.
So we still have exactly n-1 edges.
So what remains? We just have to show that it's connected.
So take any pair of vertices y and z and let's show
that there's a path between y and z in this sub graph T prime.
I chose a particular y and z in this example.
So y is over here and z is over here.
Now noticing T, there is a path between y and z of course because T is connected.
The path goes along this edge e prime.
Now what happens in T prime?
When T prime, I've removed this edge e prime.
So this old path between y and z no longer exists in T prime.
So let's let P denote the path from y to z in T in
the original tree T. And now we have to construct
a path in T prime which goes from y to z.
Now, recall that when we looked at TUe* what do we get?
We got a cycle, these blue edges are the cycle in TUe*.
So let C denote the cycle in TUe*.
Let's denote the end points of e prime as c and d. Now e prime is a path from c
to d in T. Now this cycle C has two paths between c and d,
e prime is one of those paths,
let's take the other path.
So let's look at this cycle C and take out the edge e prime, what do we have?
We have a path and this path goes from c to d and all these edges in this path,
exist in T prime because T prime contains
all these edges except for e prime but we're not using e prime, we took e prime out.
So we took the cycle,
dropped off the edge e prime and this gives us a path from c to d in T prime.
So, how do we get from y to z in T prime?
Well, we're going to follow the original path P for whenever we hit this edge e prime,
we replace this edge e prime by this new path P prime.
Now, to show that y and z are connected in T prime.
So we want to show that there is a path from y to z in T prime.
Well, we're going to use the original path in T
and then whenever we hit the edge e prime,
we're going to replace the edge e prime by this path P prime because
the edge e prime does not exist in T prime but the path P prime does exist.
So we're going to go along this path and now
the original path uses this edge e prime but it doesn't
exist now so we use the rest of the cycle.
It gets over to d and then from d we follow the rest of the path P. So,
actually, in this example we're backtracking.
So this doesn't actually give us a path, it gives us a walk.
But it shows that y and z are connected in T prime and then,
of course, we can truncate this walk to make a path.
But our whole point is to show that y and z are connected and that's all we need to show.
We've shown that's the case for any y and z therefore,
T prime is connected and since it has exactly n-1 edges then T prime is in fact a tree.