Now once again we have this subgraph T prime which is obtained by taking
the tree T adding in this edge e star and taking out the edge e prime.
We've just showed that T prime is a tree and once again,
notice that we could have removed any edge of
this cycle and we would have attained a tree.
But now we want to show that it's a minimum spanning tree.
How do we show it's of minimum way?
Well you know that T is an MST,
so we know that the weight of T is a minimum over all trees.
So to show that T prime is a minimum spanning tree,
we have to show that the weight of T prime equals the weight of T. What do
we know about the weight of each star compared to that of e prime?
Well, we know that the weight of each star is minimum over all edges cross the cut,
e prime also crosses the cut as the s spur therefore,
the way to e star is the most that of the weight of e prime.
Now what is the weight of T prime?
It's the weight of T plus the weight of e star
and then finally minus the weight of e prime.
The weight of e star is the most the weight of e prime so this part is almost zero.
So this whole thing is at most the weight of T. So we've shown that
the weight of T prime is the most of the weight of T T is minimum weight,
therefore T prime is also a minimum weight and in fact,
the weight of T prime must equal the weight of
T. So the weight of e star must equal the weight of e prime.
Otherwise we retrain the new tree T prime which is strictly smaller weight than t,
which would contradict the fact that T is an MST.
So all these edges of T which cross this cut,
must be of exactly the same weight as e star otherwise,
we can obtain a new tree which is of smaller weight.
That completes the proof of the cut property.
Now the key idea that I want to stress,
is that I can take a tree T and I add an edge into
that tree so I take T union e star that creates a cycle.
Now I can remove any edge of that cycle and I get a new tree T prime.
Now that's the idea that I wanted to get from the proof of the cut property.
The other idea I want you to get,
is the idea from the statement of the cut property.
From the statement of the cut property,
I want you to get the idea that a minimum weight edge across the cut is part of a MST.
Those are the two key ideas I want you to get from the statement of
the cut property and the proof idea of the cut property.