We're looking at this random variable W sub J,
which takes value 1 or 0 depending on whether
the clause Cj is satisfied or not by the random assignment.
We want to analyze the expectation of W sub J.
So we take the two possible values weighted by the probability of achieving that value.
So, we have value 1 times the probability that
Wj equals 1 plus 0 times the probability Wj equals zero.
That clearly, this term goes away and we're left with the probability Wj equals 1.
This is the beauty of considering a random variable which takes value 0 or 1.
The expectation is simply the probability that that random variable equals value 1.
Now, considering a sample of clause Cj, suppose this x1,
or x2 bar, or x3 bar,
or x4 and so on up to xK.
So the clause has size K. Now,
in order to achieve value 1,
the clause has to be satisfied.
Let's look at the compliment.
What's the probability the clause is not satisfied?
Now, in order to not satisfy this clause,
we have to set x1 to false,
x2 to true, x3 to true and so on.
That's exactly one setting of these variables,
these K variables, so that this clause is not satisfied.
The chance x1 is set to false is one-half.
The chance that x1 is set to false and x2 is set to true and x3 is set to true and so on,
so these K variables are set exactly to this one assignment.
The probability of that one assignment is 2 to the minus
K. That's the probability that this clause is not satisfied.
What's the probability that is satisfied is a compliment of that,
so it's 1 minus that.
The probability that Wj equals 1 is equal to 1 minus 2 to the minus K. Now,
notice something interesting, this gets better as K grows.
The worst case is when K equals 1,
it's a unit clause.
So, suppose it's just x1,
then what's the probability this clause does not satisfy
is one-half and the probability it is satisfied is one-half.
So, this quantity is always at least one-half. Since K is