We're going to have a constraint for every clause.
Let's take an example clause to get some idea of what we want to achieve.
Consider this clause X5,
or X3, or X6.
We made all the literals positive in order to make it a simple example.
Now, what do we want from our constraint?
What we want that if these variables are set to false.
Now, setting X5 to false is going to correspond to setting Y5 to 0,
and Y3 to 0.
And finally, Y6 to 0.
So if these three variables are set to 0,
which are going to correspond to setting these variables to false,
then this clause is not satisfied,
then we want the variable for this clause to be value 0.
So when this clause,
this J clause is not satisfied,
we want these variables ZJ to be constrained to be value 0.
What if it's another setting?
Well, then this clause is satisfied.
In this case, ZJ will be value 0 or 1.
We can't force it to be value 1,
but what we can do is we can try to maximize these ZJ's,
that'll be our objective function,
and then the optimal point will take value 1.
So if it can achieve value 1, then we will.
In summary, the constraint we need to add is that if all three of these variables are 0,
then ZJ is 0.
How do we achieve that?
We say that ZJ is at most Y5+Y3+Y6.
So if these three variables are 0,
then ZJ must be 0.
Now if at least one of these is 1,
then ZJ can takes values 0 or 1.
Recall that these variables are constrained between 0 and 1,
and also these Y's are constrained to be 0 or 1.