Take a look at another clause that has some positive and negative literals.
Consider this clause of size four: X1 bar,
or X3, or X2, or X5 bar.
Now, we want, that if X1 is set to true,
X3 is false, X2 is false,
and X5 is true which is going to correspond to Y1 being one,
Y3 and Y2 being value zero and Y5 being value one.
Then, we want that the variable Z, for this clause,
let's say it's clause J,
is forced to take value zero which corresponds to this clause being unsatisfied.
Well, previously when we had just had positive form of these literals,
then we looked at the sum of the Y's appearing.
Now, we're going to look at the complement for these negative literals.
So, we're going to look at one minus Y1
plus Y3 plus Y2 because these appear in positive form.
Plus one minus Y5,
because it appears as a negative form,
and we're going to constrain ZJ to be at most this quantity.
So, if this setting is true,
then ZJ must be zero.
For any other setting of these four Y's,
then ZJ can be zero or one.
And in general, for clause CJ,
we have to consider which literals are
positive form and which literals are in negative form.
So, let's use CJ plus and CJ superscript minus.
CJ plus will of course be the positive literals in the Jth clause, in this case,
it's X2 and X3 and CJ minus will be the negative literals,
in this case X1 and X5.