Let's take a look at the arithmetic mean,
geometric mean and inequality.
Let's take a look at its general form.
We have K non-negative numbers, W1 through WK.
Think of these as weights.
We want to look at the mean of these weights.
So we can look at the arithmetic mean and the geometric mean.
The arithmetic mean takes the sum and divides by the number of terms.
The geometric mean takes the product and takes the K through.
How do these two things relate?
While the arithmetic mean is always at least the geometric mean.
And this holds for any non-negative weights.
How do we relate this to our problem?
Well, we're going to set WI to be one minus YI star hat.
And then the arithmetic mean is one over K times the sum
of one minus Yi hat star And this is at least the geometric mean,
which is the product over I of
one minus YI hat star and then we take the K through of the right hand side.
Now, alternatively, instead of taking the K through to the right hand side,
we can take the Kth power of both sides and we have the following inequality.
This is the one we're going to use.