Okay, we're almost done. Actually, we really are done.
We just have to summarize. We're looking at
the probability that this clause, Cj, is satisfied.
This is equal to one minus the product over I,
of one minus Yi^*.
Then we apply the AM-GM inequality to convert this product into a sum.
Then we apply the LP constraint to relate that sum over the Yi's to Zj.
And then we got this inequality.
We got that this is at least one minus, one minus the Zj^* over K,
raise to the k-power.
Now what we just proved is that this whole thing is at least,
this constant which is a function of K,
but independent of Z, one,
minus the quantity one minus one over K to the K, times ZJ^*.
Okay, now let's simplify this a little bit.
If you recall, the Taylor series for E to the -X,
it's one minus X,
X squared over two,
X-cubed over three factorial and a plus-minus, alternating series.
Now, what if we want to relate E to the minus X to 1 minus X?
Well, the next term is positive.
So E to the minus X is going to be bigger.
So one minus one over K is at most E to the minus one over K raised to the Kth power.
We have 1 over E, and then take minus and then we have it, it's at least.
So we have this quantity becomes one minus one over E,
times Zj^*, and that's what we wanted to prove.
That was the lemma we claimed.
And therefore, we have a one minus one over E approximation algorithm.
That completes the analysis of this LP-based algorithm.