Now, let's summarize some important points about this LP-based algorithm.
It's a very general approach.
We can take a hard problem and oftentimes we can reduce it to integer linear programming.
Integer linear programming is very general, very powerful technique.
So it's very common that we can reduce
these NP-hard problems to integer linear programming.
Then we can relax it to a linear programming.
We just drop this integrality constraint, and then we can solve it.
There are polynomial time solvers,
though we can often use simplex algorithm.
It's often fast. Then we can take this LP solution
and we can round it into some randomized way as we just did for its SAT.
And this gives us a feasible point for the integer linear program and hopefully,
it's a reasonable heuristic for this solution,
the optimal value of this ILP.