So, here's Fermet's little theorem again.
For prime number p, for every z between one and p minus one,
if we look at z raised to the power of p minus one and take in mod p we end up with one.
So well let's look at the proof of this theorem.
Let me look at the set of possible z's. What are these?
These are all the numbers between one and p minus one.
One, two, three up to p minus one.
Let's define the set s as the possible z's.
So, these are the numbers one,
two, three up to p minus one.
Which is defined in this set s. Now let's look at another set s prime.
S Prime is going to be defined by taking the elements of s,
each of these p minus one elements,
multiplying each one by z.
So we got z times s and then for each of
those elements we take it mod p. So the first element is going to be one time z
mod p. The second element is going to be two times z mod p.
The last element is going to be p minus
one times z mod p. Let's look at a simple example.
Let's take p as seven and let's take z as four.
First off, what's the set S?
S there are the numbers one, two, three,
four, five, six.
What's S prime?
Well, the first element is one times four which is
four mod seven, which is going to be four.
The second element is going to be two times four which is eight mod seven which is one.
The third element is going to be three times four which is 12 mod seven which is
five and four times four is 16 mod seven is two.
Five times four is 20 mod seven is six.
Finally six times four is 24 mod seven is three. Look at this set.
It's the same as s except in different order.
So the set of elements are the same just it's a permutation of
s. So the key thing is that s and s prime are the same sets,
just in different order.
Let me prove to you this fact,
that in general s and s prime are the same sets and then we're going to use
this fact that s and s prime are the same sets to prove the Fermet's little Theorem.