Now I misled you a little bit.
We're going to use a generalization of Fermat's little theorem called Euler's theorem.
So from this little theory as Gann says,
if P is a prime then for every Z between one and P minus one,
we take that Z raised to the power P minus one is congruent to
1 mod P. Euler's theorem is going to generalize it
to any number N here instead of
just a prime number P. So Euler's theorem replaces P by any N,
not necessarily a prime number,
and any Z but we need that Z and N are relatively prime to each other.
By relatively prime, we mean that the GCD of Z and N is one.
Now if Z and N are relatively prime to each other then we're
going to perform an operation similar to Fermat's a little theorem.
So we're going to raise Z to the power phi of N,
I'll tell you what phi of N is in a second,
and that's going to be congruent to one.
Now what is this crazy phi of N?
When N is a prime then phi of N is P minus one or N minus one.
In general, what does it phi of N?
It's a number of integers between one and N
which are relatively prime to N. So in other words,
it's the size of the set of those Xs where X
is between one and N and X is relatively prime to N,
which means that the GCD of X and N is one,
and we want to look at the cardinality of this set.
How many Xs between one and N,
or N minus one, have GCD of one with N?
This function phi of N is called Euler's totient function.
Try to say that ten times quickly.
So let's take a look at what Euler's totient function
is for the case when N equals P is a prime number.
For prime number P, what is phi of P?
How many numbers between one and P are relatively prime to that prime number P?
Well every number between one and P minus one, one, two, three,
up to P minus one are all prime,
relatively prime to P. So the number of relatively prime to P is P minus one.
So if you look at Euler's theorem for the case when N is
a prime number P then we're raising Z to the power of P minus one,
and that's congruent to one mod P. So it's exactly the same as Fermat's little theorem.
So Euler's theorem is a generalization of Fermat's little theorem to arbitrary N.