Now, let's go ahead and look at what phi_of_n is for this case when n_equals_p_times_q.
Let's write out all the numbers that we're looking at.
We're looking at the numbers between one and p_times_q.
So, this pq numbers here.
How many of these numbers are multiples of p?
Well, p, two_times_p, up to q_times_p,
are all multiples of p. How many of those are there? There's q of them.
So, q are multiples of p. How many are multiples of q?
There's q, two_times_q, up to p_times_q.
So, p of these numbers are multiples of q.
So, each of these numbers has a common divisor with p_times_q,
namely p. And each of these numbers has a common divisor with p_times_q, namely q.
So, we have to exclude all these numbers.
So we had p_times_q numbers originally.
Q of them are multiples of p,
and p of them are multiples of q.
And look, we double counted.
P times q is counted twice,
so let's add one while I can.
This can be rewritten as p_minus_one_times_q_minus_one.
So, what is phi_of_n for the case when n is p_times_q for prime numbers p and q?
Is p_minus_one_times_q.