What is Euler's Theorem tell us for the case when N equal P times Q,
where P and Q are prime numbers?
For any Z which is relatively prime to N,
which means that the GCD of Z and N is one,
and if we take Z raised to the power phi of N, which is P minus one,
Q minus one, we get back one_mod_N, which is P_times_Q.
This fact here, is going to be the basis for the RSA algorithm.
We're going to generate a pair of prime numbers, P and Q.
And we're going to look at P_times_Q,
and we're going to have a message,
and we're going to use this P_minus_one, Q_minus_one,
to generate a encryption key and the decryption key,
and this is going to give us a basic fact,
which is going to allow the encryption and decryption.
Let's investigate this a little bit more and then will
see the basic idea of the RSA algorithm.