let's look at some of the issues that
can arise when we're implementing RSA
first off suppose in our message little
m is not relatively prime to capital n
so the GCD of little m and capital n is
greater than 1 now capital n is a
product of two primes P and Q so it's
only divisors are P and Q so what can be
the common divisor of m and capital n
it's got to be either P or Q so let's
suppose that GCD of little m and capital
n is P now what happens in the RSA
protocol or we take this message m raise
it to the power E and look at that mod
capital N and then the receiver takes
this encrypted message raises it to the
power D and then takes it mod N and what
do we get back well this equals the
original message M now we didn't prove
this case we proved the case when
they're relatively prime to each other
and then if followed by Euler's theorem
and we claim that this case when they're
not relatively prime followed by the
Chinese remainder theorem this is in
fact true but there's a potential
problem in this case what's the problem
well P divides m and N and if we look at
the encrypted message Y which is m to
the e mod n or of P divides M and it
divides n then it's also going to divide
Y so the GCD of Y and capital n is also
going to be P what does this mean well
anybody that's eavesdropping is gonna
see this encrypted message and from this
encrypted message and the public key
capital n by simply running Euclid's
algorithm they can take the GCD of these
two numbers and they find that the GCD
is little P prime P and once they know
prime P then they can factorize n and
therefore they can break the RSA
cryptosystem they can find the
decryption key little T so before using
this message m and sending the encrypted
version of it we have the first chat
that m and n are relatively prime to
each other if they share a common factor
then anybody will be able to use this
encrypted message to break this crypto
system what are some other issues that
can arise we need that little m is not
too large in particular we need that
little m
is strictly less than capital n now
typically our message is text so we
first have to convert it into a number
how might we do that well we can take
the binary version of the text
now the binary version of the text is
gonna be a huge number so what we do is
we break this huge number into n bit
segments these are segments of length
little N and therefore little m will be
at most strictly less than 2 to the
little n so if we break the message into
little n bit strings then we get this
property and if we ensure that P and Q
are sufficiently large so we ensure that
they're leading bit is 1 then if we look
at capital n we know that capital n will
be at least 2 to the N and therefore
little m will be strictly smaller than
capital n so this property that little m
is not too large as easy to insure but
we also need that m is not too small why
is that the case well suppose that
little e equals 3 which is a common
practice and suppose that M is very
small number so m cubed is strictly
smaller than n or when we look at M
cubed mod n what do we get
well the mod n isn't doing anything
because M cubed is smaller than n so M
cubed or m to the e is the same as m to
the e without the mod n so this mod n is
not doing anything when this number m is
too small and that means that our
encrypted message the message we're
sending in clear text is simply M cubed
the Madonna isn't doing anything now if
we see this message m cubed how do we
decrypt it we just take the cube root so
anybody seeing this encrypted message
can simply take to the to brood and we
get the original message back so it's
easy to decrypt it's easy to break this
crypto system in this case cube roots
are difficult to do when we're doing it
with respect to modular arithmetic but
in real arithmetic cube roots are easy
to do so how do we avoid this issue when
we have a small message well we can
choose a random number R and we can look
at M plus R or M exclusive or with R and
we can send this new message this padded
message and we can also send a second
message which is just R itself so we
send two messages the padded message
are itself and as long as our is not too
small then this will be okay and if our
is too small just choose a new random
string until we get an R which is
sufficiently large now there's one last
issue I want to point out if we use the
same message multiple times then we have
a potential problem suppose we have the
same message that we want to send to
three different people each of these
three people have a different public key
but they're all using a equals two three
suppose the first recipient has e equals
to 3 and n one second recipient has n 2
and e equals to three third recipient
has n 3 and e equal to three and suppose
we use the same message m to send to
these three people now the encrypted
messages are going to be different the
first encrypted message is going to be M
cubed mod and 1 the second encrypted
message is going to be M cubed mod and 2
the third one is going to be M cubed mod
and 3 so we got three different
encrypted messages y1 y2 and y3 but it
turns out that if somebody sees these
three encrypted messages which all come
from the same message same number M then
they can decrypt they can figure out M
from y1 y2 and y3 how do they do that
they use the Chinese remainder theorem
this is a homework problem in the
textbook in the desc coupe 2 textbook in
Chapter 1 is problem 44 now all that
remains for specifying the RSA protocol
is to describe how we do primarily
testing so let's dive into that