Now, we're going to derive a Primality Testing Algorithm using Fermat's Little Theorem.
Let's first recall Fermat's Little Theorem.
If r is a prime number,
then for all z in this set,
all z between one and r minus one.
If we look at z raised to the power r minus 1 modulo r,
then it's congruent to one.
Now, we're going to use this as the basis for figuring out
whether a given number r is prime or not.
So, if it's prime it satisfies this.
What if it's composite?
We'll, what if we find a z between one and r minus one,
where z raised to the power r minus one modulo r is not controlling to one.
We'll, by Fermat's Little Theorem if this is the case,
then what do we know about r?
We'll, r must be composite if there's such a z.
So, this z where z raised to r minus one is not congruent to one mod r is a witness.
It proves that r is composite.
And hence, we call this z a Fermat witness because
it's a witness with respect to Fermat's Little Theorem.
The first question we want to ask is whether every composite number has a Fermat witness.
The answer to this first question is, yes it does.
Every composite number has
at least one Fermat witness and we'll demonstrate this in a moment.
After we demonstrate this,
then we have to look at how we find a Fermat witness.
After we show that every composite number has at least one Fermat witness,
then we'll look at how to find Fermat witnesses.
What will show is that every composite number has many Fermat witness.
We'll, there are some exceptions called Pseudo Primes but if we ignore Pseudo Primes,
then every other composite number has many Fermat witness.
So, in fact it will be easy to find Fermat witnesses for composite numbers.
And that will give us our Primality Testing Algorithm.
And then, we'll see how to deal with these Pseudo Primes.
Let's first prove this fact that every composite number has at least one Fermat witness.