Once again, we have a number R and we're trying to determine if R is prime or composite.
Now we say number Z is a Fermat witness for R. First off,
Z lies between one and R minus.
And crucially Z raised to the power R minus one is
not congruent to one mod R. Then by Fermat's little theorem,
we know that R is composite.
Because if R is prime every such Z,
Z raised to the power R minus one,
is congruent to one mod R. So if we get a Z where is not
true then this R must be composite.
So Z is a witness to the fact via Fermat's little theorem that R is composite.
We want to first prove that every composite number has at least one Fermat witness.
So let's prove this fact.
Now, R is composite so we know it has at least two divisors.
So take a Z which is a divisor of R. So clearly this Z,
which is a divisor of R, lies between one and R minus one.
What else do we know about this Z?
Well, look at its GCD.
What do we know about the GCD of R and Z?
Well, if we take Z to be a divisor of R
then we know the greatest common divisor of these two numbers is Z itself.
And since R is composite,
we know this divisor is greater than one.
Well, actually, this proof works for any Z where this statement is true.
So any Z which is not relatively prime to R. And if R is composite,
we always know there is at least two such Z's which are not relatively prime to R. Now,
if the GCD of R and Z is greater than one,
what do we know?
Well, if you recall from our previous lecture about modular arithmetic,
what about the inverse of Z mod R?
We know it does not exist.
There is no inverse of Z mod R. Why?
Because the inverse of Z mod R exist,
if and only if the GCD of R and Z is one.
They're relatively prime to each other.
Now, we want a proof for this Z that Z raised to the power R
minus one is not congruent to one mod R. What are we going to do?
Let's suppose that it is congruent to one mod R. So suppose that Z raised
to the power R minus one is congruent to
one mod R. That's the opposite of what we're trying to prove.
So what will show is that,
if this holds then we get a contradiction.
How will we get a contradiction?
Will show that Z has
an inverse mod R. And we know that's not the case therefore we have a contradiction,
therefore this assumption cannot hold,
and therefore Z raised to the power R minus one must not be congruent to one mod R. Okay?
Now, we have the fact that Z raised to the power R minus one is congruent one mod R. Now,
Z raised to the power R minus one is the same as the following.
It's the same as Z raised to the power R minus two times Z.
This product is Z raised to the power R minus one.
So if Z raised to the power R minus one is congruent to one mod R,
then Z raised to the R minus two times Z
is also congruent to one mod R. Now, look at this statement.
Z times Z to the R minus two is congruent to
one mod R. That means that Z has an inverse. What's its inverse?
It's this number Z to the are minus two.
Because when we look at the product of these two,
it's one mod R. That's the definition of the inverse.
So Z to the R minus two is the inverse of Z and Z is the inverse of Z to the R minus two.
But we know that Z does not have an inverse mod R,
therefore we have a contradiction.
And thus, this assumption cannot hold and therefore we know that Z to the R minus one is
not congruent to one mod R. And that
proves that every composite R has at least one Fermat witness.