Now we call this Fermat witness that we just derived a trivial Fermat witness.
Why is it a trivial Fermat witness?
This is a Fermat witness, z,
where it also has the property that
the greatest common divisor of z and r is greater than 1.
So z and r are not relatively prime.
Notice, such as z already proves that r is composite.
If z and r have a non-trivial divisor,
then we know that r has a non-trivial divisor,
and therefore, it's not prime.
So, any z where this is the case,
proves that r is composite,
there's no reason to run Fermat's test.
So that's why we called such a z,
a trivial Fermat witness.
Now there always exists a trivial Fermat witness for composite numbers.
Why? Because every composite number has at least two non-trivial divisors.
The question is whether a composite number r,
has a non-trivial Fermat witness.
This is a number z which is relatively prime to r. Now it turns
out that some composite numbers have no non-trivial Fermat witnesses,
these are called pseudo primes,
but those are relatively rare.
For all the other composite numbers,
they have at least one non-trivial Fermat witness,
and if they have at least one,
then in fact, they have many Fermat witnesses.
And therefore it will be easy to find a Fermat witness and that's the key point.
Trivial Fermat witnesses always exist.
Every composite number has at least two trivial Fermat witnesses.
But if a composite number has a non-trivial Fermat witness,
then there are many Fermat witnesses,
they're dense and therefore they're easy to find.
And that's what we'll utilize for our primality testing algorithm.