Recall, for a number r, if we're checking whether r is prime or not,
we say that z is a Fermat witness,
if it proves that r is composite,
according to Fermat's little theorem.
What does that mean exactly?
That means, that if z to the r minus one is not congruent to one mod r,
then that z proves that r is composite.
Now, we say it's non-trivial,
if in addition GCD of z and r is one,
so z and r are relatively prime.
Because if GCD of z and r is greater than one,
so they're not relatively prime to each other,
then that z gives us a non-trivial divisor of r,
and therefore we know already,
trivially, that r is composite.
Now, the question is, does every composite number have a non-trivial Fermat witness?
We know it has a trivial Fermat witness.
Namely, if it has a one of its divisors is a trivial Fermat witness,
doesn't have a non-trivial Fermat witness.
Well, in fact there are composite numbers which do not have non-trivial Fermat witnesses.
These are called Carmichael Numbers.
These are sort of pseudo primes.
Okay. They behave like primes with respect to Fermat's little theorem.
A Carmichael number is a composite number r,
which has no non-trivial Fermat witnesses.
Therefore, such a number is going to be inefficient to use Fermat's test,
to prove that r is a composite number.
We're going to have to find a different way to deal with Carmichael numbers.
But, the key thing is that Carmichael numbers are rare.
The smallest one is 561 and 1105 and so on.
But, since they're relatively rare,
let's ignore them for now and when we ignore Carmichael numbers,
we're going to have a simple algorithm to check whether number r is prime or not,
using Fermat's test and trying to find a Fermat witness when it's composite.