So let's ignore Carmichael numbers for now since they're relatively rare.
Let's assume that every composite number r,
has at least one non-trivial Fermat witness.
If we assume that it has at least one non-trivial witness,
how many witnesses does it have, actually?
How prevalent are these non-trivial witnesses?
The key fact is that,
if r has at least one non-trivial Fermat witness,
then there are many non-trivial Fermat witnesses.
In fact, if we look at the set of possible witnesses,
one through r minus one,
then at least half the numbers in this set are Fermat witnesses.
Now, this is a relatively simple fact to prove and it's a very nice proof.
The proof is in the book.
But let's get the proof for now and let's try to use this, Lemma,
to have an algorithm for checking whether a number is prime or not,
when we ignore Carmichael numbers.
So we assume that a composite number has at least one non-trivial witness.
Then this Lemma tells us that at least half the numbers in this set are Fermat witnesses,
are witnesses to the fact that r is composite.
Can we use this fact now to get a test for whether r is composite or not?
The point is that when r is prime,
all of these numbers,
when we raise them to the power r minus one is congruent
one mod r. And when r is composite,
then at least half these numbers,
when we raise them to the power r minus one is,
are not congruent one mod r. So how are we gonna check whether a number is prime or not?
We're going to take a z, from this set,
and raise it to the power r minus one.
Look at mod r and see whether it's one or not.