We have an n-bit number r,
and here's our simple algorithm for checking whether r is
prime or not based on Fermat's Little Theorem.
And this is ignoring Carmichael numbers,
it will be an efficient algorithm for primality testing.
Recall, that if r is composite then,
at least half these numbers in this set are
witnesses to that fact using Fermat's Little Theorem.
Whereas, if r is prime,
then none of these numbers in this set are witnesses to the fact because r is prime.
So, what are we going to do?
We're going to choose a Z from this set.
How do we choose a Z from this set?
Well, we choose a Z randomly,
uniformly at random from this set.
So, we choose a random number between one and r_minus_one.
Now, we do Fermat's Test for this Z.
So, we compute Z raised to
the power r_minus_one_mod_r and we check whether that's congruent to one, or not.
If Z raised to the power r_minus_one is congruent to one_mod_r then what do we know?
Actually, we don't know for sure either way,
but we think that r is prime.
What happens if Z raised to r_minus_one is not congruent to one_mod_r?
Then, in this case we're sure that r is composite
because this Z is a witness to the fact that r is composite.