Let's take a look at how this simple Primality testing algorithm performs.
If r happens to be prime,
what does the algorithm do?
It always outputs that r is prime,
because for every z in this set,
z raised to the power r_minus_one is congruent to one_mod_r,
by Fermat's little theorem.
So, the probability that the algorithm outputs that r is prime,
is one, this is always going to do so.
So, it's always correct when r is prime.
Now, what happens when r is composite?
And let's assume that r is not a Carmichael number.
Now, sometimes the algorithm is going to be correct,
it's going to output that r is composite.
When is that the case? When it finds a z which is a Fermat witness.
So z raised to the power r_minus_one is not congruent to one_mod_r.
But sometimes it's going to get confused,
it's going to make a mistake,
and it's going to find a z, which
z raised to the power r_minus_one is congruent to one_mod_r.
So it's going to think that r is prime.
What is the probability that the algorithm outputs that r is prime,
so, it makes a false positive statement?
Well, we know that at least half the zs in this set are Fermat witnesses.
So what's the chance that it finds a non witness?
Well, at most half of them are not witnesses,
so therefore, the probability of finding a non-witnesses is,
at most, a half.
So, the probability of a false positive is, at most, a half.
Okay, so, we have a reasonable algorithm with
probability of most a half that we get a false positive,
and when it is prime, it's always correct.
But can we get this better?
Can we improve this error probability of a false positive?