So in the repeated squaring algorithm, we start off the same.
We compute X_mod_N and let's store the answer as a_one.
Then we compute X_squared_mod_N.
How do we get X_squared?
Well, a_one is X_mod_N,
so we take a_one_squared_mod_N.
So far it's the same as the other algorithm.
Now we're going to skip X_cubed and we're going to go to X_to_the_fourth.
How do we get X_to_the_fourth? We take the previous solution,
let's call it a_two and we square that.
A_two is congruent to X_squared_mod_N,
so if we take X_squared and we square that,
then we get X_to_the_fourth.
Then we take that solution and let's call it a_four.
Now to compute X_to_eighth_mod_N,
you take the previous solution and we square that.
That gives us X_to_the_fourth_squared which is X_to_the_eighth_mod_N.
And we repeat. What do we end up with?
We end up with X raised to the powers of two.
Then what do we do? We look at the binary representation of Y and
then we can use the appropriate powers of two and we can get X_to_the_Y_mod_N.
Let's look at a specific example so you illustrate the idea better.