A key concept that we're going to need for the RSA algorithm are multiplicative inverses.
Now the concept is a bit subtle for a modular arithmetic.
Let's go back and look at the normal,
real numbers and see what multiplicative inverses mean there.
If we take a number three,
what's its multiplicative inverse, it's one third.
And so if we look at three times one third what do we get? We got one.
And in general for a number a,
it's multiplicative inverse is one_over_a.
And, when we multiply those two together what do we get?
One. Now we're going to have a number z and we want to look at its inverse
mod N. So we want to know what one_over_z_mod_N is.
So we're going to define it as the number,
so that when we do z_times_one_over_z we get back one.
So our definition of the inverse of z_mod_N,
this is number x,
so that if we do x_times_z, we get one_mod_N.
In this case x is the inverse, it's one_over_z_mod_N.
And the notation is that x is z_to_the_negative_one,
same as one over Z.
So x is z_to_the_negative_one_mod_N.
So x is the multiplicative inverse of z_mod_N.
Notice also, that if x is the inverse of z_mod_N,
then z is the inverse of x_mod_N,
because x_times_Z is one_mod_N.
So, x is the inverse of z and z is the inverse of x_mod_N.
Now let's go ahead and look at a specific example to make sure this notion of
multiplicative inverse modulo N makes sense.