so when exactly are their multiplicative
inverses or not the general theorem is
that X inverse mod an exists if and only
if X and n have no common divisor so the
greatest common divisor is one GC D
stands for a greatest common divisor so
if they're both even then 2 is a divisor
of both so the GCD is at least 2 might
be bigger what's at least 2 now just
some terminology when the greatest GCD
of X and n is 1 so they have no common
divisor then we say that X and n are
relatively prime with respect to each
other they feel like primes to each
other
for instance 9 and 14 neither one is
prime but with respect to each other
they have no common divisors so they
feel like Prime's to each other so the
theorem says that if these numbers are
prime relatively prime to each other
then there is an inverse but if they
have a common divisor then there is no
inverse let's look at why this theorem
holds but before we get into it let's
look at some basic properties about
inverses