Suppose that X has an inverse mod N. So,
X inverse mod N exists.
Let's prove that this inverse,
if it exists, is unique.
What exactly do we mean by unique?
Well, let's consider a specific example.
Here's a simple example.
X equals three and N equals 11.
What's the inverse of three mod 11?
Well, these numbers are quite small,
so it's easy to figure out that the inverse of three mod 11 is four,
because three times four is 12,
which is one mod 11.
Now, if we look at four mod 11,
there are an infinite number of equivalent numbers.
For example, 15, 26,
and so on, these are all congruent to four mod 11.
We can also look at negative numbers,
negative seven is congruent to four mod 11.
And there are an infinite number of such numbers which are equivalent to four mod 11.
All of these numbers are inverses of X mod N, but for concreteness,
we'll always report the inverse of X mod N as the smallest non-negative integer.
So, we report it as the integer between zero and N minus one,
if that inverse of X mod N exists.
And if the inverse of X mod N does not exist,
we simply report does not exist.
Now, later in this lecture,
you'll see how to find the multiplicative inverse if it exists.
And to do that, we'll use the extended Euclid algorithm.
In that case, often,
the algorithm will return the negative number and then
we'll have to do a simple calculation in order to convert it to a number,
an integer between zero and N minus one.