In the base case of our algorithm Y equals zero.
So, we're looking at the GCD of X and zero.
What are the divisors of zero?
This is a case where we should define it in
an appropriate way. What is an appropriate way?
What is a reasonable manner of defining the divisors of zero?
Well, how do we get to this case?
We got to this case by taking the GCD of sum multiple of X with X.
Because look at what happens when we do the recursive call on this.
We're going to take kX, mod X,
and that's going to be zero.
So, the second parameter is going to be zero and
the first parameter will be the second parameter.
Now, what is the GCD of kX and X?
Well, this is clearly X,
since the first parameter is a multiple of X.
So, this is why we define the GCD of X and zero to be equal to X.