Now we'll dive into randomized algorithms.
Hopefully at the end,
you'll appreciate how randomness is a beautiful and powerful algorithmic tool.
We'll start with cryptography.
We'll look at the amazing RSA Cryptosystem.
This is one of the most widely used Cryptosystems.
It's extremely elegant.
Once we learn some of the basic mathematics about modular arithmetic,
you'll appreciate the ingenuity of the RSA protocol.
Then you'll have a basic understanding of how these Cryptosystem that we use everyday,
many times a day in fact, actually work.
Another beautiful and incredibly useful application of
randomized algorithms that we'll study is for hashing.
We're going to look at a hashing scheme known as Bloom Filters.
This is a simple scheme that's quite popular in many different fields.
We'll look at the mathematics behind it.
This will involve some basic probability analysis and then you'll
do a programming project to implement and study Bloom Filters.