Let me give you an overview of the topics that we're gonna study in this lecture.
Now the mathematics of the RSA cryptosystem are very
beautiful and they're fairly simple once you have the right mathematical background.
So we're going to start with a short primer on the mathematical topics that we need.
The relevant topic that we need is Modular Arithmetic.
Some of you may have seen this before,
so it might be a reveal, for others it's fairly simple to learn.
Then one key concept that we need are multiplicative inverses,
and what they mean in modular arithmetic.
And then we're gonna look at Euclid's GCD algorithm,
greatest common divisor, which is gonna be used in the RSA cryptosystem.
Next we're going to learn about Fermat's Little Theorem and it's
the key tool in the design of the RSA algorithm.
So at this point we'll be able to detail the RSA algorithm.
Finally, we'll look at Primality testing, given a number,
can we test whether the number is prime or not, or composite?
Once we see how to do that using Fermat's Little Theorem,
then we're going to be able to generate random primes.
Generating random primes is a key component in the RSA algorithm.
So once we complete that,
we'll have completed our discussion of the RSA algorithm.
Now let's go ahead and dive into the algorithms related to the RSA.