Now let's take a look at modular arithmetic.
This is the basic mathematics that underlies
the RSA algorithm and we're going to see a lot of beautiful mathematics along the way.
Let's look at a simple example,
X modular two where X is an integer.
What is X mod two?
This is the least significant bit of X.
What does the least significant bit of X tell you?
It tells you whether X is odd or even.
In particular, it's one if X is odd and zero if X is even.
Now, what's another way of looking at this least significant bit of X?
Well, we can take X divided by two.
If it's even then the remainder is going to be zero because it's a multiple of two,
and if it's odd, then the remainder when X divided by two is going to be one.
So we looked at X mod two.
Now let's look at X mod N where N is an arbitrary integer at least one.
Recall X mod two is the remainder when we do X divided by two.
So X mod N is going to be the remainder when we divide X by
N. Finally let's look at some important notation for modular arithmetic.
Suppose we have two numbers X and Y,
and we look at these two numbers modular N,
and suppose that they're same mod N,
how do we denote that? Well, they're not equal.
The two numbers are not equal,
but they're congruent in this,
or they're equivalent in this world modular N.
So how do we denote that equivalence or congruence?
So the standard indication is three lines instead of two lines.
So this notation means that X and Y are congruent modular N,
which means that when we look at X divided by N,
and Y divided by N,
they have the same remainder,
and we denote that by three lines,
X is congruent to Y modular.