Look at a simple example to make sure everybody
understands the concept of modular arithmetic.
Let's look at numbers modulo three.
When you look at the number mod three,
there are three possible values, zero, one, or two.
Hence, there are three equivalence classes for the numbers modulo three.
Now we set three mod three is also zero.
Same with six, nine, and so on.
All the multiples of three.
Similarly four mod three is one.
Same with seven, and 10, and so on.
Finally, five mod three is two.
Same for eight, and 11, and so on.
But look, we can also go negative.
What is negative three mod three?
Well, negative three divided by three is negative one,
and the remainder is zero.
So negative three mod three is zero.
Same for negative six,
negative nine, and so on.
Now if I look at negative two mod three,
then it is one. Why is that?
X mod N equals R means that when I divide X by N,
I get a remainder of R. What does that mean?
That means that there are some multiple of N,
so I can take Q copies of N,
and I have to add an R, and I end up with X.
Now look at negative two mod three.
That is one. Why is that?
So if I look at negative two divided by N,
what do I get? I get negative one.
So negative two, I have Q equals negative one times three.
So there's negative three plus one,
so, R equals one.
And I end up with two.
So the remainder is one.
So negative two mod three is one.
Similarly, negative five mod three is one.
Negative eight mod three is one as well.
Finally, negative one mod three is two.
Same with negative four mod three is two,
and negative seven, and so on.
So these three equivalence classes all of these numbers,
negative nine, zero, nine,
are all the same with respect to modulo three.
They're all congruent mod three.
These numbers are congruent mod three.