Here's a basic fact that we're going to use repeatedly throughout our work.
Let's say I have two numbers, x and y,
which are congruent mod N. And I have two additional numbers, a and b,
which are also congruent mod N. Now, the point is,
that with respect to mod N,
x and y are equivalent and a and b are equivalent.
So, I can replace one by the other.
More precisely, suppose I'm looking at x plus a mod N. Well,
x is equivalent to y,
so I can replace x by y,
and a is equivalent by b,
so, I can replace a by b.
So, x plus a mod N,
is congruent to y plus b mod N. I can replace x by y and a by b.
Similarly, if I look at x times a mod N,
instead of adding or multiplying,
then I can do the same replacement operation.
So x times a mod N,
is congruent to y times b mod N. Now let's
look at an example to illustrate the usefulness of this basic