Recall our basic recipe for designing a dynamic programming algorithm.
The first step is always to define the sub-problem in words.
Our first attempt is always to try the same problem on a prefix of the input.
Therefore, we let K of I be the max value
achievable using a subset of the first I objects.
All we've changed is we've changed the set of objects available to us from
the first N objects 1 through N to a subset of objects 1 through I.
Our second step in our recipe for designing a dynamic programming algorithm is to find
a recursive relation which expresses K of I
the solution to the I sub-problem in terms of smaller sub-problems.
In this case K 1 through K I minus 1.