The running time with the algorithm we just described as order n time capital b.
The question I'd like to ask is that is
an efficient algorithm or not? What do we mean by efficient?
By efficient, we typically mean polynomial time.
What do we mean by polynomial?
We mean polynomial in the input size.
So, is this running time of this algorithm that we just
described is a polynomial in the input size?
So I'll let you answer, yes or no?
Is it polynomial in the input size,
the running time of our argument we just described?
And if it's no, I want you to detail exactly why is it not polynomial in the input size,
and detail what exactly would it mean to be polynomial in the input size?
What would be the requirement on
the running time for it to be polynomial in the input size?