Let's take a look at this algorithm for a moment.
Often, when we get a solution which uses a two or three dimensional table,
it's useful to look at it and see if we can simplify it to get a smaller table.
And we might get a faster or less space or just a simpler solution.
Okay? And that's what we're going to try to do here.
So, look at our solution here.
Now, why do we have this parameter i?
The point of the parameter i in the original version of the knapsack problem,
was to keep track of which objects we've considered or not.
So, after we consider object i,
then we can look at the first i minus 1 objects and look at a subset of those.
But in this version of knapsack,
we're allowed to use the object multiple times.
So actually, it's not at all clear that we need to consider this parameter i.
And in fact, we can get rid of it.
So, let's write a new version of knapsack solution which,
for this version, we're only going to have a single parameter.
So, we'll just have a parameter for the weight available and we'll
drop this parameter for the subset of objects that we consider.