So, to output the actual multi-set,
which obtains the optimal solution what we need to keep track of is,
what is the last object we add in?
What is the object I,
which we add in, which obtains this optimal solution.
In order to maintain that,
we make a separate array,
S. We initialize S(b)=0 corresponding to the empty set solution.
And then when we update our current solution.
So, when we get into this if then statement then we set S(b)=i corresponding to that
the optimal solution for this subproblem is obtained by adding
object I and then re-cursing on this smaller subproblem.
Now, we can use this set S to backtrack.
And, so, we can use it to produce a multi-set,
which obtains the maximum value.
The details of that backtracking are similar to
what we did for longest common sub-sequence.