Recall, our goal is to compute A x B x C x D. Now,
matrix multiplication is associative.
So, there are many ways to compute them.
The standard ways to compute A x B.
Take that product, x C,
take that product, x D. But there are other things we can do.
For instance, we can do A x B first,
then we can do C x D second,
and then we can multiply these two together.
Or we can start with B x C,
multiply that with A, and finally,
multiply that with D. Or you start with C x D,
multiply that with B, finally multiply that with A.
Which of these is best?
That's what we want to determine.
Which is the best or what is the cost of the optimal parenthesization.
In order to figure out which is
the best or most efficient method for computing the product of these matrices,
we need to assign a cost for each of these operations.
So, let's take a look again at matrix multiplication and then we
can figure out a reasonable notion of cost.