Let's take two matrices, w,
and y, where w is of size a times b.
So, it's got A rows and B columns.
And Y is of size b time c. So,
it's got the rows and c columns.
And this will create the product of these matrices.
So, we're looking at Z, which is W times Y.
Now, note that Z is going to be of size a times c. It's going to have A rows,
it's going to have the same number of rows as
W and it's going to have C columns the same number of columns as Y.
Now, let's look at the multiplication a little more carefully.
Now, here's an example where we're multiplying W times Y,
W has a lot of rows and a few columns, B columns.
Similarly, Y has a few rows,
it has B rows, and it's got a lot of columns,
C. The product matrix,
Z, is going to have A rows and C columns.
Let's look at a specific entry Z, i, j.
Row i. Column j. How do we get this entry?
What we do is, we take row i from W and we
take column j from Y and do the inner product of those entries.
So, we move along the row and the column,
K going from one to b and we take the Kth entry of
this row times the Kth entry of this column.
We multiply those together and then we take the sum of these b terms.
So, to compute this one entry Z, i, j,
it took us b multiplications and b-1 editions.
Now, Z has a, c entries.
So, in total, there will be a, c,
b multiplications and there'll be roughly the same number of additions.
So, therefore, we're going to say the cost of multiplying these matrices is a,
b, c. Since these two terms are about the
same and multiplications take longer than additions.
So, this is a dominant factor.
So, the cost of computing Z, the product matrix,
W times Y is a, b,
c where W has size a times b and Y has size b times c.