In the general problem, we have N matrices A1,
A2, up to An.
Our goal is to determine the minimum cost for computing the product of these N matrices.
Now, the key parameter is the sizes of these matrices.
So, we'll denote the size of the Aith matrix,
Ai, as Mi-1 rows and Mi columns.
So A1 will be of size M0 by M1.
It has N0 rows and M1 columns.
A2 will have M1 rows and M2 columns.
So, the number of columns of A1 matches the number of rows of A2.
Finally, the last Matrix has MN-1 rows and MN columns.
All we need for this problem is the sizes of these matrices.
We don't need to know the entries of the matrices given our cost.
Our cost just depends on the sizes of matrices.
Therefore, the input to the problem are these sizes.
These N+1 parameters defining the sizes of these N matrices.
And our goal is to find the minimum cost for computing the product of these N matrices.
And we're just putting the minimum cost, if we can do that,
then we can go back and figure out the parentheseszation,
which realizes that minimum cost.