There's going to be two parameters,
I and J. I is going to be the start of the substring,
j is going to be the end of the substring.
So, i is between j and one,
and j is between i and n. And then we're going to define our subproblem as
C(i,j) is going to be the minimum cost for computing
the product of the matrices Ai through Aj.
Now, let's try to write recurrence for C(i,j).
Let's start with the base case.
What is the easiest case to compute for C(i,j)?
That's the case when i equals j.
Then we're just computing Ai.
So, the entry C(i,i ) what's the cost for?
It's zero, because there's no work to be done.
Let's look at our matrix actually,
what are these base cases correspond to?
Your matrix C and these are the diagonal entries.
And notice, we're computing the entries where j is at least i.
So, we're just trying to do this upper diagonal over here.
We're not trying to compute this lower diagonal of the matrix.
Now, let's try to do in general what the recurrence for C(i,j) is.