Now, let's go ahead and write a recurrence for C(i,j).
In our graphical view, this corresponds to the root of
the tree which corresponds to Ai through Aj.
We're going to try all possibilities for the split
at index L and we're going to take the best of those.
The best means minimum costs,
so we're going to do a minimization over the choices of
L and L is allowed to vary between i and j minus one.
And we have this left subtree and this right subtree.
The left subtree corresponds to Ai through Al.
The right subtree corresponds to Ai plus one through Aj.
The minimum cost for computing this left subtree is the entry C(i,l).
The minimum costs for computing this right subtree is Cl plus 1j.
Finally, we have to combine these together.
Recall this product matrix is of size Mi minus one
by Ml and this product matrix is of size Ml by Mj.
To multiply these together,
the cost is Mi minus one times Ml times Mj.
Adding that term into our recurrence.
We take the mean over the choices of L where L can vary from i to j minus one.
And for that specific L,
the cost is the cost for the left subtree
C(i,l) plus the costs for the optimal right subtrees CL plus
one j plus the cost of merging that left subtree with
that right subtree which is Mi minus one times Ml times Mj.
We take the sum of those three terms and we take
the L which minimizes that sum some That's our recurrence for C(i,j).