Once again, the general computational problem that we're considering is,
given this vector of coefficients for A of X,
and this vector of coefficients defining B of X,
we want to compute their convolution C. Now a simple algorithm for
computing this convolution is going to compute each of these coefficients in turn.
Now there were order n coefficient.
How long did it take to compute each coefficient?
Well a naive algorithm takes order K time to compute
the Kth coefficient because there are order K terms that we have to sum up.
This is going to lead to an order n squared time algorithm to compute all
of the order n coefficients of the polynomial C of X.
What we are going to do now in this lecture is an order n log
n time algorithm for computing this product polynomial C of X,
the convolution of a_n.