Before we dive into the algorithm,
let us take a look at a few of the many applications of convolution.
One important application is filtering.
So here we have a data set of endpoints.
What we are going to do is we are going to replace
each data point by a function of their neighboring points.
This is used for such things as reducing noise or adding effects.
Let's take a look at a more detailed example of filtering so it becomes clear.
In mean filtering we have a parameter capital M and we replace the data point Yj
by the mean of the neighboring 2M+1 points and we do this for all j.
Now this smooth dataset Yi had can be viewed as the convolution of
Y with a vector f. The vector f is this vector of size 2M+1.
To smooth the data set in this way with computers convolution with this simple
vector f. Now of course we can smoothen more sophisticated ways for example,
we can replace this factor f by a Gaussian function,
in this way points nearby Yj are given more weight.
In particular a Gaussian filter uses the following vector.
This quantities Z, is just
a normalizing factor so that the sum of the entries in this vector sum up to one.
Now there are many other filters one might consider.
A different type of filter one might consider is Gaussian blur.
This is used to add some visual effect to an image,
in particular to blur an image.
In particular, Gaussian blur applies a two dimensional Gaussian filter to an image.
Now let's get back to our original problem of how do we
compute the convolution of a pair of vectors.