And let's look at some basic properties of polynomials.
Consider the polynomial A(x).
There are two natural ways of representing the polynomial A(x).
The first way, is by its coefficients,
this is the vector A that we've been considering so far.
A second way, is by looking at the value of this polynomial A(x) at n points.
So, we take n points (x1), (x2),
up to (xn) and and we evaluate this polynomial A(x) at these n points.
The key fact is that a polynomial of degree n minus one is
uniquely determined by its values at any n distinct points.
So, that this statement makes intuitive sense,
the example to keep in mind is that of a line.
A line is a degree one polynomial,
and a line is defined by any two points on that line.
And in general, a degree n-1 polynomial is defined by any n points on that polynomial.
The vector of coefficients is a more natural way to represent a polynomial.
However, the values are more convenient for the purposes of multiplying polynomials.
We'll see this in a second.
Now, what FFT does,
is it convert from coefficients to the values and values to coefficients.
So, it does this transformation between these two representations of the polynomial.
And the point is that coefficients is a more convenient way to represent a polynomial
oftentimes but the values are more convenient for multiplying polynomials.
So, we'll take the coefficients as input,
we'll convert them to the values.
We'll multiply the polynomials and then we'll use
FFT to convert it back to the coefficients once again.
One important point is that FFT converts from the coefficients to the values,
not for any choice of (X1) through (Xn) but
for a particular well chosen set of points, (X1) through (Xn).
And part of the beauty of the FFT algorithm comes from
this choice of these points (X1) through (Xn).
Before we dive into FFT,
let's take a look at why the values are convenient for multiplying polynomials.