One of the key ideas for multiplying polynomials is that multiplying
polynomials is easy when we have the polynomials in the values representation.
So suppose that we know the polynomial A(x) evaluated at two n points,
x1 through x2n, and we know this polynomial B(x) at the same two n points.
Then we can compute the product polynomial C(x) at
these two n points by just computing the product of two numbers for each i.
So C(xi) is the product of the number A(xi) and B(xi).
This is just a number, and this is just a number.
Since C(xi) is just the product of two numbers,
it takes order one time for each i,
and therefore it takes order n total time to compute this product polynomial.
Now why do we take A and B at two n points?
Well, C is a polynomial of degree at most 2n minus two.
So we needed at least 2n minus one points.
So two n points suffices.
The summary is that, if we have the value of these polynomials,
A(x) and B(x), at n,
or two n points,
then we compute this product polynomial at the same points in order n total time.
So what we're going to do is we're going to use FFT to
convert from the coefficients to the values,
this is going to take order n log n time to do this conversion,
and then I'll take order n total time to
compute the product polynomial at these two n points,
and then we do FFT to convert back from the value of C of x,
at these two n points,
back to the coefficients for C(x),
and that again will take order n log n time.
So let's dive in now to see how we do FFT,
which converts from the coefficients to the values.