Now here's the smaller computational task that we're focusing on now.
We're given this vector a.
These correspond to the coefficients for the polynomial A(x) and we want to compute
the value of this polynomial A(x) at two endpoints, x1, through x2n.
And the key point is that we get to choose these two endpoints x1 through x2n.
How do we choose them?
Well that's our main task.
A crucial observation is suppose that
the first n points are opposite of the next endpoints.
In other words Xn+1 is -X1.
Xn+2 two is -X2, and so on.
The last one is X2n is -Xn.
Let's suppose that our two endpoints satisfy this property,
which we'll call the plus minus property,
and let's see how this plus minus property