Once again the plus minus property says that
the first n points are opposite of the next n points.
And let's see how this plus minus property is useful for
recursively computing a of x at two n points.
Let's look at a evaluated at the point xi and a evaluated at the point xn plus i.
Since we're assuming the plus minus property,
these two points are opposites of each other.
Now let's break up this polynomial A(x) into the even terms and the odd terms.
Even terms are of the form a,
two k times x raised to the power two k. Since the powers even,
this is the same for xi and negative xi.
So these even terms are the same for the point xi and the point xn plus i.
Now what about for the odd terms.
Well since it's an odd power it's going to be opposite for xi and xn plus i.
Now given this observation about the even terms and the odd terms,
it makes sense to split up A(x) into the even terms and the odd terms.
So let's partition the coefficients for the polynomial
A(x) into those coefficients for the even terms.
Let's call this vector a even and into the coefficients for the odd terms.
Let's call this factor ai.