So given this vector of coefficients for this polynomial A of X,
to find A even as the coefficients for
the even terms and A odd as the coefficients for the odd terms.
Then we can look at the polynomials defined by this vector of coefficients.
This vector A even defines this polynomial A even of
Y. I have used a variable y to avoid confusion with A of X.
Notice that A 2 is the quadratic term in A of X,
but in A even,
it's the linear term since it's the second coefficient.
And similarly A 4 is going to be the quadratic term.
Similarly this vector A odd defines this polynomial A odd of y.
Notice that the degree of these two polynomials is N over two minus one.
So we took a polynomial A of X of degree N minus
one and we defined a pair of polynomials of degree N over two minus one.
How does a polynomial A of X relate to the polynomial A even and the polynomial A odd?
Well notice if I take the polynomial A even and I evaluated at the Y equals X squared,
then I get the even terms of the polynomial A of X.
Similarly if I evaluate the polynomial A odd at the point Y equals X squared.
Then I get the odd terms except it's off by one in the exponent.
So I multiply by X.
So A of X is equal to A even evaluated at the point X
squared plus X times A odd evaluated at the point X square.
At this point you just start to see
the semblance of the idea of the divide and conquer approach.
We started with a polynomial of degree N minus one.
And now we have defined a pair of polynomials of degree N over 2 minus one.
So we went down from N to N over two and we got two subproblems,
A even and A odd.
And if we want A at a point X,
then it suffices to know A even and A odd at the point X squared.
So we've got two subproblems of half the size.
Now the degree of this polynomial A of X went down from N minus
one to N over two minus one for these two smaller polynomials.
However if we need a of X at two endpoints,
we still need A even and A odd at
two endpoints the square of these original two endpoints.
So the degree of these polynomials went down by a factor of two.
But the number of points we need to evaluate
them at hasn't gone down by a factor of two yet.
This is where we're going to use the plus minus.