Given this polynomial A of X,
we would define this pair of polynomials,
A even and A odd.
They satisfy the following identity,
A evaluated at the point x is equal to A even
evaluated at the point x squared plus x times A odd evaluated at the point x squared.
Now let's suppose that the two endpoints that we want to evaluate
A of X at satisfy the plus minus property.
So the first end points are the opposite of the next end point.
So let's look at A evaluated at the point XI and A evaluated the point X N plus I.
Because of the plus minus property,
this is A evaluated at XI and A evaluated at negative X I.
Plugging this into our earlier formula.
We have that A evaluated at the point XI is equal to A even evaluated at
the point XI squared plus XI times A odd evaluated at the point XI squared.
And similarly for A evaluated to point negative XI,
we have it's equal to A even again at the point XI squared minus XI times again,
A odd at the point XI squared.
So notice to get A at these two different points,
we need A even and A odd at the same points.
Our conclusion is that if we're given A even and A odd at
these endpoints Y1 through YN which are the square of these two endpoints.
Notice that since these two endpoints satisfy this plus minus property,
the square of these two endpoints are these endpoints.
Then in order N time,
we get A evaluated at these two endpoints in particular to evaluate A at the point XI,
it takes order one time given the value of A even at this point and A odd at this point.
And similarly to evaluate A at the point XN plus I it takes order one
time given the value of A even at this point and A odd at this point.