In order to get two endpoints which satisfy the plus minus property,
we are going to choose points so that
the second N are the opposite of the first endpoints.
What happens in the next level of the recursion?
Then the points we're considering are the square of these two endpoints.
So these are the endpoints which are X one square up to
XN square and we want these endpoints to also satisfy the plus minus property.
Let's assume that N is a power of two.
Then we need that Y one is the opposite of YN over two plus
one and up to YN over two is the opposite of YN.
What does this mean in terms of X?
This means that X one squared is the opposite of XN over two plus one square.
But the square of a number is always positive,
so this is a positive number,
and this is a positive number.
So how can they be opposites of each other?
Well it's impossible if we're working with real numbers.
The only way to achieve this is by looking at complex numbers,
so we can easily achieve the plus minus property at the top level of the recursion.
But for all further levels of the recursion,
in order to achieve the plus minus property we need to look at complex numbers.
So let's do a quick review of complex numbers and then
we'll see the appropriate choice of these two N numbers.