As we mentioned earlier polar coordinates are convenient for multiplication.
Let's consider an example.
Consider Z1 and Z2, a pair of complex numbers and let's look at their product.
Let's say that Z1 in polar coordinates is r1 theta
1 and Z2 in polar coordinates is r2 theta 2.
Now let's look at the product of these polar coordinates.
We simply multiply the lengths and we add up the angles.
Now suppose that I have a point Z. I have
a complex number Z and I want to look at its opposite.
So I want to look at negative Z so this corresponds to multiplying Z times negative 1.
What is negative 1 in polar coordinates?
Here's the point negative 1 in the complex plane.
It's a distance one from the origin and it has angle 180 degrees or pi,
so its polar coordinates are 1 comma pi.
And let's say Z is this point at polar coordinates r comma theta,
then negative Z corresponds to the product of
r comma theta times negative 1 in polar coordinates which is 1 comma pi.
Then using this above rule we have that negative Z
is at the polar coordinates r comma theta plus pi.
So the point negative C is the reflection of the point Z.
It's just the same distance from the origin.
It's a distance r from the origin,
and instead of going in angle theta we go in angle theta plus pi.
So if you view the complex numbers in the complex plane,
it's easy to find their opposites by looking at their reflection.