And what we just saw are
that the nth roots of unity correspond to the points in polar coordinates
1 comma 2pi over n times j. j equals 0 corresponds to this point which is 1.
Then we take step sizes of angle theta, where theta equals 2pi over n,
this gives us j equals 1 comma j equals 2 and so on and we
keep taking the equal size steps around the unit circle.
Let's introduce a little bit of notation to make it more
convenient for expressing these nth roots of unity.
So let's let omega sub n denote the point corresponding to j was 1.
So it's this 1 right here so this is
omega sub n. Now what is the next point correspond to?
Well, we just doubled the angle so it's just a square of this point
omega sub n. And the next one is going to be the cube of this point.
And the jth point is going to be the jth power.
So the last one is going to be omega sub n to
the n minus 1th power and then we have omega sub n to the nth power,
which is the same as omega sub n to the zero power which is the number 1.
So the nth roots of unity are the following n numbers,
it's omega sub n to the zero power,
to the 1th Power,
to the square, to the n minus 1 power.
These n numbers in polar coordinates are 1 comma 2pi over n times j,
where j varies from 0 to n minus 1.
And recall Euler's formula,
so this number omega sub n equals e raised to
the power 2pi i over n so the jth of the nth roots of unity,
omega sub n raised to the jth power,
where j varies between 0 and n minus 1,
is e raised to the power 2pi i times j over n.