That we saw that for the case n equals 2,
the square roots of unity are the points 1 and minus one.
For the case n equals 4,
we also have the points i and minus i so we have the four points 1_i minus 1 minus i.
This corresponds to going around the unit circle in step sizes of space Pi over 2.
And for n equals 8, we further subdivide the unit circle.
Now we go step sizes of Pi over 4 and then how do we get the points for n equal 16?
We further subdivide.
So this corresponds to omega_sub_16.
The next one is omega_sub_16 squared and notice that it's also omega_sub_8.
It's the first one of the eighth roots of unity.
And this point i is omega_sub_16 to the fourth power,
it's also omega_sub_8 squared,
it's the second one of the 8th roots.
And it's the first of the 4th roots.
So take the nth roots and square them.
And let's suppose that n is a power of 2 as in these examples.
So what happens when you take the 16th root square?
Well this guy goes there,
this one goes there, this one goes there,
this one goes there. What do you get?
You get every other one of the 16th roots,
which are the 8th roots so the 16th root squared are the 8th roots.
And when n is a power of 2,
the nth root squared are the n over 2nd second roots.
The other key property is this plus minus property.
Take this point omega_sub_16.
What is the opposite of it?
It's this point right here.
This is negative omega_sub_16.
It's also a 16th root of unity. Which one is it?
Well, this is the 1st first, this is the 8th,
this is the 9th.
This is the point omega_sub_16 to the 9th power.
And in general, for even n,
omega_sub_n to the jth power is opposite omega_sub_n to the j plus n over two.
By going an extra n over 2, I'm going an extra Pi around so I'm getting the reflection