The second key property holds when n is a power of two.
If we look at the nth roots squared,
we get the n over second roots.
So we take the jth of the nth roots,
so omega sub n to the jth power,
and we square it.
So in polar, we're taking the point one comma two pi over n times J squared.
So we simply double the angle.
So we get the point one comma two pi over n over two times J,
which is omega sub n over two to the Jth power.
So the Jth of the nth roots squared is the Jth of the n over second roots.
And similarly, if we take the n over second plus Jth of the nth roots and we square it,
well, this is just the opposite of this.
So when we square the negative of it we get the same thing.
So why do we need this property that the nth root squared or the n over second roots?
Well, we're going to take this polynomial A of x,
and we want to evaluate at the nth roots.
Now these nth roots satisfy the plus minus properties,
so we can do a divide and conquer approach.
But then, what do we need?
We need to evaluate A even and A odd at the square of these nth roots,
which will be the n over second roots.
So this subproblem is of the exact same form as the original problem.
In order to evaluate A of x at the nth roots,
we need to evaluate these two subproblems,
A even and A odd at the n over second roots.
And then we can recursively continue this algorithm.
Now we're all set to do our FFT algorithm,
and the end points where we choose to evaluate
the polynomial A of x are the nth roots of unity.