Now we can detail the pseudocode for the FFT algorithm.
Now, the first input is vector A,
which are the coefficients for this polynomial A(x),
and we're assuming that n is a power of two.
What is this second input? This Omega?
Omega is an nth root of unity.
For now, just think of Omega as Omega_sub_n.
In polar coordinates, this is 1,
2 pi over n. And using Euler's formula,
this is e to the two pi i over n. For now,
you can view Omega as Omega_sub_n.
But later, we're going to use this exact same algorithm.
This is identical pseudocode with a different Omega.
We're going to use Omega as Omega_sub_n to the n - first power.
And that's going to allow us to do inverse FFT.
In inverse FFT, we're going from the value of
the polynomial at n points to the coefficients.
Now, what's the output of the FFT algorithm?
Well it's the value of the polynomial at the nth roots of unity.
If Omega is Omega_sub_n,
what are the nth roots of unity?
Well it's just the powers of this.
So, the output is a evaluated at Omega to the zero,
a evaluated at Omega,
a of Omega squared,
and so on, up to a at Omega to the n - first power.
When Omega equals Omega_sub_n,
this gives a evaluated at the nth roots of unity.