Part of the appeal of FFT is that the algorithm is quite concise.
The algorithm is very simple.
So let's re-express FFT in a more compact manner.
First off we have the base case, n equals one.
This is a polynomial of degree zero.
So in this case we simply return the constant term a naught.
Once again we define a even, the vector,
as the even terms in the vector a,
and a odd as the odd terms in the vector a.
Then we recursively run the FFT algorithm with the vector a even and omega square.
The output we get back we record as s naught through sn over two minus one.
Similarly we will run FFT with
a odd and omega square and we record
the output in t naught through t n over two minus one,
then we combine the solutions for
these subproblems to get the solution to the original problem.
So rj, which is going to be a of x at the point omega to the j equals s sub j,
which is a even at the point omegas to the two J plus omega to the J times tj.
And similarly r sub n over two plus j two equals s sub j minus omega to the j times tj.
Finally we return these n numbers r naught through rn minus one.