Before we explore inverse FFT,
it will be useful to explore the linear algebraic view of FFT.
In this way, we can look at FFT as multiplication of matrices and vectors.
So consider a point x_j.
The polynomial A of X evaluated at the point x_j equals a_0
plus a_1 x_j plus a_2 x_j squared and so on.
The last term is a_n-1 x_j to the n-1.
Notice that this quantity can be rewritten as the inner product of two vectors.
The first vector are the powers of x_j.
And the second vector are the coefficients for this polynomial A of X.
Now, FFT is evaluating this polynomial A of X and endpoints.
So let's look at this linear algebra view for the endpoints.
Now we're evaluating this polynomial A of X at these endpoints.
So we're computing A of_x_0,
A of x_1 and so on up to A_of_Xn-1.
The rows of this matrix would correspond to the powers of these points x_0 through Xn-1.
We'll fill that in a second.
But first what is this vector?
This vector are the coefficients of the polynomial A of X.
Now, filling in the rows of this matrix.
The first row are the powers of x_0,
and then the powers of X1.
And finally, we have the powers of Xn-1.