We just saw this linear algebra view of the evaluation of
this polynomial of A(x) at these end points x knot through xN-1.
Now let's look at it for the perspective of FFT.
For FFT, these n points correspond to the nth roots of unity.
So let x of j be the jth of the nth roots of unity.
So it's omega sub n to the jth power. Now let's rewrite these vectors and matrices.
Replacing these n points by the nth root of unity we have now A(1),
A of omega sub n and so on up to A of omega sub n to the n minus 1 power.
So these are the nth width of unity.
This column vector is going to stay the same it's still going
to be the coefficients of this polynomial A(x).
Now let's look at the rows of this matrix.
Now the first of the roots of unity is 1,
so the first row are the powers of it so it's just going to be one.
The second row are going to be powers of omega sub n.
This in fact are just the nth roots of unity.
The third row is going to be one omega sub n square,
omega sub n to the fourth and so on up to omega sub n to the two times n minus one.
It's just the powers of omega sub n square.
The last row are going to be the powers of this last root of unity.
So it's going to be 1 omega sub n to the n-1 and so on.
The last term is omega sub n to the n-1 times n-1.
Now what's important thing to notice about this matrix.
Well, first off it's symmetric,
the entry IJ is the same as the entry JI,
so it's probably going to have some nice properties.
The other thing to notice is that it's just a function of
omega sub n. The entries of this matrix are just powers of omega.