Once again, FFT when we run it with input little a.
Which are the coefficients for this polynomial a of X and the nth root of unity,
then it outputs capital A,
which is a value of this polynomial at the nth root of unity,
which corresponds to the product of this matrix M times little a.
Now for inverse FFT,
we want to take these values of this polynomial and multiply by the inverse of them.
And that will give us little a the coefficients.
What does the inverse of M look like?
Well what we show is that the inverse of M equals one over n,
just a scaling factor,
times Mn with instead of Mn with omegas of n It's omegas of n to the inverse.
So we take the same matrix Mn,
and instead of plugging in the nth root of unity,
we plug in the inverse of the nth root of unity.
Now what exactly is the inverse of the nth root of unity?
Well, this is the number when multiplied by omegas of n equals one.
You multiply a number by its inverse you get one.
So what is the inverse?
It's omegas of n to the n minus one.
It's the last of the nth roots of unity.
Notice that if you multiply omegas of n times
omega of n to the nth minus one, what do you get?
You get omegas of n, to the nth.
Which is the same as omegas of n to the zeroth power, which is one.
So the inverse of omegas of n is omegas of n to the nth minus one.
So the inverse of omegas of n is omegas of n to the n minus one.
Now this is the basic facts,
so we should make sure that is clear for you.
If it's not intuitively clear,
I would either convince yourself by plugging in these points
in polar coordinates and also you can look at it geometrically.
So draw the picture of the complex plane and look at these points on the unit circle.
Now we can plug this in and simplify.
So the inverse of this matrix M,
with parameter omegas of n,
is one over n times this matrix with
the inverse of omegas of n which is omega of n to the n minus one.