The answer is zero.
This sum is zero.
The sum of the nth roots of unity is zero.
Why is that true?
Well, that follows just from the plus minus property,
which was the key to our divide and conquer algorithm.
One is omega sub n to the zero power.
What is omega sub n to the n over two?
Well, if you think of the complex plane and the roots of unity,
we're going halfway around the unit circle. This is negative one.
They're opposites of each other.
So when we add them up they're going to cancel each other out.
Similarly, the jth of the nth roots of unity is opposite of the n over second plus jth.
So the first n over two are opposite the last n over two.
They're are going to cancel each other out and we're left with zero.
This is true for any even n.