Now let's go back to proving the lemma.
We're trying to show that the inverse of this matrix M is one over
n times this matrix M parameterized by omega sub n to the negative one.
So the inverse of this nth root of unity,
which we saw before is omega sub n to the n minus one,
but it will be more convenient to treat it as omega sub n to the negative one.
Now rewriting this, so multiply both sides by the matrix capital
M. This side becomes the identity matrix, capital I,
and the right hand side becomes one over n times M parameterized by
omega sub n to the negative one times M parameterized by omega sub n. Now,
what is the identity matrix?
Well, this has ones on the diagonal and zeros off the diagonal.
So let's look at the product of
these two matrices and we're going to look at the diagonal entries of
this product and show that those are
n and the off diagonals we're going to show are zeros.
So to recap, we have to show that
the product of these two matrices, the diagonal entries,
are n because one over n times these products should be ones,
and the off diagonal entries,
so for k not equal to j,
the entry k, j,
these should be zeros.
So we'll have two cases,
the diagonal entries and the off diagonal entries.