Let's first look at the proof for the diagonal entries.
So let's look at the product of these two matrices,
capital M parameterized by omega sub n inverse
and capital M parameterized by
omega sub n. And we want to show that the diagonal entries,
so the entries k, k equal n. First off,
let's recall what this matrix capital M is.
So capital M parameterized by omega sub n is this matrix.
This is what we saw before when we analyzed FFT.
Now this matrix capital M parameterized by omega sub n inverse is
just this same matrix with omega sub n replaced by omega sub n to the negative 1.
So we get this matrix here.
Now we're looking at the entry k,
k. So when you take the kth row and the kth column.
The kth row of this matrix is the vector
1 omega sub n to the negative k and then powers up to
omega sub n to the negative n minus 1 times k.
The kth column of this matrix is this vector the entry k,
k in the product matrix is the dot product of these two vectors.
First term is one and then we do omega sub n to negative k times
omega sub n to the k. This is the same as omega sub n to the 0, which is 1.
So this term is 1.
And similarly the third term is also 1.
All the terms are 1. How many terms are there?
There's n terms. So we get n. So we proved what we want for the diagonal entry.