Now let's look at the off-diagonal entries of this product matrix.
So we want to show that entries k,
j equals zero when k is not equal to j.
Because if k equals j,
that's the diagonal entry.
And we just showed that equals n. But,
if they're not equal, we'll show it equals zero.
Here are the pair of matrices once again.
We're again going to take row k and now we're going to take column j over here.
The kth row of this matrix is the same as
before and the jth column of this matrix is this vector.
When we take the dot product of these two vectors we get the
following one plus omega sub n to the j
minus k. And then we get powers of
omega sub n to the j minus k. Well, let's simplify this.
Let's do a change of variables to simplify it.
Let's let omega be omega sub n to the j minus
k then the dot product of these vectors can be simplified as one,
first term is omega sub n to the j minus k which is
omega plus omega squared up to omega to the n minus 1.
Now what do we know about omega.
Well, it's the nth root of unity raised to some power.
So it's still an nth root of unity and we know that the exponent is not zero.
Since it's not zero,
then this thing is not 1.
So omega is an nth root of unity it's not one.
So we can apply our claim.
We're just doing powers of the nth root of unity.
We know for any nth root of unity which is not one.
If we take powers of it,
what do we get? We get zero.
Which proves this off-diagonal entries are zero as we desire.
And that completes the proof of the lemma.