Let's go back to this earlier slide with our polynomial multiplication algorithm.
Now we know how to do this last step.
We know how to do inverse FFT which goes from
the values of this polynomial C_of_x to the coefficients of this polynomial.
So let's add in the details of this last step which
will complete our polynomial multiplication algorithm.
Now in this last step, we're going to run FFT using these values t,
t are the values of C_of_x at the 2nth roots of unity.
Now we treat these values t as the coefficients for a polynomial.
So this vector t is the first parameter in our input.
The second parameter is a root of unity.
What root of unity do we choose?
We want to use the inverse of the 2nth root of unity,
which is the last of the 2nth roots of unity,
namely its omega sub-2n raised to the 2n minus one power.
Now when we run FFT on this input,
we're going to get 2n points return.
Let's use this vector C as the return value,
so C_nought through C_sub_2n minus one.
But recall, we have to scale this output,
so we have to take the vector that's returned by FFT,
scale it by one over 2n,
and that gives us the coefficients of this polynomial C_of_x, and that's it.
That completes our polynomial multiplication algorithm
and similarly, our convolution algorithm.