Here is one of our earlier examples of an LP.
This LP had three variables X_1, X_2,
X_3 and four constraints,
and the non-negativity constraints.
Now this was an example where we illustrate the simplex algorithm on and we found that
the optimal value was achieved at this vertex (200, 200, 100).
And when you plug in this point into the objective function,
the profit, the value of the objective function is 2400.
Now suppose somebody simply gives us this point and claims that it's optimal.
Is there some way that we can verify that this point is in fact an optimal solution?
So what we're going to try to do is we're going to try to upper bound the profit,
we're going to try to upper bound
this objective function and show that the profit is at most 2400.
How are we going to achieve an upper bound on this objective function?
Well, we know that these constraints are all satisfied.
So we're going to take linear combinations of these constraints and
then try to achieve an upper bound on this objective function.