Here again is the LP that we're considering,
and we're interested in this point 200,
200, 100, which has profit.
The value of the objective function at this point is 2,400,
and we're trying to verify that this is the optimal,
the maximum profit that we can achieve.
Now consider this vector Y.
It's got four coordinates,
and we're considering the vector zero, one-third, one, eight-thirds.
Let's ignore how we got this vector Y for now,
we'll address that later.
Let's simply consider this vector for now.
Now this vector has four dimensions because we have four constraints in this LP.
So this number, these constraints.
So X1 is the most 300,
is the first constraint, and so on.
The fourth constraint is X2 plus 3X3 is at most 500.
Now we know any feasible point satisfies all four constraints,
so it also satisfies any linear combination of these constraints.
So let's take the linear combination defined by Y.
So we're going to look at Y1 times the first constraint,
Y2 times the second constraint,
plus Y3 times the third constraint,
and Y4 times the fourth constraint.
Let's go ahead and write this out.
So this linear combination,
this expression is equivalent to the following.
As to Y1 times the first constraint.
So we get X1Y1 on the left hand side,
and the right hand side we get 300 times Y1.
Now for the second constraint,
X2Y2 on the left hand side,
and 200Y2 on the right hand side.
Now let's use the third constraint.
The left hand side has X1 times Y3 plus 3X2Y3 plus 2X3Y3.
And the right hand side has 1000Y3.
And finally the fourth constraint gives us X2 times Y4 plus 3X3 times Y4,
on the left hand side,.then we get 500Y4,
on the right hand side.
Now we know that any feasible point X satisfies this inequality for any non-negative Y.
If Y happens to have negative coordinates,
then we have to worry about flipping the sign.
But assuming Y is non-negative,
then this inequality is satisfied by any feasible X.
Now before we plug in our specific Y,
let's collect terms and simplify this expression slightly.
What are the X1 terms?
Well we have a Y1 and a Y3.
Now what are X2 terms?
Well we have a Y2, 3Y3 and Y4.
And lastly, what are the X3 terms?
We have a 2Y3 and 3Y4.
That completes the left hand side.
The right hand side stays the same.
So we have 300Y1 plus 200Y2 plus 1000Y3 plus 500Y4.
Now finally, let's plug in the specific Y which we chose.
So the coefficient of X1 is zero plus one, so it's one.
So we get X1.
For X2, we get one third plus eight thirds plus three.
So we get 6X2.
For X3, we get two plus eight, so we get 10X3.
And the right hand side when you plug it in,
it computes to 2,400.
Now notice that the left hand side is exactly the objective function of the original LP.
And we proved that this objective function is at most 2,400.
So we've shown that any feasible X,
the value of the objective function is at most 2,400.
Therefore, the maximum profit that we can achieve is at most
2,400 and we have a point which achieves this profit.
Therefore this point is optimal.