Let's summarize and recap the previous example.
So, this was the original LP.
We had three variables and four constraints.
Our new LP, the dual LP had four variables: y1, y2, y3, and y4.
The objective function was to minimize 300y1 plus 200y2 plus 1000y3 plus 500y4.
This was the right hand side of the linear combination of these constraints.
First constraints, so that y1 plus y3 is at least one.
This gave us a coefficient of at least one on the left hand side.
y2 plus 3y3 plus y4 is at least six.
We took the constraints containing x2 that the final left hand side
and the right hand side was from this coefficient
of this objective function in the original LP.
The third constraint was 2y3 plus 3y4 is at least 10.
And finally we needed that the y's were non-negative.
Now, a feasible x here, achieved this profit.
So any feasible x gives us a lower bound on the profit that we can achieve.
It actually shows an example where you can achieve that profit.
Now, in this dual LP,
any feasible y gives an upper bound on the profit that we can achieve in the original LP.
Now, this new LP is called the dual LP.
The original LP in order to give it a name,
it's referred to as the primal LP.