Let's do a quick sanity check.
Let's take a primal LP.
So take a primal LP in canonical form,
maximize C transpose X,
Ax is at most B,
X is at least zero.
Now let's take the dual of this LP and then let's take the dual of that dual LP.
What should the final result be?
Well, it should be equivalent to the original LP.
The dual of the dual should be the primal.
So let's check that as true.
Let's take the dual of this LP.
This gives us minimize B transpose Y.
Our variables now are Y.
The constraints are that A transpose Y is at least C,
and Y is nonnegative.
Now we want to take the dual of this LP.
First, we have to convert it into a canonical form.
Now in order to convert this LP into canonical or standard form,
it changes min into a max.
So we multiply it by negative 1.
This minimization is equivalent to maximizing negative B transpose Y.
We do a similar trick to convert this greater than or
equal to constraint into a less than or equal to constraint.
It becomes negative A transpose Y is at
most negative C and we keep the last non-negativity constraint.
Now let's take the dual of this LP.
Let's denote the new variables as Z.
The dual will be a minimization problem.
The objective function will be defined by this vector,
negative C. So we get negative C transpose times Z as the objective function.
The constraints will be defined by the transpose of this,
so it will simply be negative A times Z is at least negative B.
And Z is at least 0.
Now if you convert this into canonical or standard form,
the objective function becomes maximize
C transpose Z which is the same as the original primal LP with X replaced by Z.
And this constraint becomes A times Z is at most B.
Which is again, is equivalent to the original constraint with X replaced by Z.
So these two LPs are equivalent.
So if you take an LP and you take it's dual,
and then you take it dual once again,
you get back the original LP. The primal LP.