Let's get some practice writing the dual LP.
Here's a simple example LP with three variables: x_1, x_2, and x_3.
The objective function is to maximize five times x_1 minus 7x_2 plus 2x_3.
There are two constraints.
The first constraint is that x_1 plus x_2 minus 4x_3 is in most one.
The second constraint is that 2x_1 minus x_2 is at least three.
And, finally, there's the non-negativity constraint x_1,
x_2, and x_3 are at least zero.
For this primal LP,
what is its dual LP?
Now, let's break it up into several parts,
then do it more slowly.
The first question is: how many variables are in this dual LP?
And the second question is: how many constraints in this dual LP?
And by constraints we're not counting the non-negativity constraints,
so this one has two constraints.
So, let's first address these two questions and
then we'll address the details of the dual LP.