Let's look at the solution to our earlier quiz before detailing the dual LP.
Since the primal LP has three variables, x1, x2, x3,
the dual LP has a constraint for each variable in the primal LP.
So, there are three constraints in the dual LP.
And since the primal LP has two constraints,
the dual LP has a variable for each constraint.
So there are two variables in the dual LP.
Let's denote these variables as y1 and y2.
Now, since the primal LP is maximizing, in the dual LP,
we're trying to find the smallest possible upper bound.
So we have a minimization problem.
Now the objective function is going to be a linear function of y1 and y2.
The question is, what are the coefficients of this objective function?
Let's denote these coefficients as d1 and d2,
and we're trying to find this vector d. Now there are three constraints.
Each one is a linear function of y1 and y2.
And let's denote the left-hand side,
the coefficients of the left-hand side of the constraints by matrix
e. So for the first constraint this will be e1 1 and this will be e1 2.
Second constraint will be e 2 1 times y1 plus e2 2 times y2.
And for the third constraint we'll have e3 1 and e3 2.
Now in the dual LP, in standard form,
these constraints will all be at least constraints,
and let's denote the right-hand side of these constraints by the vector
f. So this will be f1, f2, and f3.
And the next quiz is to detail this dual LP.
To do that we need to specify this vector d, d1 and d2.
We need to specify this matrix e. And finally,
we need to specify the right-hand sides of the constraints,
which is the vector f. And, of course,
there are also the non-negative constraints,
y1 and y2 are at least zero.
So why don't you go ahead and specify this vector, and this vector,
and this matrix, and then we'll show the solution video,
which is detailing this dual LP.