To define the Dual LP, we first have to convert
the primal LP into canonical or standard form.
This conversion is just for convenience.
It's easier to remember how to convert an LP in standard form into its Dual LP.
When we have an LP like this,
with these mixed inequalities,
it's harder to remember how to convert into dual LP.
Now to convert this into canonical or standard form,
we need to flip this inequality.
We flip it by multiplying both sides by negative one,
and it becomes minus two times x_1,
plus x_2, isn't most negative three.
This is equivalent to the original constraint.
To get the coefficients for the object function in a dual LP,
we look at the right-hand side of the constrains in the primer LP.
The right-hand sides are one, and negative three.
So this vector d is one, negative three.
And the objective function is minimizing Y_1,
plus negative three times Y_2.
This matrix E will be the transpose of the constraint matrix E over here.
The first row in E will correspond to the column for x in the primal.
The column for x is one, negative two.
So the first row will be one, negative two.
So the left-hand side of the first constraint is Y_1, minus 2Y_2.
Second row is defined by x_2,
which is one, one.
So the left-hand side is Y_1, plus Y_2.
The third row is defined by x_3,
which is negative four, zero.
So the left-hand side of the third constraint is negative 4_Y_1.
For the right-hand side of the constraints in the dual LP,
we look at the objective function in the primal LP.
The coefficients are five, negative seven, two.
So this vector f is five, negative seven, two.
And the right- hand sides are five, negative seven, tow.
So the first constraint is Y_1,
minus 2Y_2 is at least five.
The second constraint is Y_1,
plus Y_2 is at least negative seven.
The last constraint is negative 4Y_1 is at least two.
And this defines a Dual LP.