Now, we can state that weak duality theorem.
This is an immediate consequence of how we formulated the dual LP.
Take a feasible point for the primal LP.
The value of the objective function in this case is C transpose X.
And recall, we're trying to find the X which maximizes this objective function.
Now, let's look at the dual LP.
Take a feasible point Y for the dual LP.
What's the value of the objective function for this dual LP?
Well, that's B transpose Y.
Now what we need to know is that any feasible Y gives
an upper bound on the objective function of the primal LP.
So this B transpose Y is an upper bound on the objective function.
So we know that C transpose X,
this is a value of the objective function that we can obtain at the point X.
This is upper bounded by the value of the objective function at Y which is
B transpose Y. Y gives an upper bound on the objective function of the primal LP.
And this is the value of an primal LP objective function that we can obtain.
So the left hand side is the primal LP objective function,
and the right hand side is a dual LP objective function.
Since any feasible point gives an upper bound on the primal LP objective function,
we have this week duality theory.