Now, in our original example of the dual LP,
we use a specific primal LP where we had run simplex,
we found the point 200, 200,
100 and had profit the value of the objective function was 2400.
Now we were able to find a feasible Y where it's
value of the objective function in dual LP was also 2400.
So that established, that proved that the optimal value was at most
2400 and since we achieved 2400 at this point X therefore,
it was an optimal point.
And in general, we have the following corollary of this theorem,
the weak duality theorem.
If we find a feasible point X for the primal LP and a feasible Y
for the dual LP where their values of the objective functions match.
So C transpose X equals B transpose Y.
So, we have equality here which is what we achieved in that early example.
Then what we can conclude from this weak duality theorem,
is that X and Y are both optimal.
X is an optimal point for the primal LP.
It maximizes the objective function of
the primal LP and Y is an optimal point for the dual LP.
It minimizes the objective function of the dual LP.
So, if we can find a feasible point X in
the primal LP and a feasible point Y in the dual LP,
where their objective functions match,
then these two points are optimal.
Now, does there always exist a point X in the primal LP and
the point Y in the dual LP where we have equality? Yes, there does.
That's the strong duality theorem.
Under certain conditions, we have to have
an optimal value for the primal LP and an optimal value for the dual LP.
So, we need both the primal and the dual to be feasible and bounded.
So, let's first discuss these special cases.
The cases where one of them is infeasible or unbounded.