Now let's take a look at another corollary,
the weak duality theorem.
Here's the second corollary.
Suppose the primal LP is unbounded so the left hand side here will be infinite.
What does that imply about the dual LP?
Well, the right hand side has to be bigger than infinite.
There's no way to achieve that.
So the dual LP must be infeasible.
So if the primal is unbounded,
then the dual LP is infeasible and vice versa.
If the dual is unbounded,
then the primal is infeasible because the dual LP is minimizing the right hand side.
So if that's negative infinity,
then this is undefined.
So the primal must be infeasible.
Now notice this is not an equivalence.
This is not an if and only if statement.
It can be the case that the primal is infeasible and the dual is infeasible.
So the implication has only one direction.
If we know that the dual is infeasible,
then the primal LP might be unbounded or it might be infeasible.
And you'll do as a homework exercise to construct an example where the
primal is infeasible and the dual is also infeasible.
But now this implication is important.
It says that if the primal LP is unbounded,
then the dual is infeasible. Now let's use that.