Now let's go back to one of our questions from earlier.
Can we check whether an LP is unbounded?
So consider an LP in canonical form,
maximize C transpose X,
AX is at most B,
and X is non-negative.
Now, can we check whether this LP is infeasible or not? Well, we saw how to do that.
We make a new LP by adding another variable Z,
and we maximize Z and we change the constraint to AX plus Z is at most B,
and we check whether there's a solution where Z is non-negative.
If there is such a non-negative Z which satisfies this new LP,
then that gives us a feasible point of the original LP.
So we saw how to do this,
and we saw how to obtain a feasible point of this LP, if it is feasible.
Now, how do we check whether this LP is unbounded or not?
Well, what do we know? We know if it's unbounded then the dual LP will be infeasible.
So we could simply check the dual LP and check whether it's feasible or not.
Well, if we simply check the dual LP and we see it's infeasible,
then what do we know about the primal?
Well, if the dual LP is infeasible,
then the primal is either unbounded or infeasible.
We don't know which of these two is the case because
the weak duality theorem just tells us that if the primal is unbounded,
then the dual is infeasible.
But it's non-equivalence.
So how do we check whether this original LP is unbounded or not?
Well, first we check whether it's feasible or not,
whether there is a feasible point for this primal LP.
Assuming there is at least one feasible point so the feasible region is non-empty.
So it is not infeasible.
And then we check whether the dual LP is infeasible.
So now we know that the primal is not infeasible.
So it's true to this case.
So now if the dual LP is infeasible,
then we know the primal is unbounded.
So we simply have two feasibility questions.
We check whether the primal is feasible or not.
And then we check whether the dual is infeasible or not.