Now to recap, our weak duality theorem gave us two nice consequences.
The second consequence that we obtain was that if
the primal LP was unbounded then the dual is infeasible.
This gave us a way of checking whether an LP is unbounded or not.
We simply first check whether the primal LP is infeasible or not.
If it's not infeasible so the feasible region is
non-empty then to check whether it's unbounded,
we checked the dual LP and see whether it's infeasible or not.
Now, the original consequence was that if we find a feasible point for the primal LP and
a feasible point for the dual LP and if
the value of the objective function for these two points match up,
we have equality then these two points that we obtained X and Y are optimal.
So, X achieves the optimal value for
the primal LP object function and Y
achieves the optimal value for the dual LP objective function.
Now for this specific example we consider,
we were able to obtain a Y which achieved this equality.
Now, the question is, is there always a Y and an X which achieve equality here?
And that's the case if the primal LP and the dual LP are both bounded and feasible.