The strong duality theorem states that,
the primal LP is feasible and bounded.
So it is not infeasible and it is not unbounded.
So the feasible region is non-empty,
and there is an optimal solution.
If this is the case for the primal LP,
then the dual LP has a similar scenario.
It's also feasible and bounded and vice versa.
Now, if the primal LP is feasible and bounded,
that means there exists an optimal solution.
So an equivalent formulation of this statement is the following.
The primal has an optimal point X star,
if and only if the dual LP has an optimal point Y star.
So if there is an optimal point for one,
then there's an optimal point for the other.
Now, what do we know about these optimal points?
When we saw in our earlier example that these objective functions match up.
And that turns out to always be the case.
The value of this object function at X star,
equals the value of this objective function at Y star.
So C transpose X star equals B transpose Y star.
So for every LP given the optimal solution X star,
there is always a certificate from the dual LP
which certifies that that is in fact an optimal solution.
Now, one of the nice implications of
this strong duality theorem is that if we write the LP for the max flow problem,
then the value of the objective function for that LP is
the size of the max flow from S to T. Now,
if we write the dual LP it turns out that what we get is the capacity of the min st-cut.
Now, since these are dual LPs of each other,
then we know that we have equality.
So the size of the maximum flow equals the capacity of the min st-cut.
So this max flow min theorem which we saw earlier in the max flow section,
we can also prove it using strong duality theorem.