First off, what is an independent set?
Well, let's consider an undirected graph G,
here's an undirected graph.
A subset of vertices is an independent set
if there are no edges contained in that subset of vertices.
The green vertices here,
the three vertices, are an example of an independent set for this graph.
To check that this subset is an independent set,
we can check all pairs of vertices in this subset,
and we can check that these pairs are not adjacent.
Here is another example of an independent set,
this one of size six.
Now, it's trivial to find very small independent sets.
For example, the empty set is an independent set,
or any singleton vertex is an independent set.
The challenging problem is to find the large independent set.