The solution to this quiz is false.
Now, why is this problem not in the class NP?
Because if you give me a solution,
and you claim it's of maximum size,
I have no way to verify that it is,
in fact, of maximum size.
The only way I can verify that it is of
maximum size is if I can solve this problem in polynomial time.
And that only holds if P equals NP.
So assuming P is not equal to NP,
then the max independence set problem is not in the class NP.
Now recall we had a similar scenario for the optimization version of knapsack problem.
When we looked at the version which tried to achieve the maximum value possible,
that was not known to be in the class NP.
But there was a simple fix so that the problem was in the class NP.
So let's look at the search version of the independent set.