So take an input to the three subproblem,
it is defined by a formula F,
and we'll say the formula F has variables X1 through Xn,
and clauses C1 through CM.
So it has N variables and M clauses.
And now we have to find an input to the independent set problem.
And recall since this is three set,
each of the clauses has size at most three,
so it contains one,
two or three literals.
The input to the independence set problem is a graph G. We're
going to define a graph G based on this formula F,
which is the input to the three set problem.
We also need to specify our goal little g. It
turns out we're going to set our goal g to be M,
the number of clauses.
Here's the high level ideal for the construction of our graph G. For each of the clauses,
we're going to create a vertex in our graph
G corresponding to each of the literals in this clause.
So this clause has three literals,
then we're going to create three vertices.
Since there are M clauses,
there's going to be at most three M vertices in our graph
G. And then we're going to add edges to encode this clause.
And then we're going to add additional edges between vertices in different clauses,
in order to ensure a consistent assignment.
Let's define it more precisely.