This motivates the notion of variable edges.
If I had an edge from this vertex corresponding to
X_1 to this vertex corresponding to X_1-bar,
then I ensure that any independent set contains this vertex or this vertex or neither,
but it cannot contain both vertices.
And therefore, I'll never try to set X_1 to be true and X_1 to be false.
In general, for each of the variables X_i,
I'm going to add edges between all copies
corresponding to X_i and all copies corresponding to X_i-bar.
This will ensure that our independent set corresponds to a valid assignment and then
the clause edges will ensure that our independent set
corresponds to an assignment which satisfies all of the clauses.
Let's take a look at a specific example to illustrate this construction.