In this example, we'll have four variables which we'll label X,
Y, W, and Z.
Now, our three-set input is the following formula.
X-bar or Y or Z-bar,
that's the first clause.
Second clause is X or Y-bar or W. The third clause is X-bar or W-bar.
Fourth clause is Y-bar or Z or W. Now,
to start a construction of the graph, for each clause,
we construct a vertex corresponding to each of the literals.
So for this clause, we have three vertices
corresponding to the literals X-bar, Y, and Z-bar.
We have three vertices corresponding to this clause,
two vertices for this clause,
three vertices for this clause.
Now we add the clause edges.
So we add a triangle on these three vertices,
a triangle on these three,
an edge on this pair,
and a triangle on these three.
Finally, we want to add the variable edges.
So we run an edge from X to all copies of X-bar.
Similarly, from Y to all copies of Y-bar.
From all copies of W to W-bar.
Finally, from Z to Z-bar.
Now let's look at an example independent set of size four in this graph.
Let's say we take X-bar from this triangle,
Y-bar, W-bar, and Y-bar.
This independent set corresponds to
the assignment X equals false because of this literal,
Y equals false because of this and this literal,
W equals false because of this literal,
and Z has no constraints.
And notice that such an assignment satisfies this formula.
Let's prove that in general,
that an independent set of size m in this graph
corresponds to a satisfying assignment of this formula,
and a satisfying assignment of this formula corresponds to an independent set of size m.