Now let's look at the reverse implication.
Now since this independent set has size at least G and G is set to M,
then we know that this independent set has exactly one vertex in each of the clauses,
actually in each of the triangles corresponding to the clauses.
Now this vertex corresponds to a literal in the original formula.
So we set that corresponding literal to true.
So we satisfy that literal,
since every clause has a satisfied literal then we know
every clause is satisfied and therefore the formula is satisfied.
But does this correspond to an assignment, a valid assignment?
But notice we have no contradictory literals in this set.
Why? Because we added edges between Xi and Xi bar so we can never
including vertex Xi and a vertex Xi bar in an independent set.
Therefore, we never attempt to set Xi to true and Xi to false.
So this assignment we constructed corresponds to a valid assignment.
This is a valid assignment and it says every clause.
Therefore, it satisfies the formula F,
so we've taken an independent set of size at
least G and we construct a satisfying assignment.
This completes the proof of the reverse implication.
So we've shown this equivalence.
This proves that a reduction from 3SAT to independent set is
correct and it shows how to take
an independent set and construct a satisfying assignment.
And if there is no independent set of size at least
G then there is no satisfying assignment.
So this completes the proof that the Independent set problem is NP-complete.