A clique is a fully connected subgraph.
Let me define it more formally for you.
The clique problem is defined for undirected graphs.
So, let's consider an undirected graph G. Here's
an example of an undirected graph that we'll use to illustrate a clique.
A subset S of vertices is a clique if the following holds,
for all pairs of vertices in this subset,
say the pair is X and Y,
then X and Y are connected by an edge.
So, all pairs of vertices in this subset S are connected by an edge.
Here's an example of a clique of size five in this graph.
Notice that all five choose two pairs are connected by an edge.
And in fact, this is the largest clique in this graph.
This vertex can almost be added to
the clique but it's not connected to this vertex over here.
The challenging problem is to find large cliques.
Why is that the case?
Well, very small cliques are trivial to find.
For example, the empty set of vertices is always a trivial clique.
Moreover, any singleton vertex by itself is also a clique.
And if you take any edge,
the two endpoints of the edge form a clique.
So very small cliques are easy to find.
The difficult problem is to find the largest clique or the clique of maximum size.