Now let's formally define the Clique problem.
The input to the clique problem is an undirected graph G,
and it goal little g. The output from the clique problem is a subset of vertices S,
which is a clique of size at least
g. Now we're trying to find the largest clique possible.
Therefore we're trying to output a clique of size at least
g. If we outputted a clique of size at most g,
that would be quite trivial,
because we could always output the empty set.
Now we output such a clique if one exists,
and if no such clique exists in the graph, then we output NO.
And what we're going to prove now,
is that the Clique problem is NP-complete.