What exactly is a vertex cover?
Let's formally define it.
Once again, we're going to consider undirected graph G. Here's an example graph.
A subset of vertices is a vertex cover,
if, it covers every edge.
The red vertices in this graph,
our vertex cover for the graph G. What
exactly does it mean that the set S covers every edge?
Well, if you look at this example,
for every edge, such as this edge,
at least one of the two endpoints is in the red set,
is in the vertex cover.
For this edge, one endpoint is in.
For this edge, both endpoints are in the red set.
Formally, to cover every edge,
we mean that for every edge of the graph.
Say x, y, either endpoint x is in the set S and/or y is in the set S. So,
both end points can be in there,
or at least one of the endpoints is in there.
Now it's easy to find a large vertex cover.
For instance, I can include all the vertices in the vertex cover.
And, this is a large vertex cover for this graph.