to prove that the vertex cover problem
is np-complete there are two parts the
first part once again is to prove that
it's in the class and P so consider an
input to the vertex cover problem a
graph capital G and a budget little B
and consider a proposed solution capital
S this is a proposed vertex cover in the
graph G can we verify in polynomial time
that ass is a vertex cover of requisite
size in the input graph G first in order
to verify that s is a vertex cover we
have to check every edge of the graph
and we have to check that at least one
of the two endpoints is in set s this
can be done in linear time in order n
plus M time next we have checked that
the set s is sufficiently small this can
easily be done in linear time in order n
time this shows that in polynomial time
we can verify that s is a solution to
this input instance now we can do the
second more non-trivial aspect of the
proof now we have to show that the
vertex cover problem is at least as hard
as every problem in the class NP so we
have to take a known np-complete problem
we now have four problems that we know
are np-complete sad 3sat independent set
and clique and we have to reduce one of
them to the vertex cover problem it's
most natural to take one of the graph
problems either independent set or Klee
these are quite similar to each other so
it doesn't matter too much we're gonna
take independent set problem and reduce
it to the vertex cover problem now let's
do the reduction from the independent
set problem to the vertex cover problem