To get an idea for the reduction,
let's look at our earlier example of a vertex cover.
The red vertices are our vertex cover in this graph.
What do you notice about the vertices that are not red?
The white vertices. They form an independent set in this graph.
Let's take a look at another example of a vertex cover.
There's a minimum sized vertex cover.
What do you notice about the white vertices in this graph?
They also are an independent set in this graph.
We claim this holds in general as is a vertex cover in
the graph if and only if S bar the complement of s is an independent set.
So the red vertices are vertex cover and
the non-red vertices are an independent set and vice versa.
Let's prove this claim and then the reduction from
independent set to vertex cover will be straightforward.