Let's start with the forward implication of this claim.
So let's take a vertex cover S and let's prove that S bar is an independent set.
So let's consider this example,
the red vertices are in vertex cover S. Now consider an edge of the graph.
For instance, this is a particular edge,
notice that at least one of the endpoints is red.
Similarly for this edge,
at least one of the endpoints is red.
In this case both endpoints are red and in general we know for every edge X, Y,
at least one of the endpoints is in the set S,
because the vertex cover, covers every edge.
And therefore, at most one of X or Y is in S bar,
the complement of S. If at least one is in S then at most one is in S bar,
this means that no edge of the graph is contained in S bar.
S bar contains at most one of the endpoints for every edge.
So it doesn't contain both endpoints for any edge.
Therefore, S bar is an independent set.
So we've shown that if S is a vertex cover,
then S bar is an independent set.