Now, let's prove the reverse implication.
Let's take an independent set, S-bar,
and let's prove that S is a vertex cover.
S-bar, we're assuming, is an independent set.
So what do we know? We know that no edge is fully contained in this set, S-bar.
Therefore, we know that, at most, one of the endpoints,
x or y, is in the set, S-bar.
If both endpoints, x and y, are in S-bar,
then that means the edge is fully contained in the set,
S-bar, and therefore, S-bar is not an independent set.
But since it's an independent set, at most,
one of the endpoints or neither the endpoints is in the set, S-bar.
If at most, one is in S-bar,
then at least one is in S. Thus,
S covers every edge of the graph,
because for every edge of the graph,
at least one of the endpoints is in S. And therefore,
S is a vertex cover.
This proves this direction,
that if S-bar is an independent set,
then S is a vertex cover.
And that completes the proof of the claim.
Now, we can do the reduction.