Let's detail the reduction from Independent set problem to the Vertex cover problem.
So we're trying to find an independent set of size at least little g in
the input graph capital G. Now we have to define our input for the vertex cover problem.
We let little b=n-g. And then we run the vertex cover problem on the input graph G,
the same graph as before with budget little b.
Now, that defines the reduction.
Now let's look at the correctness of this reduction.
What do we know from the claim?
What we know that G has a vertex cover of size at most N minus a little g which is b.
So, we have a vertex cover S of this size and we know that in G,
S bar is an independent set and
this independent set is going to be of size at least little g. So,
if we find a vertex cover of the requisite size in G,
then its complement set is an independent set of
the desired size in G. And if there is no vertex cover of the requisite size,
then there is no independent set of the desired size.