Our reduction took this input instance for the independence set problem.
So we took a graph, a capital G,
with a goal, little g,
for the independence set problem,
and we reduced it to the vertex cover problem with input instance,
capital G, the same graph,
and budget, little b.
And little b was defined as n minus little
g. Now given a solution s for this vertex cover instance.
So this is a vertex cover of size at most little b.
Then we return S-bar as the solution to the independence set problem because
we know that if S is a vertex cover of size at most little b,
then we know that S-bar is an independent set of size at least little
g. And if our vertex cover problem comes back with no, there's no solution,
then when we return no, there's no solution for the independence set problem,
because we have this if and only if statement,
if there's no solution here and there's no solution here and vice versa.
That completes the reduction and that proves the correctness of the reduction.
That completes the proof that the vertex cover problem is NP complete.