Our plan now is to prove that the 3SAT problem is NP-complete.
What we just saw is that if we have a problem such as SAT,
which is known to be NP-complete,
then this makes our task much easier.
So, we're going to use the fact that SAT is NP-complete.
This is known as a Cook-Levin-Theorem.
It was proved independently in 1971 by Steven Cook and Leonid Levin.
And they proved that SAT is NP-complete.
Now, we're going to take this theorem for granted.
And later, I'll give you some high-level idea
of the proof that the SAT problem is NP-complete.
Now, after Steven Cook published his paper,
then the importance of NP-completeness was highlighted by a paper by Dick Karp in 1972.
He showed 21 other problems which were NP-complete.
We're going to look at a few of these 21 in the next few lectures.
We'll start with 3SAT, which was one of the 21