Let me give you a quick reminder of the formulation of the 3SAT problem.
So the input to the 3SAT problem is a boolean formula f in
conjunctive normal form and we use n for the number of variables and m for
the number of clauses in the formula f. Now the extra restriction in 3SAT
as opposed to SAT is that we assume this formula f has the following constraint.
Each clause has at most three literals.
Now the output for the 3SAT problem is a satisfying assignment if one exists.
This is an assignment of true and false to the n variables,
so that the formula f evaluates to true.
Now if there's no satisfying assignment, we simply output-