We're going to show now that 3SAT problem is NP complete.
Before we dive into the proof,
let's outline what we need to show in order to
establish that the 3SAT problem is NP complete.
The first thing we need to show is that the 3SAT problem lies in the class NP.
This will be straightforward to prove.
Now our main task is to take a known NP complete problem.
In this case, all we know is that SAT is NP complete.
So we have to just show a reduction from SAT problem,
to the 3SAT problem.
Now once we've shown this reduction from SAT to 3SAT,
what does that establish?
That establishes that for every problem in NP,
we have a reduction from this problem A to SAT.
And then we have this reduction from SAT to 3SAT,
therefore, we have a reduction from A to 3SAT.
The implication of this is,
that if we have a polynomial time algorithm for 3SAT,
then we have a polynomial time algorithm for every problem in NP,
because we can reduce every problem in NP to 3SAT.
So let's start with the easy task.
Let's prove that 3SAT is in the class N-