Now to prove that 3SAT is in the class ϵNP,
we have to show that we can verify solutions efficiently.
So, let's take a particular input for the 3SAT problem.
So f is our input for the 3SAT problem.
And let's take a proposed solution.
So this is a true false assignment for the n variables.
Now we need to check that this assignment is a satisfying assignment for this formula.
Now, how are we going to verify that this assignment is a satisfying assignment?
Well, we're going to go through the clauses.
So let's take each clause.
For a particular clause C,
you will take us order one time to check
that at least one of the literals in C is satisfied.
Why is it order one time?
Because each clause has at most three literals.
Now if every clause C is satisfied,
then the formula f is satisfied.
It takes order one time per clause, there's M clauses,
so it takes order M total time to verify that this assignment satisfies the formula.
So this proves that the 3SAT problem is in the class ϵNP.