Let's try to get some idea for the reduction.
So let's take a sample input for the SAT problem.
So here's a formula with four variables and three clauses.
Let's label the clauses as C1, C2, and C3.
Now, let's define our input for the three set problem,
let's denote this as f prime,
where clause 1 and clause 3 we can keep the same.
Those are valid inputs.
Those are valid clauses for a three set.
Now, the challenge is what do we do with the second clause.
This is a clause of size four,
but valid inputs with three set has size at most three.
So what are we going to do for this second clause.
Well, we're going to create a new variable y and we're going to
replace the second clause by the following pair of clauses.
So it's x2 bar or x3 or y.
These are the first two literals in C2 and
the second clause is y bar or x1 bar or x4 bar.
These are the last two literals in the clause C2.
Now, the key claim is that this original clause C2 of size four is
satisfiable if and only if this new pair of clauses is satisfiable.
So C2 is satisfiable if and only if C2 prime is satisfiable.
Therefore, replacing C2 by this pair of clauses makes an equivalent formula.
And in this new formula,
all the clauses have size-