Now, let's go ahead and prove this claim,
so that we have some idea how to generalize this construction.
Here's our original clause of size 4
and here's our new pair of clauses each of size, the most three.
And we want to prove that this original clause C_2 is satisfiable,
if and only if this new pair of clauses C'_2 is satisfiable.
Let's do the forward direction first.
Let's take a satisfying assignment for C_2.
This is an assignment for x_2,
x_3, x_1 and x_4,
which satisfies this clause and we want to
show that there is a satisfying assignment for C_2 prime.
Now in order for this assignment to satisfy C_2,
one of the four cases must hold.
Either x_2 equals false,
x_3 equals true, x_1 equals false or x_4 equals false.
Maybe some combination of those hold,
but at least one of those has to hold.
We'll break up these four cases into the following pair of cases.
We'll consider whether x_2 equals false or x_3 equals true.
These are the pair of literals which appear in the first clause of
C'_2 and the other case is if x_1 equals false or x_4 equals false.
This is the pair of literals which appear in the second clause of C'_2.
Now if x_2 equals false or x_3 equals true,
then we're going to set y to be false.
Notice in this case,
we have x_2 is false or x_3 is true.
Therefore, the first clause is satisfied and we're setting Y to be false.
So this satisfies the second clause.
C_2 prime is satisfied in this case.
Similarly in the second case,
if x_1 is false or x_4 is false,
then we set y to be true.
In this case, since y is true,
this satisfies the first clause.
And since x_1 is false or x_4 is false this satisfies the second clause.
And given a satisfying assignment for C_2,
we've constructed a satisfying assignment for C'_2.