Now let's look at the reverse implication.
In this case we're going to take a satisfying assignment for C to
the second prime and we're going to
construct a satisfying assignment for C to the second.
What we're going to show is that if we just ignore y,
whatever the assignment was for x to the first,
x to the second, x to the third,
and x to the fourth which satisfied C to the second prime,
that's going to satisfy C to the second.
Now there will be two cases,
either y is true or y is false.
Suppose y is true.
We know that C to the second prime is satisfied,
so each of these two clauses is satisfied.
y is true so that satisfies this clause.
How about the second clause?
Well, either x to the first must be false or x to the fourth must be false.
Well, if x to the first is false or x to the fourth is false,
both of these satisfy C to the second.
So in either of these scenarios,
we have an assignment which satisfies C to the second.
Now suppose y is false.
So this assignment for y satisfies this second clause.
How do we satisfy this first clause?
What we're assuming that this is a satisfying assignment for C to
the second prime so it must satisfy this first clause.
y is false, so that's not helping.
So it must be the case that either x to the second is false or x to the third is true.
So either x to the second is false or x to the third is true.
Now if x to the second is false,
that means that this is an assignment which satisfies C
to the second and if x to the third is true,
then also this is an assignment which satisfies C to the second.
So in any of these four cases,
we have an assignment which satisfies C to the second.
So every satisfying assignment for C to the second prime if we ignore y,
it's also a satisfying assignment for C to the second.
And this establishes the reverse implication.
We've done both directions,
so we've shown the if and only if.