Now, we just saw how to transform a clause of size 4 into a pair of clauses of size 3.
Now, let's try to generalize this idea.
Let's do it one step at a time.
So let's take a clause of size 5 now,
and let's try to transform this into a triple of clauses of size 3.
Now, previously, to transform the clauses size 4 into a pair of clauses of size 3,
we added one new variable y.
Now, to transform a clause of size 5 into triple clauses of size 3,
we're going to create two new variables, y and z.
Now, we're going to make a formula, C prime,
which is three clauses,
and each of these clauses is going to be of size and most 3.
Actually, they're going to be a size equal to 3.
And we want to do this in such a way that C is satisfiable.
The original clause C is satisfiable,
if and only if this triple of clauses,
C prime, is satisfiable.
And, therefore, in our original input F,
if we have a clause such as this,
we can replace it by this triple of clauses,
and we'll get an equivalent formula.
Now, the quiz is to define C prime.
Define this triple of clauses,
each is of size exactly three literals,
and use this pair of new variables, y and z.
For simplicity, for entering your solution,
let me enter the or symbols for you.
And also to simplify your input,
let's relabel these literals.
So let's relabel these five literals as a, b, c, d,
e. So a is equal to X2 bar,
b is equal to X3,
c is equal to X1 bar,
d is equal to X4 bar,
e is equal to X5.
So use a, b, c,
d, e, and y and z,
and create a formula, C prime,
such that C Prim is satisfiable,
if and only if C is satisfiable.