Now we can formalize our reduction from SAT to 3SAT.
So let's consider our input formula for the satisfiability problem.
And let's create an input formula for the 3SAT problem,
by the following procedure.
Let's consider the clauses of f one by one.
So, for clause C in f,
we'll have two cases depending on whether the clauses of size are most three,
or strictly bigger than three.
If C contains at most three literals,
then we can add this clause as is to this new formula.
Now what if C contains more than three literals?
Then we have to use our previous construction.
In this case, we create k-3 new variables as we said before,
and we replace C by this new formula C prime,
this sequence of k-2 clauses,
as we defined before.
So, small clauses stay the same,
big clauses are replaced by k-2 new clauses,
as we defined before.
Now that we've defined the input to the 3SAT problem,
now we have to prove that this original input to the SAT problem is satisfiable,
f is satisfiable if and only if its input to the 3SAT formula f prime, is satisfiable.
So f is satisfiable,
if and only if f prime is satisfiable.
Now this statement is quite straightforward to prove,
given that we've already proven that C is satisfiable,
if and only if C prime is satisfiable.
Then afterwards, the remaining task is to
show that given a satisfying assignment to f prime,
we can construct a satisfying assignment to f. That again will be straightforward,
because we just ignore these auxiliary variables and the setting for
the original variables will give us a satisfying assignment to the original form-