Let's prove this equivalence and hopefully it seems
obvious given what we've shown so far.
So let's start with the forward implication So let's take an assignment to
the original n variables which satisfies the original formula f. Now we
want to show that keeping this assignment the same for these original n variables there
is an assignment to the new variables so that this new formula f prime is satisfied.
Now since we're keeping the assignment for these n variables the
same and the new variables are as distinct for each new clause.
Therefore, we can look at it a clause by clause.
So let's look at clause C in the original formula
f. If C has at most three literals then it's obvious.
If C is bigger than size three then we replace C by
this sequence of K minus two clauses called C prime.
Now the key is that C prime uses K minus three new variables.
These variables only appear in C prime for
C. They don't appear in any other sequence of clauses.
So the new variables for C are distinct from the new variables for any other clause.
So we can set these variables however you want with respect
to C and this won't affect any other clauses.
And what we saw before is that there is an assignment to these K minus
three new variables so that this new formulas C prime is satisfied.
In particular, we took the first literal was satisfied in C,
call it Ai and then we set the first Ai minus
2 new variables to true and the remaining new variables to false.
And we show that that satisfied C prime.
Now let's look at the reversed implication.
Let's take a satisfying assignment for f prime.
And we want to ignore the assignment for the new variables and show that
this assignment for the original n variable satisfies f. Consider
a sequence of clauses corresponding to sum C prime in f. What we saw
before is that at least one of the literals in the original clause C must be satisfied.
If all of these literals in the original clause were set to false then
there would be no way to satisfy this sequence of clauses C prime.
So therefore we can ignore the setting on
the new variables and just looking at the setting on the original n variables.
That's going to satisfy each of the clauses in the original formula f.