In this section we're going to study computational complexity.
We're going to address the following question.
What precisely does NP completeness
mean and how do we prove that a problem is NP complete.
Many of you have probably heard of the equation P equals NP or P naught equals NP.
We're going to take a look at what precisely this question means.
Finally we're going to look at how do we show that a particular problem is intractable.
Now what exactly do we mean by intractable,
we mean that is unlikely to be solved efficiently.
Now we'd love to say that it definitely cannot be solved efficiently,
instead of unlikely to be solved efficiently.
But that's more than we can achieve at this time.
Now what exactly do we mean by efficiently.
Well, by that we mean that is polynomial in the input size.
Can we solve this particular problem,
in time polynomial in the input size.
Now in order to show that a particular problem is intractable,
what we're going to do is, we're going to prove that it's NP complete.
So we're going to learn how to prove that a particular problem is NP complete.
So let's dive in now to see what P and NP mean.