I start with the satisfiability problem.
This was one of the original NP complete problems.
Therefore, it has some special significance in the theory of NP completeness.
Now this is a SAT problem which we defined before when we looked at graph algorithms.
And we saw an algorithm for 2-SAT.
Now the input of SAT is a Boolean formula f in conjunctive normal form, CNF.
And we'll say that f has n variables,
x_1 through x_n, and it has m clauses.
Now the output is a satisfying assignment if one exists. What does that mean?
That means an assignment to the variables, true or false,
for each of the variables, so that when we evaluate the formula,
it evaluates to true.
Now if there is no satisfying assignment,
so there's no way to assign true or false to each of the variables,
so that the formula evaluates to true.
Then we simply output no.
Now here's an example input to SAT with three variables and four clauses.
So n equals three and m equals four.