Now, we just saw a particular input formula f and we saw satisfying assignment for it.
And then we checked that that satisfying assignment was
in fact satisfied this formula f. So,
when we plugged in that assignment of true and false to the variables,
that the formula f evaluated to true.
Now, let's look at the general problem.
Suppose I give you a formula f and I give you
assignment of true or false to each of the variables.
Now, what is the running time to verify that
this assignment actually evaluates this formula to true?
So, this assignment satisfies the formula.
As a function of n and m, what is the running time to do that?
Why don't you go ahead and write the running time in big O notation.