Let's look at the k-colorings problem.
This is a natural graft problem that many of you've probably seen
before but I don't think we've looked at this particular problem in this course yet.
You've probably heard of the four-color theorem.
This is the formulation of the general problem.
Now, the input to the problem is an undirected graph G and
an integer K. K is a number of colors in our palette.
Now, our goal is to assign colors to
the vertices so their neighboring vertices have different colors.
So, if there is a proper coloring,
we're going to output an assignment of colors to the vertices.
So, each vertex is going to get a color between one through K. These are the names
of the colors and this is a proper coloring if adjacent vertices get different colors.
Now, if this G has no such coloring, then we output no.
So, if there is a proper vertex K coloring for this graph G,
then we output such a coloring.
And if there is no such proper K coloring, then we output no.
Now, the K-colorings problem is in NP.
Why? Well first off,
it's the correct form when there is a solution.
When there is a proper coloring,
we output such a coloring.
And if there is no such coloring,
then we simply output no.
Now, the non-trivial step is we have to show that we can verify solutions.
So, suppose that were given a graph G and were given a K-coloring for this graph.
So, we're given assignment of the vertices to each of the one of the K colors.
Now, how do we check that this coloring is a proper coloring.
Well, we go through the edges of the graph and
we check that each edge is not monochromatic.
In particular, in order m time which is the number of edges,
we can check for every edge that
the color assignment for V is different than the color assignment for W. So,
for every edge, the two endpoints have different colors.
That's it. That's all we have to do to show that the K-colorings problem is in NP.
We simply have to show an algorithm which can verify solutions in polynomial time.
And it's a trivial algorithm,
so it's a simply one sentence proof that the K-colorings problem is in NP.