To reduce colorings to SAT, what do we need to show?
We need to find these two functions,
f and h. f takes an input for
the colorings problem and produces an input for the SAT problem.
If you think of the input for the colorings problem as a graph and a number of colors,
so it's a G and a k,
then there are input for the SAT problem is f of Gk.
Now, h takes a solution to this SAT problem o this f of Gk is a Boolean formula.
It's going to take an assignment,
a satisfying assignment for this boolean formula and it's going to
produce a solution to the original colorings problem on Gk.
So it's going to take an assignment which
satisfies this boolean formula and it's going to
produce h of S which is a colorings for this graph using k colors.
We need to define these two functions f,
which transforms inputs to colorings to inputs to SAT and h,
which transform solutions to SAT into solutions for two colorings.
Now, what do we need to prove in order to prove that this reduction is valid.
Well, we need to prove that,
if S was a solution to f,
then h of S is a solution to the original
G. But we also need that if there was no solution to f,
then there is no solution to the colorings problem.
So we need to show that if S was a solution to this SAT input,
then h of S is a solution to this colorings input and vice versa.
We need to show this equivalence,
this if and only if statement because we need to know that the solutions
here map to solutions here and no instances here are mapped to no instance here.
We need both directions.
We need solutions here if and only if solutions here.