Now let's go back and see how we show that a particular problem is NP complete.
Later we're going to consider this problem,
independent sets problem, and we're going to
prove that the independent sets problem is NP complete.
Now the details of the independent sets problem is not important at this point.
But, what exactly do we need to show in order to
show that independent sets problem is NP complete?
We need to show the following.
I'm a bit lazy, so let me denote independent sets problem by IS.
First, we need to show that the Independent sets problem
is in the class NP, that we know how to do.
We need to show that we can verify solutions in polynomial time.
The second thing we need to show,
is that if we can solve independent sets problem in polynomial time,
then we can solve every problem in NP in polynomial time.
Now the second thing we need to show,
is that for every problem A in the class NP,
there is a reduction from A to the problem independent sets.
That means that if we have a polynomial time algorithm for the independent sets problem,
then we can use that as a subroutine to solve the problem A in polynomial time.
And since we can do this for every problem A in the class NP,
then if there is a polynomial time algorithm for the independent sets problem,
then there is a polynomial time algorithm for every problem in NP.
But how can we do this second step?
We need to take every problem in NP,
and show reduction from every problem in NP to the independent sets problem.