Now, at this point, you should understand the notions of the class P
and the class NP and the notion of reductions.
Now, we're going to see a lot of examples of proofs that a problem is NP complete.
So I don't expect you to be comfortable with that at this point.
But just based on these definitions,
there are a few practice problems you can try from the textbook.
The first two problems in Chapter 8 of the textbook,
Dasgupta, Papadimitriou, and Vazirani,
are relevant at this point.
The first problem looks at reductions between optimization problems and search problems,
and the second problem looks at reduction between search problems and decision problems.
Now, in the next lecture,
we're going to do our first NP completeness proof.
We're going to prove that three set is NP complete using the fact that set is NP.