Divide and Conquer Algorithms or Recursive Algorithms
is one of the first algorithmic tools that many of you may have learn.
For example, binary search or merge sort.
To see the power of divide and conquer,
we'll look at a fundamental problem multiplying two n bit numbers.
Here, we'll assume the numbers are huge.
For example, they may be thousands of bits long.
This will be the case in an application such as RSA.
Since they are so large,
we can no longer utilize the hardware implementation.
We'll see a clever divide and conquer algorithm
which is faster than the standard multiplication approach.
Another fundamental problem we'll look at is given n numbers,
we'd like to find the median element.
The numbers are unsorted,
so they are in arbitrary order.
Can we find the median without first sorting the list?
We'll look at a really ingenious divide and conquer algorithm to do just that.
Finally, we'll dive into the beautiful FFT algorithm, Fast Fourier Transform.
It's impossible to overstate the importance of this algorithm,
it's used in many fields.
For example, signal processing.
In fact, it was called the most important numerical algorithm of our lifetime.
At least that was the case at time of the quote in 1994.
To understand FFT, we're going to have to recall some basics about complex numbers.
Once you understand the basic mathematics behind it,
you'll appreciate the beauty and simplicity of the algorithm.
It will take some time and mental effort to get up to steam for the FFT algorithm,
but it'll be worth it. It's a masterpiece.