We've now seen many NP-complete problems.
When a problem is NP-complete it signifies to us that
it's computationally difficult. Formally what does that mean?
That means it is the most difficult problem in the class NP.
So, if we can solve this NP-complete problem in polynomial time,
we can solve all problems in the class NP in polynomial time.
And now since there are literally thousands of problems in the class NP from
all scientific fields it's unlikely that we're going to
derive a polynomial time algorithm for our NP-complete problem.
To be precise if P is not equal to NP,
then that implies that there's no algorithm which can run in
polynomial time on every input for this NP-complete problem.
Notice the important distinction is on every input.
We may have an algorithm which takes polynomial time on
some inputs or even on most inputs or almost every input,
but there's no algorithm which is guaranteed to take polynomial time on every input.
Now we're going to look at the class of undecidable problems.
These are problems which are computationally impossible.
For an NP-complete problem it's unlikely to have
an algorithm which solves the problem in polynomial time.
In contrast, for an undecidable problem there is no algorithm which
solves the problem on every input regardless of the running time of the algorithm.
You run polynomial time, exponential time;
there's no algorithm which is going to solve it on every input.
Now in 1936 the great Alan Turing proved that the halting problem is undecidable.
And we're going to see the idea of that result now.
Now this paper by Turing in 1936 introduced the notion which
we now refer to as Turing Machine what Turing showed
is that the halting problem is undecidable on a Turing Machine
and a Turing Machine captures the power of a conventional computer.
Now by conventional we're excluding things like quantum computer.
Now later, many other problems were showed to be undecidable,
but the halting problem is quite nice,
so we're going to dive into that proof.