Let's detail once again what's happening in this simple program.
We're running Terminator on input J,
J. What does that do?
That runs program J on input J,
and Terminator returns true if program J on input J terminates. It eventually halts.
And it returns false if J on input J never terminates.
It has an infinite loop.
So there are two cases,
either Terminator of J,
J returns true or false.
In which case, we either go to the THEN statement or the ELSE statement.
Now, if program J on input J terminates so we get a true,
then in this case, what happens in the program?
So we go to the THEN statement and we have a GOTO(1) and then we have an infinite loop.
So in this case, Harmful of J never terminates. It has an infinite loop.
Because if terminator of J,
J returns true, then we go to one and we have this loop.
In the other case, if we get false,
then we go to the ELSE statement and we exit the program right away.
So Harmful of J terminates.