Let's discuss the geometry of linear programs.
Consider a linear program in standard form.
Let's say, that there are N variables.
So, X is a column vector of size N. And let's let M denote the number of constraints.
As we discussed earlier, the feasible region,
the set of axes which satisfy these constrains,
forms a convex set.
Each constraint defines a half space in N dimensions.
The set a points satisfying all M constraints are in
the intersection of these M half spaces defined by the constraints.
So, this forms a convex polyhedron in N dimensions.
We illustrated the simplex algorithm on our earlier example and recall
that the simplex algorithm is walking on
the vertices or the corners of this feasible region.
Now, the key point is that since this feasible region is convex, the optimum,
the points maximizing this objective function,
are going to be achieved at vertices of the feasible region.
Now, that's not always true.
So, let's explore exactly when it is true.