Now, the key, once again,
for algorithms which solve linear programs is that the optimum is
achieved at a vertex of the feasible region except for the following cases.
The two exceptions to this are when the LP is infeasible,
and when the LP is unbounded.
An LP is infeasible means that the feasible region is empty.
There are no points which satisfy all of the constraints.
Here's a simple example of an infeasible LP.
We have two variables, x and y,
and objective function is to maximize 5x minus 7y.
And this is subject to the following constraints,
x plus y is at most one,
3x plus 2y is at least six,
and x and y are non-negative.
Now let's take a look at the feasible region for this LP.