Now here's our example from the previous slide.
Here's the illustration of the feasible region.
First off, we have the non-negative constraints defined by the axes.
So in the upper right quadrant,
the first constraint says that x plus y is that most one.
That's illustrated by this line,
and we're looking at the points on this side of this line.
The next constraint says that 3x plus 2y is at least six.
That's defined by this line,
and we're considering this half space.
Now notice that the two half spaces defined by these two constraints don't intersect.
So there are no points x,
y satisfying both these constraints while maintaining the non-negativity constraint.
Hence, the feasible region is empty.
So there are no points satisfying these constraints.
So this objective function,
this LP, is undefined.
Now notice that infeasibility had nothing to do with the objective function.
Regardless of the objective function for these constraints,
the LP will be infeasible.