Now les take a look at what it means for an LP to be unbounded.
This means that the optimal value of the objective function is arbitrarily large.
Let's take a look at an example of an unbounded LP.
Let's look at the following LP.
We have two variables x and y,
we're maximizing x plus y subject to the following constraints,
x minus y is at most 1,
x plus 5y is at least three.
And then we have the non negativity constraints.
Let's take a look at the feasible region for this LP.
Here's the feasible region based on the non-negativity constraints.
We're in the upper right quadrant.
The first constraint x minus y is at most one,
defines this half space and x plus 5y is at least three,
defines this upper half space.
And this colored region are the feasible points.
Now the picture is truncated at y equals five
but actually this feasible region is unbounded set.
Now let's look at this objective function x plus y.
What we've illustrated here are the heat map and the level
set for this object to function x plus y.
So the blue regions are the lower values of
this objective function and as we get up to the red regions,
we get the higher values of this objective function.
So notice the objective function is increasing as we move up.
And we've also illustrated the level sets so we look at x plus
y equals c for different values of c. So here c equals two,
c equals four and as we keep going up,
we get larger values of this objective function.
And once again, the picture is truncated y equals five,
but the feasible set is unbounded.
So we get unbounded values of feasible points x, y.
For unbounded values of c. Now one important point is the fact that this LP is unbounded,
is a function of this objective function.
The optimal value for this objective function is
achieved in this unbounded region of this feasible region.
Now there could be some objective functions
where their optimum are achieved at these vertices.
Let's take a look at such an example.