So here, again, is the feasible region for
this LP and let's change this objective function.
Let's maximize 2x-3y.
Let's look at the level sets for this objective function in this feasible region.
Here's the feasible region once again with the heat map and the level set's mark.
So if we look at this line, 2x-3y=c,
we achieve c=-12 on this line,
and then it increases as we go down.
So the optimal value of this LP is going to be
achieved at this vertex of the feasible region.
So this maximization is defined for this objective function,
whereas for the other objective function,
the maximization was undefined.
So whether an LP is feasible or infeasible simply depends on the constraints,
whether an LP is bounded or unbounded depends on the objective function.