We're looking first at this recurrence,
T(n) = 4T (n/2) +O (n).
Let's start by getting rid of the big O notation.
Order n means that there's some constant c so that t of n
is almost 4 times T of n over 2 plus cn.
So we replaced order n by most cn.
We also have the base case,
let's say the base cases of size 1 since
the inputs of size 1 it must solve in order one time.
So we can place that order 1 by a constant c and
notice we can use the same constant c for both of these by taking
the max of these two constants and calling that c.
Let's solve for T of n. So I simply restated the recurrence,
though for convenience I rearranged the terms so T of n
is the most c times n plus 4T of n and over 2.
Now let's replace T of n over 2 by this recurrence.
So replace n by n over 2 so we get this term c times n again
plus we get 4 times and then let's replace T of n over 2 with this expression.
So we have 4 times T of and we're placing n by n over 2 so we get n over
2 squared and then for the last term we're
replacing n by n over 2 so instead of c times n,
we get c times n over 2.
Now let's rearrange this and it collects similar terms.
So we want to collect c times n with 4 times c times n over 2.
So these have a common factor of c times n,
this term is 1,
this term is 4 over 2 times c times n and then finally,
the last term is 4 squared times T of n over two squared.
Now let's repeat this process and replace T of n over 4 by this expression.
Now we're replacing n by n over 2 squared.
So the first term becomes 4T of n over
2 cubed and the last term becomes c times n over two squared.
Rearranging once again so bringing this term over here.
So we have T of n is the most c times n times the quantity 1 plus 4
halves plus 4 halves squared plus 4 cubed times T of n and over 2 cubed.
Notice we're starting to get a geometric series here.