Consider some positive constant alpha.
In our previous example alpha was 4 over 2 and we're looking at this geometric series.
We're summing over J going from zero to k of alpha to the j.
Expanding this out we have 1 plus alpha plus
alpha squared and so on up to alpha to the j.
Now since we are solving our recurrences within big O notation,
we don't need to solve this expression exactly.
We simply need to solve it within constant factors,
so that makes life much easier.
Now the key for a geometric series is to figure out
which term dominates either the first term,
the last term or all terms are equal.
The three cases are whether alpha is bigger than 1,
equal to 1 or less than 1.
Now if alpha is bigger than 1,
then each term is growing,
so the last term is going to dominate.
So the whole expression is going to be on the order of the last term.
Conversely, if alpha is less than 1 then
the terms are decreasing and the first term dominates,
so the whole expression is on the order of the first term, so it's order 1.
Finally, the middle case is if alpha equals one then every term
is exactly 1 and then the number of terms is k plus 1,
so the whole thing is on the order of k.
This first case where alpha is bigger than 1
is what arises in the recurrence we just analyzed.
In that case alpha equals 2 and what we saw there was that the last term dominates.
When we look at merge sort,
then we'll have alpha equals one,
all the terms will be the same and we'll get an order again from that.
The final case is what arises in the example of the median finding algorithm,
there we'll have alpha equals three quarters so
the geometric series which arises will be on the order of 1.