The final tool that we'll need is manipulating polynomials.
What we saw in the previous example is that 4 raised to
the power log base 2 of n is the same as n squared.
Now that example is quite straightforward but we're going to have
other examples which arise such as three raised to the power log base 2n.
And we want to convert this into a polynomial.
So we want to convert this into n to the c for sum constant c and we want to figure out
what is this constant c. So let's see
the basic recipe for converting this into a polynomial.
The key is that the base of this log is 2.
So I want to change this base from 3 to 2.
Well, 3 is the same as 2 raised to the power log base 2 of 3.
That's by the definition of log.
So let's substitute this in, to this expression.
So we have 3 raised to the power log base 2n and then we replace 3 by this expression.
So we have 2 raised to the power log base 2 of 3
raised to the power log base 2 of n. Notice these exponents multiply.
So this is the same as 2 raised to the power log base 2 of 3 times log base 2 of n. And
we can rewrite this as 2 raised to
power log base 2 of n and raised to the power log base 2 of 3.
What we've done is just swapped these exponents.
Now look at this inner quantity.
That's just, n, so we have n raised to the power log base 2 of 3.
So we see that this exponent c is log base 2 of 3.