Now, let's look at the more general form of recurrences.
So for positive constants a and b greater than one.
Let's look at the recurrence T(n) = a T(n/b) + O(n).
Our previous two examples had b=2,
and we did a case where a=4, and a=3.
Now, the recurrence for the median finding algorithm has a = 1 and has b = 4/3.
And merge sort has a = 2 and b = 2.
Now, when you expand this out you get c*n from this O(n),
times the following quantity,
1+ (a/b) + (a /b²).
And so on up to a/b.
And then, it's going to stop when we get the logb(n).
In the last term is going to be a,
^logb(n)/T(1 ), which is O(1).
Now, the key is what happens for this geometric series?
It depends on whether a/b > 1,
= 1, or < 1.
If a is bigger than b,
then we get an increasing geometric series and the last term dominates.
If a = b,
then we get a geometric series where I term is one.
If a < b, then we get a decreasing geometric series and the first term dominates.
Let's do the easy case first,
a < b, so the first term dominates.
So this geometric series is on the O(1).
So we get O(1) for this geometric series,
get O(n) here, so the whole thing is going to be O(n),
so we get O(n), in this case.
What happens when a = b?
Then each of these terms is one.
So we get log n terms.
So the geometric series is on the order of log n,
so we have O(n) times O(logn).
So that's going to be O(n) logn.
So in the case, a = b, we get O(n),
log n that's for merge sort.
Finally, what happens in the case when a > b?
Now, the last term dominates.
Notice the denominator here is b ^logb(n) which is n,
so this term, cancels this term.
So the whole thing is on the order of a ^logb(n).
Converting that into a polynomial,
we get that this recurrence in the case a > b is on the order of n, ^logb(a).
And of course, one can look at more general forms of recurrences where here,
we have instead of O(n),
we have O(n) ^d,
where d is a constant.
This is commonly referred to as the master theorem and you can look at
your textbook for the form of the master theorem and the solution to the master theorem.