The input to the Ford–Fulkerson algorithm,
or to the Max flow problem in general, is a flow network.
This is a directed graph G with
a specified star and N vertex S and T. And for each edge of the graph,
where specified a positive capacity C_sub_e.
Now, if you recall for the Ford–Fulkerson algorithm,
to analyze the running time,
we required that the capacities were integer value.
Let's ignore that assumption for now and let's look at the more general Max flow problem.
The output for the algorithm or for the Max flow problem is a flow of maximum size.
And recall that the size of the flow is the flow out of
the source vertex or the flow into the sync vertex T. Now recall,
we analyzed the running time of the Ford–Fulkerson algorithm but we didn't prove that
the flow that's outputted by the Ford–Fulkerson algorithm is of maximum size.
So let's look at that now.
What do we know about this flow that's outputted by the Ford–Fulkerson algorithm?
In particular, when did the Ford–Fulkerson stop?
What is the stopping condition for the algorithm?
The algorithm stops when we look at the residual graph for the current flow.
So this is G superscript f-star.
Now in this residual graph,
we look for a path from s to t. Such a path is called an augmenting path.
If there's no augmenting path,
there's no path from s to t in this residual graph,
then the algorithm stops.
We have no way to augment the flow to get a bigger flow.
We're going to prove the following general lemma: for a flow f-star,
If there's no augmenting path in the residual graph G superscript f-star,
then its flow is a Max flow.
So if in the residual graph there's no path from s to t,
then this flow is a Max flow.