The solution is linear time.
It takes O(n+m) time to check whether a particular flow f is maximum or not.
This follows as a consequence of the lemma we stated on the previous slide.
For a flow f*,
if there's no augmenting path,
no path from s to t in the residual graph for this particular flow,
then this flow f* is a max-flow.
So to check whether f is a max-flow,
we build its residual graph which takes linear time,
O(n+m) time, and then we check for a path from s to t in this residual graph.
To do that, we simply run DFS from s to check whether t is reachable from
s. What this lemma says is if there is no path from s to t in this residual graph,
then this particular flow f is a max-flow.
So we output yes.
Now what if there is a path from s to t?
Well, then we can augment a flow along this path.
And then we get a flow of larger value.
And therefore, this particular flow f is not
a max-flow because we can build a flow of larger size.
Now we'll get back to the proof of this lemma shortly.
But let's go back first to the max-flow min-cut theorem,
and let's see what min-cut actually means.