Now a cut of the graph is a partition of the vertices and two sets.
We will think of these two sets as the left side and the right side.
So we denote it as L and R. Then we are going to be looking at st-cuts.
These are a particular type of cuts.
This is the cut which separates S from T. So S is on one side,
let's say the left side,
and T is in the right side.
Now here's our example of a flow network that we looked at earlier.
Let's mark an example of an st-cut in this graph.
Here's an example of an st-cut.
We put these four vertices S, A,
B and F in the set L. Notice this set doesn't have to be a connected set.
F is not connected to A and B in this subset.
And the set R are the remaining four vertices, C,
D, E and T. Now we're going to be interested in the capacity of this st-cut.
What exactly is the capacity?
Recall is a directed graph.
We're going to look at these directed edges
VW where V is in the left side and W was in the right side.
So these are all edges which go from the set L
to the set R and we're going to look at the capacity of these edges.
So we're looking at the total capacity of edges from
the set L to R. But we're not looking at edges from R to L. So we're
looking at sum of the capacities of these six edges which exit L. Notice that
these edges such as C to F which go into L do not count in this count.