Let's formally state the min st-cut problem.
The input is a flow network.
So we have a directed graph with a specified start and end vertex.
And for every edge, we have a positive capacity.
Now the output for the min st-cut problem,
it's an st-cut (L, R),
so s has to be an L and t has to be an
R. And we want to find that st-cut with minimum capacity.
Recall the capacity of this cut is
the sum of the capacities of the edges that go from L to R,
and we ignore the edges that go from R to
L. Now let's take a look at this cut that we looked at earlier.
So the set L contains s,
a, b and f. Now,
the capacity of this cut is A plus two,
plus two, plus five,
plus seven, plus three.
So the capacity is 27.
We want to find the cut of minimum capacity.
Here is an st-cut of minimum capacity.
R simply contains T and L contains everybody else.
The capacity of this cut is 12.
We just have these two edges exiting L to R. How do we know this is min st-cut?
Well, we're going to prove the Max-flow-min-cut theorem which says that
the size of the Max flow equals the size of the min st-cut.
We know there's a flow in this graph of size
12 and since there is an st-cut of capacity 12,
therefore we know that this flow and this st-cut are both optimal.