Recall, we want to show that the size of
the max-flow is the most to the capacity of the min st-cut.
And to do that,
we need to show that for any particular flow f and any particular st-cut L,R,
the size of this flow is at most the capacity of this cut.
Let's take a look again at our earlier example of a flow network.
And here is our example of an st-cut.
These four vertices are set L and the other four vertices are
the set R. Now the capacity of this cut is 27.
That's the total capacity of the edges going from L to R. Now the intuition for
this claim is that this flow is going from s to t. At some point,
it has to exit from L to R. These six edges which go from
L to R are the only edges that the flow can escape L from.
Now the total capacity of these edges is 27.
So the total amount of flow that can go along these edges is at most 27.
So the size of this flow has to be at most 27. That's the intuition.
Let's formalize it. To formalize the intuition we just stated,
we're going to prove the following claim.
We're going to prove that the size of this flow equals the total flow out of the set L,
minus the total flow into the set L. Now it will just be a few lines to prove this claim.
It's quite easy. And then once we have this claim,
the main statement that the size of f is at most of
capacity of this cut will follow immediately.
And this claim is going to be useful later.
We're going to use it when we prove the reverse inequality,
that the max flow is at least the min st- cut capacity.