So now we've proven this claim,
the size of F equals the flow out of L minus the flow in it to L,
and this is true for any flow F,
and for any ST cut L,
R. Now, recall we want to show,
that the size of this flow F is at most the capacity of this ST cut L,
R. And we saw before that this inequality
implies that the max flow is at most the min ST cut capacity.
So, let's see how this claim implies this desired result.
Well, the size of F equals the flow out of L minus the flow into L,
that's just the claim again.
Where we can drop this second term,
and it only gets bigger.
So, this is at most the flow out of L. Now,
along every edge that leaves the set L,
the flow along that edge has to be at most the capacity of that edge.
Therefore, the total flow out of this set L,
has to be at most the capacity.
Because the capacity is defined as the total capacity from the set L to
R. We didn't count the edges from R to L. Looking back at our earlier example,
for this ST cut L,
R, the capacity of this cut is 27,
and the total flow along these six edges,
which leave this set L,
clearly, must be at most the total capacity along these edges, which is 27.
So, the flow out of this set L has to be at most the capacity of this cut.
So, this proves that desired result.
And therefore, we have that the max flow size is at most the min ST cut capacity.
Now, to complete the proof of the theorem.
We have to prove the reverse inequality.
That the max flow size is at least the min ST cut capacity.
Let's dive into that now.