Now, we'll show the following inequality.
We'll show that max over the flows, F,
the size of F. So the max flow size is at least,
the capacity of the min ST-cut.
We just proved that the max-flow size is at most,
the min ST-cut capacity.
Now if we prove this inequality,
then we shown that it's the quality,
that the left hand side equals the right hand side.
To prove this inequality, what we're going to do,
is we're going to take the flow F*,
produced by the Ford-Fulkerson algorithm.
What do we know about this flow?
The Ford-Fulkerson algorithm stops,
when there's no augmenting path in the residual network.
So we know that this flow, F*,
has no path from S to T in this residual network for this flow.
What we're going to prove, is that for any flow, F*,
which has no augmenting path in the residual network,
we're going to construct an ST-cut,
L, R which has the following property.
The size of this flow, F*,
equals the capacity of this cut that we construct.
Now once we prove this,
we claim that it's done.
Why does this statement imply this inequality?
Well this is one particular flow, F*.
How does this compare to the max-flow size?
Certainly, if we maximize over the flows F,
the size of this flow,
is at least the size F*.
It maybe quality if F* is a max-flow,
but certainly, the max flow is at least the size of F*.
And how does the capacity of this particular cut L, R,
compare to the capacity of the min ST-cut?
Well certainly, the capacity of this particular cut,
is at least the minimum capacity of any kind.
So if we prove this middle equality,
that the size of F* equals the capacity of this cut L,
R that we construct,
then that implies that the max flow size is at least,
the min ST-cut capacity,
which is what we want to prove.
So it just remains to prove this equality