So let's go ahead and prove the claim.
So let's take a flow f* that has
no augmenting path in this residual network and we wanted to find an s-t cut now.
We want to use this property about this f*.
We know there's no st-path in this residual network.
So we know that t is not reachable from this vertex s in this graph.
So that's a way to separate s from t. Therefore,
we're going to let L be those vertices which are
reachable from the vertex s in this residual network.
Now we know this vertex t is not in this set L, why?
Because we know there's no path from s to t in this residual network,
that's our assumption about this flow f*.
Therefore, we let R be the remaining vertices and we
know that the vertex t is in this set R. So s is clearly reachable from itself.
So s is in L and t is in R. So this set (L,
R) is an s-t cut.
So we've constructed our s-t cut,
now we have to prove that this s-t cut has
capacity which is equal to the size of this flow.