Let's recap and summarize our recurrence.
We're looking the length of the shortest path from S to Z
using at most I edges and we're considering the case where I is at least one.
When I equals zero we have our base case.
Now either the shortest path from S to Z uses
the most I minus one edges or it uses exactly I edges.
And we're going to take the best of those two scenarios.
If it uses the most I minus one edges,
then the solution is in D of I minus one Z.
If it uses exactly I edges,
then we're going to try all choices for
the penultimate vertex Y and then we're going to take the length of
the shortest path from S to Y using the most
I minus one edges plus the length of the last edge.
So we have a double min. We take the min of the I minus
one case and the min over Y, choices for Y.
And this defines a recurrence for D of I Z.
Notice, in order to get this D for I Z,
we're using entries which involve I minus one.
So if we build up the table from I going from zero,
which is the base case, to N minus one,
we'll have a valid dynamic programming algorithm.
So let's go ahead and detail-