Let's go ahead and try to find the recurrence for the sub-problem we just defined.
The sub-problem we just defined was D of IST.
This is the length of the shortest path from vertex S to vertex T,
where the set of allowed vertices on the path from S to T
are a prefix of the vertex N. These are the first I vertices, one through I.
These are the vertices that are allowed to be
intermediate vertices on the path from S to T. Let's start with the base case.
Why don't you go ahead and write down what is
the base case and what is the solution to the base case?
For intuition about the solution for the base case and what is the base case itself,
think back to the Bellman-Ford algorithm for the single source problem.