So we're going to have two situations,
either s and t are connected by an edge and therefore,
we don't need to use any intermediate vertices,
or they're not connected by an edge and then there's
no path from S to T. In the first case,
if there's a directed edge from S to T,
then D of 0, S,
T is exactly the length of that edge from S to
T which is W of S T. In the other scenario,
there's no edge from S to T. In this case,
then what is the length of
the shortest path from S to T which doesn't allow any intermediate vertices.
It's infinite. Let's look at the shortest path from S to T
where we only allow vertices one through I as intermediate vertices.
So this is the solution.
This path P is the solution to this problem.
And if there's multiple paths,
just choose any path arbitrarily.
So our goal is to figure out D of I, S,
T. And we want to write recurrence for this so we want to do this for D of I,
S, T in terms of smaller Is.
Okay? So we're going to have two cases.
We're considering this vertex as last vertex I.
So what are the two cases for this path?
Either this path uses vertex I or it doesn't use vertex I.
Let's try the two cases separately.
So what's the easy case?
The easy case is when the path doesn't include vertex
I and then the slightly harder cases when the path includes vertex I.
Let's start with the case where vertex I is not on
the path and in this case what is D of I-