Now, to write a recurrence for D of i, s, t,
we want to use D of i minus one for some pair s and t,
which might be different vertices.
But the key thing is that we want to change this parameter i to i minus one.
So how do we get that? Look at this path.
This is a path from s to i which only uses
a subset of the first i minus one vertices as intermediate vertices.
So, that is D of i minus one s, i.
That's a smaller subproblem which we've already
solved in our dynamic programming algorithm.
Similarly, this portion of the path is the shortest path from i to
t which uses a subset of the first i minus one vertices as intermediate vertices.
This is D of i minus one because the
first i minus one vertices only are intermediate vertices
on the path and it's starting at i and it's ending at t. So
the total length of this path is the sum of these two terms.
So now we have a recurrence with D of i, s,
t. It's D of i minus one, s,
i that gives us the shortest path from s to i using a subset
of the first i minus one as intermediate vertices plus D of i minus one,
i, t that gives us the path from i to t using
this subset of one through i minus one as intermediate vertices on the path.
So we have a recurrence for D of i, s,
t in the case when i is in
the path and we have the recurrence for the case when i is not in the path.
What do we do? We take the best of those two sce-