What's a simple idea for choosing this subset S,
which is of size n over five?
Well, perhaps the simplest idea is let
the subset S just be the first n over five elements of A.
Then we're going to set a pivot to be the median of
this subset S. How does this pivot perform?
Is it a good pivot?
Is this pivot P a good pivot?
No. Why not?
Well, that would be too easy.
Let's see why it fails.
Let's see the scenario where this pivot P is not a good pivot.
Well, suppose A was sorted.
Well in this case, actually, it's easy to find the median of A.
So, there's no reason we're running the whole algorithm.
But suppose A is sorted and then, actually,
this is going to imply that this pivot P is a bad pivot.
So if A is sorted, then what is S?
S is going to be the first n over five elements of A.
So it's the smallest elements of A.
So S contains all the n over five smallest elements of A.
What is the median of these n over five smallest elements of A?
The median of the n over five smallest elements is the n over 10th smallest element.
So this pivot is the n over 10th smallest element of this list A.
Well if this is the n over 10th smallest element.
Then when we partition A into the small,
equal and big sets,
the big set all we can guarantee is that it's at most
nine-tenths n. And then if you go back to the running time of our algorithm,
then we're going to have t of n is at most t of nine-tenths
n instead of three-fourths n. So this pivot P is not a good pivot,
because this large set is going to be too large in the worst case.
So is there a better choice for this set S?
Well, there's some hope because we chose
this set S right now without looking at A at all.
So, can we look at A and do a little bit of
computation and choose a better representative set S?