Now a natural question is,
why do we break A into these groups of five elements each?
Why did we choose five?
What would have happened if we would have broken into
n over three groups of size three elements each,
or n over seven groups of seven elements each?
This is nice homework question to make sure you
understand the analysis of this algorithm.
So consider groups of size three each and seven each,
and look at the analysis of the algorithm.
What is the recurrence in these cases where we break into groups of three or seven?
Write down the recurrence and see whether that recurrence solves to order n or not,
and that'll show you why we consider groups of size five.