A satisfying assignment for this formula is the assignment which sets X_1 to be false,
X_2 to be true, X_3 to be false.
X_1 to be false satisfies this clause,
X_2 to be true satisfies this clause,
X_3 to be false satisfies this clause and this clause.
Now we're going to look at a restrictive form of the SAT problem called k-SAT.
For example, for three-SAT,
the input is going to be a formula in CNF with n variables and m clauses.
But now, all the clauses are of size,
at most, three, or k in general.
Now, the size of a clause is the number of literals in it.
So, this formula is an example of a three-SAT formula.
Actually, it's an example of a k-SAT formula for all k at least three.
Now, what we're going to see later is that SAT problem is NP-complete.
And for every k at least three,
we'll see that the k-SAT problem is NP-complete.
So, three-SAT is NP-complete,
four-SAT is NP-complete, and so on.
What we're going to see now is a polynomial time algorithm for two-SAT.
So, there's a very interesting dichotomy for two-SAT,
that there's a polynomial time algorithm and we're going to
solve it using our strongly connected components algorithm.
And then, when k is at least three,
so three-SAT is NP-complete.
So let's dive into our algorithm for two-SAT.