Now, here's our specific two-SAT example from earlier,
and here's the graph corresponding to this Boolean formula.
Let's take a look at this graph and explore some properties of it.
Here's a particular path which is quite interesting.
We go from X_1, we follow this edge to X_2-bar,
to X_3, and then we can follow it to X_1-bar.
So, we have this path which goes from X_1 and ends up at X_1-bar.
Now this is a path of implications.
Each edge is an implication.
So, if we follow those implications out,
so if we set X_1 to be true,
we satisfy this literal,
then we're going to have to satisfy this literal.
How do we satisfy this literal?
By setting X_1 to be false.
So, if we set X_1 to be true,
then in order to satisfy the formula,
we have to set X_1 to be false.
That's clearly a contradiction.
So, there's no way we can satisfy the formula by setting X_1 to be true.
Now, what happens if we set X_1 to be false?
Well, there are no edges out of X_1-bar.
So, there are no implications from setting X_1 to be false.
So, it might be okay. We don't know.
We have to proceed with the other variables.
All we know is that,
because there is a path from X_1 to X_1-bar and clearly we cannot set X_1 to be true.
Now, what if there was a path from X_1 to X_1-bar and from X_1-bar to X_1?
Then we know that we can't set X_1 to be true,
because that would lead to a contradiction,
and we can't set X_1 to be false,
because that would lead to a contradiction.
So, there's no valid setting of X_1.
There's no setting of X_1,
which leads to a satisfying assignment.
Therefore, we can conclude that F is not satisfiable.
Now, we saw that if there is a path from X_1 to X_1-bar,
then we can't set X_1 to be true.
We cannot satisfy the formula by setting X_1 to be true.
Similarly, suppose there's a path from X_1-bar to X_1,
then we know that we can't set X_1 to be false.
So now, suppose that there is a path from X_1 to X_1-bar
and also there's a path from X_1-bar to X_1,
then what do we know about F?
Well, we know we can't set X_1 to be true and we know that we can't set X_1 to be false.
So in fact, there is no way to satisfy
the formula F. What does this mean about the graph?
If there is a path from X_1 to X_1-bar and from X_1-bar to X_1,
that means that these two vertices are in the same strongly connected component.
They're strongly connected with each other,
so they're in the same SCC.
So, if this literal and its negation are in the same SCC,
then this formula is not satisfiable.
And if this is true for any variable,
the positive literal X_i and X_i-bar are in the same SCC,
then the formula is not satisfiable.
What we're going to see is that if this is not true.
So, for every variable,
the literal and its negation are in different SCCs.
So, they never lie in the same SCC.
Then, in fact, we're going to find a satisfying assignment.
So, we're going to prove it satisfiable by finding a satisfying assignment.