Now let's formalize what we've just said.
If for some i, xi the positive literal
and the negative literal xi bar are both in the same SCC,
so these two literals are strongly connected with each other,
then the formula is not satisfiable.
We just solved why this is true,
because if we set xi to be true,
then we get a contradiction because we have to set xi to be false.
And if we set xi to be false,
then we get a contradiction because that leads to xi being true.
Now suppose this is not the case, for every i,
xi and xi bar are in different SCCs.
Now in this case f is satisfiable.
So for every i, xi and xi bar are in different strongly connected components,
then f is satisfiable.
We'll prove this part by finding a satisfying assignment.
So this statement that if xi and xi bar are in the same SCC then f is not satisfiable.
We already discussed why that's true.
For this one, where for every i,
xi and xi bar are in different strongly connected components we're
going to prove that f is satisfiable by finding a satisfying assignment.
So we're going to construct an algorithm which is
going to find a satisfying assignment and therefore we're
going to prove that f is satisfiable by actually
satisfying this f. Let's go ahead and construct the algorithm.
So we're going to assume that for every i,
xi and xi bar are in different strongly connected components.
And we're going to use that fact to construct a satisfying assignment for f.