Now let's finish off the rest of the proof of this key fact.
What have we shown so far?
We've shown that if we take a sink SCC S,
then its complement is a SCC.
Now we have to show that S bar is also a source SCC.
So we have to show that if this is a sink,
then this is a source.
Now, since S is a sink SCC,
if we take a vertex,
a literal in S,
then we know that alpha has no outgoing edges.
So there's no edges of the form alpha to beta for any beta.
Now, if there are no edges from alpha to beta,
then what does the claim imply?
That implies that there are no edges into alpha bar.
So if there are no outgoing edges from alpha,
then there are no incoming edges to alpha bar.
So if for all alpha in S there are no incoming edges to the complement of alpha,
then that means that the complement of S bar has no incoming edges.
So that means that as S bar is a source SCC.
So we've shown that if S is a sink SCC,
then by this claim,
S bar must be a source SCC.
And we can do the argument in reverse and show that if S bar is a source,
then S is a sink SCC.
So we've shown that if S is a sink SCC,
then S bar is a source SCC.
And that proves the key fact.
Now it just remains to prove this claim.