Now let's prove this claim that,
if there is a path from alpha to beta then there's
a path from beta bar to alpha bar, and vice versa.
So let's take a path from alpha to beta and let's
construct a path from beta bar to alpha bar.
Let's give some notation for the vertices along this path from alpha to beta.
So let's say this path from alpha to beta goes along
gamma0 to gamma1 and so on up to gammal.
So it starts at alpha,
so gamma0 is alpha and gammal is beta.
Now let's take one of these edges.
Let's look at the edge from gamma1 to gamma2.
How do we get an edge from gamma1 to gamma2?
Well this edge from gamma1 to gamma2 comes from this clause,
gamma1 bar or gamma 2.
Now every clause has two edges which it implies.
This is one of the edges. What's the other edge?
The other edge we get, the other implication is gamma2 bar implies gamma1 bar.
Similarly, if we look at this edge gamma0 to gamma1,
we're going to see that there's also an edge from gamma1 bar to gamma0 bar.
And if we look along this part of the path,
we're going to see that we get a path from gammal bar all the way over to gamma0 bar.
What is gammal bar?
This is beta bar. And what is gamma0 bar? It's alpha bar.
So what we've shown is that if there is a path from alpha to beta,
then there must be a path from beta bar to alpha bar,
and that's what we wanted to prove.
We wanted to prove that if there is a path from alpha to beta,
then we can show that there is a path from beta bar to alpha bar.
And then we can apply the same argument in reverse,
and we can show that if there is a path from beta bar to alpha bar,
and there's a path from alpha to beta.
That proves the claim,
and that completes the proof of correctness of our algorithm.
So we've completed the argument for the linear time algorithm for two set.