The input once again is specified by
an undirected graph G where the vertices correspond to the pixels.
And in addition, we have the following parameters;
for each pixel, we have two parameters, fi and bi.
Fi is the likelihood or weight that vertex i,
pixel i is in the foreground.
And bi is the weight or likelihood that pixel i is in the background.
Now, we'll assume that both of these parameters are non-negative.
In addition, we're given a parameter for each pair of neighboring pixels.
Pij is a separation penalty for this edge.
It's the cost of separating i and j into different objects.
And once again, we'll assume that pij is not negative.