This is our example of an image from before.
Let's look at an example setting of the parameters in this case.
Here are example settings for the foreground and background likelihood for this image.
So we're saying that the white pixels are more likely to be in
the foreground and the black pixels are more likely to be in the background.
For this image, we could have just as well reversed what we called foreground and
background since we've defined the matrix to be symmetric.
And here are sample separation penalties.
And when the pixels are different,
we don't pay any penalty for separating the pixels into different objects.
Now keep in mind, this is very much a toy example.
All the pixels are monochromatic.
So we've chosen very simple weights in this example.