Our goal is to partition the vertices of pixels into two sets F and B. F
will correspond to the foreground pixels and
capital B will be the pixels that we assign to the background.
Now, for a particular partition B,
we need some score or weight to measure the likelihood of this partition.
Thus, we defined the weight of this partition as the
following for each pixel assigned to the foreground we get
FB for each pixel assigned to the background we get
BJ have used different indices for these two sets to avoid some confusion.
Finally, we pay a separation penalty for separated edges.
This is a penalty so we're going to subtract it.
And, we're going to look at all edges where the first endpoint is
an F and the other end point is in B or vice versa.
And, the penalty is of course CIJ.
This defines the weight for a particular partition FB.
So, for a particular assignment of the pixels to
foreground and background we have a weight associated with it.
Our goal is to find the partition or assignment of
pixels to foreground and background with maximum weight.