Here is our new problem formulation.
The input is an undirected graph corresponding to the image,
once again, and we're given the following weights.
For each pixel, for each vertex I,
we're given fi and bi and these are non-negative weights.
And, for each edge,
we are given the weight Pij,
which is also non-negative.
And, our goal is to find the partition of the vertices or pixels into two sets,
F and B, and we want the partition which minimizes the weight,
w prime of FB.
Recall the partition, FB,
which minimizes w prime of FB,
is the same partition which maximizes w
of FB and therefore it solves the original image segmentation problem.
Now, let's see how to reduce this to the max flow problem.