So, we're going to add a vertex S,
a source vertex, corresponding to the foreground pixels.
Now, here's the same directed graph, once again,
with the vertices shrunk a little bit,
just for illustrative purposes.
Now, we're going to add two additional vertices,
S and t. S will correspond to the foreground,
t will correspond to the background,
and this will be our source and our sync for our max-flow problem.
We're going to add an edge from S to every pixel, every vertex.
So, for every pixel in the original undirected graph,
we add an edge from S to i.
Now, S is supposed to correspond to the foreground.
So, the capacity of this edge will be fi.
So, we encode the foreground likelihoods.