Now, to approve our main demo about the number of rounds of the Edmonds-Karp algorithm,
we're going to analyze the level of
a vertex during the course of the Edmonds-Karp algorithm.
Now, in particular we want to look at the vertex Z,
and we want to look at how it's level changes as the residual network changes.
Now, what can happen in the residual network?
Well, edges can get deleted.
For instance, suppose we delete this edge from A to D,
then what happens to the level of D?
Well, now the minimum number of edges to get from S to D is one, two, three.
So, D will be at level three.
So, the level of D will increase when we delete this edge from A to D. Now,
we're also going to add edges into the residual network.
For instance, what if we add an edge from B to D?
Or maybe we'll even add this edge back from A to D,
then will the level of D decrease back to level two.
Well, we're going to prove that that does not occur.
Even though we're adding edges into the residual network sometimes,
the level of vertex is never going to decrease.
We're going to prove, that for every vertex Z,
it's level over the course of the algorithm does not decrease.
It can stay the same or can increase in some levels.
But if for instance, this vertex D,
it's level increases to three,
then it can never go back down to two.
It can only stay the same or increase further.
Now, to prove this claim,
we have to understand which edges are added into the residual network,
and which edges are removed from the residual network.
So, let's look at that in more detail.