Here are the key conclusions that we need from this analysis.
If we add an edge from vertex y to vertex z to the residual network,
then what can we conclude?
Well that's this case, and this case.
Notice that in both of these cases,
the opposite direction edge is always on the augmenting path.
So if we add this edge from y to z to the residual network,
then we know that the edge from z to y is on the augmenting path.
Similarly, if we remove the edge from y to z from the residual graph,
then what can we conclude in this case?
Well, when we remove,
then we notice that the edge itself is on the augmenting path.
So in this case, we know that the edge from y to z is on the augmenting path.
So if we add an edge y to z to the residual graph,
then the opposite direction edge is on the augmenting path.
If we remove an edge,
then the edge itself is on the augmenting path.
This should make intuitive sense,
because to remove an edge from the residual graph,
that means we remove the leftover capacity.
In order to remove the leftover capacity,
that means we have to increase the flow along this edge.
To increase the flow along the edge,
the edge has to be on the augmenting path in order to augment along it.
To add an edge to the residual network,
we have to increase the spare capacity.
That means we have to decrease the flow along this edge.
To decrease the flow along an edge,
then the reverse direction edge must be augmented.
So it must be on the augmenting path.