We just showed that if we delete an edge v to w from
the residual network and later we add this edge back into the residual network,
then the level of this vertex v increase by at least two.
If we look at the level of vertex v before this deletion compared to after the insertion,
the level of the vertex increase by at least two.
Now, what do we know about the level of vertices?
The minimum level is zero,
that's for vertex S itself.
The maximum level is n. Therefore,
what's the maximum number of times that we can delete and
then add this edge back into the residual network?
We can delete it and then reinsert it back in at most n over two times.
Since there m edges in the graph,
this proves our main result that there is at
most nm rounds in the Edmonds-Karp algorithm.
And that completes the analysis of the Edmonds-Karp algorithm.