We've seen now how to find connected components in
undirected graphs and how to topologically sort a DAG.
Both of these algorithms involved one run of a vanilla version of DFS.
Now let's look at general directed graphs.
First we have to talk about what is the right analog
of connected components for directed graphs.
It turns out to be strongly connected components.
And then we'll see an algorithm to find
the strongly connected components of a general directed graph.
Now the amazing aspect is,
that we're going to find these strongly connected components with
just two runs of the vanilla version of DFS.
Let's dive into this algorithm and let's start by defining strongly connected components.