We're looking now at connectivity in directed graphs.
So the remainder of the lecture we're going to be talking about directed graphs.
First off, we have to talk about what is
the correct notion of connectivity between a pair of vertices.
So let us take a pair of vertices,
V and W and we we'll say they're strongly connected.
If there's a path from V to W and W to V. I have
this vertex V and this vertex W and there's a path from V to W,
it may pass through many vertices on the way and there's a path from
W to V that may pass through many vertices along the way and these paths may intersect.
So these vertices V and W are strongly connected.
So instead of connected components in undirected graphs,
the analog for directed graphs is going to be
strongly connected components which we'll denote as SCC.
Now an undirected graphs,
the connected component is a maximal set of connected vertices.
We keep adding in connected vertices as long as we can.
For directed graphs, strongly connected components
are the maximal set of strongly connected vertices.
So we keep adding in strongly connected vertices as long as we can.
Let's take a look at a specific example and mark
the strongly connected components in the example to make sure everybody understands it.