In this graph, there are five strongly connected components.
Let's go ahead and mark them.
An easy one to notice is A by itself.
Notice that from vertex A,
I can reach many other vertices but no other vertices can reach A,
so A is not strongly connected to any other vertices,
therefore A is a strongly connected component by itself.
These five vertices form a strongly connected component.
Notice that all five vertices are strongly connected with each other, in particular,
from vertex J, I can reach all of
the other vertices and all the other vertices can reach vertex A via I.
Similarly, these three vertices form a strongly connected component.
These two vertices B and E form a strongly connected component and D is
by itself because other vertices can reach D but D can't reach anybody else.
So I have these five strongly connected components,
A by itself, B and E, C, F,
G, D by itself and then H,
I, J, K, L are together.
I want to point out some interesting properties of
strongly connected components so I want to look at this graph on five vertices.
I'm going to make a meta vertex for each strongly connected component.
So when I have a meta vertex for A by itself,
B and E together C, F, G,
D and H through L. So I'm going to think of
compressing each of these purple blobs into a vertex,
a meta vertex and then there's going to be an edge from
this meta vertex to this meta vertex because there is an edge from some vertex in C, F,
G to some vertex in this strongly connected component namely from F to I
and similarly there will be an edge between
these meta vertices and these meta vertices and so on.
So when we look at this graph on the meta vertices
of strongly connected components we're going to see some interesting properties.