let's look back at our earlier example
and now we can illustrate our algorithm
for finding strongly connected
components in this example here's our
input graph G now this graph G had to
sink strongly connected components D by
itself and these five vertices formed a
strongly connected component now our
main observation from before was if we
ran DFS starting from one of these
vertices in the sink SEC so suppose we
ran DFS starting from this vertex K well
initially everybody's marked as
unvisited we want we set K to be visited
then we visit L I J and H and noticed no
other vertices in the graph are visited
so the only visited vertices are exactly
this strongly connected component
containing K so we can mark all the
vertices that were visited so far as
component 1 and then we can rip it out
of the graph and we can look at the
remainder of the graph and we can find a
sink SCC and the remainder of the graph
for example D will run explore from it
will find this component then the
remainder of the graph and we'll find
one of these vertices or an explore from
it find this component and continue
that's how our algorithm is gonna work
now how do we find this vertex in a sink
SCC well to do that we look at the
reverse graph here's the reverse graph
it's got the same vertex set we simply
flipped all the edges so this has an
edge from B to D this has an edge from D
to B now what we claimed is that if we
run DFS on this graph of the reverse
graph the vertex with the highest post
number is gonna lie in a source SCC in
this graph what are the source strongly
connected components in this reverse
graph it's these five vertices and D so
the sink SEC is over here in the
original input graph our source SCC is
over here in the reverse graph the
vertex with the highest post number is
gonna lie in one of these source
strongly connected components and
therefore it lies in our sink SCC in the
original graph so let's run DFS on this
graph here's an example run of DFS on
this reversed graph and I'll make
arbitrary choices for the order on the
vertices and on the neighbors so let's
choose a vertex to start DFS from let's
say we start from vertex C
we'll give see pre-order number one and
then from see we visit G and we give it
pre-order number two then we go to F
from F there's nobody left to explore so
we give it its pre-order number and it's
post order number only popped back up to
G and so on let me skip ahead from C
these are the vertices that we can visit
we can see G F B a and E and this is one
example of the DFS tree that we see and
these are the preorder and postorder
numbers that will get now DFS will
continue to an unfitted vertex let's say
D from D we can't get anywhere so it'll
just stop I'll give it a preorder and
postorder number then finally we'll get
one of these five vertices starting from
L this is the DFS tree we get for this
component and here's the preorder and
postorder numbers and notice the vertex
with the highest post order number is
vertex L which is in this source SCC
well you may think well the go-to
started at vertex C if he would have
started at one of these vertices then
the vertex with the highest post order
number would not lie in this component
but in fact if we would have started the
DFS from one of these five vertices then
who can be visited from that vertex well
we can visit all this graph except for D
so all these other vertices will be in
the subtree say of L so they'll all get
post order numbers which are smaller
than L and then finally we'll go to D
and D will be the last vertex visited
it'll have the highest post order number
so we'll still get a vertex with the
highest post order number lying in a
source SCC so let's take this vertex L
it has the highest post order number in
this DFS run that's the important
property that we needed now later we're
gonna explore all these vertices in this
component and then we're gonna need the
vertex with the highest post order
number of the remaining vertices so in
order to obtain that it'll be useful to
have all these vertices sorted by their
decreasing post order number so let's do
that so this is a list of vertices of
the original graph or the reverse graph
sorted by decreasing post order number
from this DFS run on the reverse graph
and now we're done with the reverse
graph and we can go back to our original
graph
here's our input graph once again now
what are we gonna do we're gonna run DFS
starting from this vertex L when we run
from L who do we visit we visit i j k
and h now as we visit these vertices
let's cross them out to mark that
they're visited and let's assign them a
strongly connected component number so
our mark these five vertices are
strongly connected component number one
now we need to continue DFS who do we
want to continue from we want to look at
this graph and we want to find a sink in
this remaining graph so who are we gonna
choose we're gonna choose the vertex
with the highest post order number of
the remaining vertices in this case it's
D so we run DFS from D we Explorer from
D D becomes visited and we mark it with
component number two then we run from C
we see these three vertices and we mark
them with component number three then we
take the highest post order number of
the unvisited vertices B in this case we
explore from B who do we see we see B
and E that would be component 4 finally
a that's component 5 valla
we have our strongly connected
components and the vertices are labeled
by their strongly connected component
number and one other very cool feature
what do you notice about these strongly
connected component numbers here are the
five strongly connected components
notice there's an edge from meta vertex
3 to meta vertex 1 from 4 to 1 and so on
these are the rest of the edges in the
meta graph now what do you notice about
these edges they all go right to left so
notice we've outputted these strongly
connected ponens in Reverse topological
order so it's quite amazing we've done
two runs of DFS one on the reverse graph
and one on the original graph and what
we found are the strongly connected
components of the original graph and we
output it these strongly connected
components in topological order or to be
precise in Reverse topological order so
we can take any directed graph a general
directed graph and with two runs of DFS
we can find it's strongly connected
components and we can structure these
strongly connected components in
topological order
let's formalize this algorithm