Let us take a look at one of our flow network examples from earlier.
And let us look at the feasible flow problem in this example.
So here is a directed graph with the specified start and end vertex.
Let's mark the demand and the capacities along every edge.
The green numbers specify the demand along
the edge and the red numbers specify the capacity along the edge.
So along this edge we want the flow to be at least two units and at most eight units.
Along this edge, there is no demand constraint.
It has got to be at least zero and at most three.
Here it has got to be at least three and at most six.
Is there a feasible flow for this example?