So let's dive into the reduction.
So let's take a particular input for the feasible flow problem.
This is specified by a directed graph G,
capacities along the edges and demands along the edges.
Now we need this to construct an input for the max flow problem.
This is specified by a directed graph which we'll call
G prime and capacities along the edges which was specified by C prime.
Now these capacities don't have to be the same as the original capacities.
In fact, we need these capacities to
encode not just the capacities in the original graph,
but also the demands in the original graph.
Let's take a look at a particular example, very simple example,
here's a small example of four vertices,
this is our directed graph G,
which is our input to the feasible flow problem.
That specified some example capacities and demands.
We've written a pair of numbers for each edge.
The first number, for example three,
specifies the demand, and the second number specifies the capacity.
Now let's try to create a graph G prime.
Well we want to keep all this information,
so we're going to keep the same graph G and we're going to add additional vertices to it.
So this is going to be our directed graph
G prime which is going to be the input to the max flow problem.
So we're going to start with the same graph G that
was the input to the feasible flow problem and we're going to add
a new start vertex which will denote is as
prime and a new n vertex which will denote as t prime.
So the original s and t will now serve as internal vertices.
Now these are the vertices of this new graph G prime.
Let's now look at the edges that are in this graph and
also the capacities and along the edges in this new graph.