Now the edges in the original flow network G,
remain in this new flow network G prime.
What will change is the capacities along these edges.
Now we want the capacities along these edges to
capture the capacities along the original network,
and the demands in the original network.
What we want to capture is that there is non-negative flow along an edge,
if and only if we can construct a flow in the original network,
where the flow is at least the demand.
And we also want that the flow in this new graph G prime,
satisfies this new capacity constraint,
if and only if this flow f,
that we're going to construct,
satisfies the capacity constraint in the original network.
Now, the idea is that we want to flow zero in
this new network to correspond to flow d in this original network.
So this flow is going to be a shift of this flow by d units.
So, were going to shift the capacity as well by d units.
So the capacities along these edges,
which were edges in the original network,
will be the original capacities minus the demand.
So, whereas this edge from s to a originally had capacity 10,
now it'll have capacity seven.
This edge will have a capacity of one,
four, four, and also four.