Now, there's one additional edge that I almost forgot to
mention in this graph G prime that we're constructing.
Now, notice in the original graph S is the start vertex and T is the end vertex.
In this new graph,
S and T are internal vertices.
So, the flow in has to equal the flow-out for both these vertices.
Whereas over here, we don't have that constraint.
Notice there's no flow-in.
There's no capacity into this vertex,
S and T has no capacity.
So, in the current set up we don't have any flow into S and any flow out of
T. How do we get around that so that we can have the
flow-in S equal to the flow-out and similarly for T?
Well, we know the flow-out of S equals the flow into T,
so we simply have to offset the flow-out of T and the flow-in to S. So,
we compare these up with each other.
So, we're going to add this edge from T to
S. And we don't have any constraints on the flow along this edge,
our flow goes into T. We want to send that back to S. So,
we give this edge capacity infinity.
So, to summarize, we're adding this edge from T to S and the capacity is infinite.
Now, we really have completed our construction of this graph G prime.