Now in order to show that this flow F is valid,
we need to show that for every vertex,
the flow in equals the flow out of the vertex.
Now this is for every internal vertex.
So this is for every vertex in the original graph except for S
and T. Now this is for the flow F that we constructed.
Now what do we know?
We know that this flow F prime was an output from the max flow problem.
So F prime is a valid flow for the graph G prime.
So we know in this graph G prime,
the flow into the vertex V equals the flow out from
the vertex V. So we want to use this fact to imply this fact.
So let's take a look at this first quantity.
The flow into the vertex V in this graph G prime.
Now which vertices have edges to the vertex V?
This is in the graph G prime that we constructed.
While this new vertex S prime has an edge to every vertex.
So there's an edge from S prime to V and for every vertex in the original graph,
if U was connected to V in the original graph,
then it's still connected in this new graph G prime.
Now what do we know about this first term?
We assume that F prime was a saturating flow.
That means that all the edges out of S prime are fully capacitated.
So this flow along this edge is up to its full capacity.
What's the capacity of this edge?
It was defined to be the demand into the vertex V. Now what about this latter quantity?
Well let's rewrite this flow F prime along this edge in terms of
F. The flow F along this edge from U to V was,
by our definition, equal to the flow of F prime along this edge plus the demand.
Therefore, F prime equals F along this edge minus the demand along this edge.
That we can factor out this sum over U to each of these terms
and then this latter quantity is minus the sum over U
of the demand into V. So that sum is equal to the demand into
V. So this term and this term cancel each other out and what are we left with?
We're left with the flow into V in this flow F. So that means the flow into V under
this flow F prime is equal to the flow into V in
this flow F. Now that's not too surprising because we set up this flow,
this capacity along this edge from S prime to offset this difference.
So this was by design but we have this nice fact,
the flow into V is the same in F prime and in F and similarly you can show
that the flow out of V under F prime and F are the same by similar algebra.
So therefore, if the flow into V is the same as the flow out of V under
F prime and F prime and F have the same flow into V and the same flow out of V,
then we also have this statement that we want to prove.
So we've shown that F is a valid flow.
So we've shown that we can take a saturating flow F prime and we can construct
a feasible flow F by simply setting F
equal to the flow F prime plus the demand along the edge.
Now we have to prove the reverse direction.