To prove the reverse direction,
what we want to do now is take a feasible flow f in the graph G,
and we want to construct a saturating flow f-prime in this new graph G-prime.
Now for each edge of the original network G,
we're going to define the new flow along that edge to be
the old flow shifted down by the demand along this edge.
Now that defines a flow for all the edges in the original network.
What about the new edges that we added to
this graph G-prime when we did the construction?
Well for every vertex in the original network,
we have an edge from s-prime and edge to t-prime.
So we have this edge from s-prime to v and v to t-prime.
Now we're trying to construct a saturating flow.
So each of these edges is supposed to be fully capacitated.
So we might as well set this flow to be equal to its capacity which is the total demand
into v for this edge and the total demand out of v for the edge two t-prime.
That defines a flow f-prime for all the edges except for one.
We have this edge from t to s which had infinite capacity.
We want to set the flow along this edge to be equal to
the size of this flow f. That defines the flow f-prime.
Now we have to check that f-prime is valid and it's a saturating flow.