Now we know that f is feasible. What does that mean?
That means that the flow along this edge E is at least its demand.
Now f-prime along this edge E is defined to be f along this edge minus the demand.
So since this is true,
we have the flow f-prime along this edge is at least zero.
So f-prime is non-negative.
Similarly, we have that f is at most its capacity.
Therefore, f-prime is at most the capacity minus
the demand which is the definition of the capacity in this network G-prime.
So we know that this new flow f-prime that we constructed
is non-negative and satisfies the capacity constraints.
Now we simply have to check that
f-prime satisfies the flow in equals the flow out constraint.