So we need to check that the flow into every vertex,
except for S prime and T prime,
under F prime, equals the flow out.
Now we started from F,
and we know that the flow into the vertex V, under F,
equals the flow out from the vertex V.
So now we're going to do a little bit of algebra that's similar to before.
So we want to go from this fact, to this fact.
Now, what is the flow into the vertex V under F prime?
Where we have the flow from S prime,
we set that equal to the demand into the vertex V. So this is the flow from S prime.
Now for every other edge,
the flow from that vertex U to V in F prime,
is it defined to be the flow in F minus the demand along this edge?
As before, this sum over U of this demand into V is the same as this quantity.
They're both equal to the total demand into V. So they offset each other,
and we're left with the total flow into V under F. So as before,
the flow into V under F,
is the same as the flow into V under F prime.
And similarly, the flow out of V under F prime,
equals the flow out of V under F, by similar calculation.
Therefore, since the flow into V equals the flow out of V under F,
and these are equal to F prime,
we also have this factor F prime.
And therefore, F prime is a va.