Linear programming is a very general technique for solving optimization problems.
It handles any problem that can be formulated as
an optimization over a set of variables with
a goal known as the objective function and
the constraints can all be expressed as linear functions of the variables.
We'll see that max flow can be formulated as a linear program.
Also, we'll see that many problems from operations research can be expressed as LPs.
We'll describe the general idea of
the simplex algorithm which is widely used for solving LPs.
We'll take a closer look at one of the beautiful aspects
of linear programming, LP duality.
We'll explain what LP duality is and some of the useful consequences for us.
Finally, we'll look at an application of LP to approximation algorithms.
We'll use linear programming to design
an approximation algorithm to the classic set problem.