Let's take a look at a simple example of a linear program.
This is motivated by a basic production problem.
Consider a company that makes two products,
let's call them A and B.
We want to figure out how many of each product
to produce in order to maximize our profit.
Now let's make some modeling assumptions.
Each unit of A that we sell makes a profit of one dollar and for each unit of B,
we'll assume that it makes a profit of six dollars.
Now let's make some assumptions about the demand for each product.
We'll assume that the demand for A is
at most 300 units per day and at most 200 units per day for B.
We'll also assumes some supply constraints.
We'll assume our employees can work at most 700 hours per
day and each unit of A that we produce takes one hour,
whereas each unit of B takes three hours.
Now let's express this is as a linear.