First off, what are the variables in our linear program?
What we're trying to determine how many units of A and B to produce each day?
Hence, let x1 be the number of units of A that we should produce
per day and x2 is the number of units of B to produce per day.
Our goal is to maximize the profit.
So we have a maximization problem.
Now, how do we express the profit in terms of x1 and x2?
Well, we make a profit of $1 per unit of A,
so that's x1 and $6 per unit of B that we sell.
So, that's 6x2.
Now what are the constraints?
First off, the demand constraint.
Well, we want to make at most 300 units of A.
So, this means that x1 is at most 300 and x2 is at most 200.
Now, also we want x1 and x2 to be non-negative.
We can't produce a negative amount of any of the products.
So, let's throw in these non-negative constraints.
Now let's look at the supply constraint.
The total supply, the total number of man hours available is
700 and it takes one hour per unit of A and three hours per unit of B.
So, we want that x1 plus 3x2 is at most 700.