Now let's go ahead and restate the LP we just formulated.
Our objective function was to maximize X_1 plus 6_x_2.
Recall, this was a profit we obtained.
Now,this was subject to the following constraints.
First off, the demand for X_1 product A was at most 300 units.
For Product B the demand was at most 200 units,
so X_2 is at most 200.
We need it to ensure that these variables are non-negative.
Finally, we have the supply constraint.
Now let's look at this problem geometrically.
For now let's ignore the objective function and let's look at the five constraints.
Now each of these five constraints is a half plane.
If it was equality, it would be a line,
but we're doing one side of the line.
So, this gives us a half plane.
Now note, we're in two dimensions because we have two variables.
Now we want to satisfy all five constraints,
so we want to look at the intersection of these five half planes.
The intersection of these five a half planes is going to give us a set of feasible X.
A set of X which satisfy all five constraints and then we're going to
look in that feasible set to find the X which maximizes this objective function.
So let's first look at this feasible region.