let's take a look pictorially at these
five constraints now once again we have
two variables so we're in
two-dimensional space
now our first constraint says that x1 is
a most 300 so we have this line x1
equals 300 and we're looking at the left
side all points on the left side of this
line the second constraint is that x2 is
the most 200 so we're looking at our
points below this line and we want
points satisfying both constraints so
we're looking at the points in the
bottom left quadrant of these two
vectors next we have the non-negative
constraints putting in both non-negative
constraints now we lie in this rectangle
and then we have our final our fifth
constraint which says that we lie on
this side of this line hence this tan
region is our feasible region all the
points in this tan region in this convex
polygon satisfy all five constraints