Now, how do we find the optimal point?
Our goal is to maximize this function x1 plus 6x2.
So, let's look at this line x1 plus 6x2 equal C. We're trying to maximize the C,
which intersects this feasible region.
So, let's find the maximum value of this C,
where this linear function intersects the feasible region.
So, let's take a look at this function,
this linear function for different values of C. Now,
here's the line x1 plus 6x2 equals 600.
Now, all these points on the line which intersect the feasible region,
so these points, all satisfy the five constraints and achieve profit of 600.
Now, clearly these are not optimal because we can move up this line.
Now, we can think of moving up this line into
the last point when we intersect the feasible region.
Now, it turns out the maximum value of C for which
this line intersects the feasible region is C equals 1300.
This line x1 plus 6x2 equals
1300 intersects the feasible region at this corner of this polygon,
this vertex of this feasible region.
This is the point 100, 200.
So, we know the optimum is at the point x1 equals
100 and x2 equals 200 and that achieves a profit of 1300.
Now, this was a simple two dimensional example.
Let's look at a simple three dimensional example and then we'll
get some idea of how it generalizes to higher dimensions.