Let's take a look at another example before
giving the general formulation of linear programming.
Now this will be a slight twist on the previous example.
Now we have three products A,
B and C. We'll look at the profit obtained from each,
the demand for each,
the supply just as before and we'll add one additional constraint compared to before,
this will be a packaging constraint.
We'll say the profit is one dollar for each unit of A that we sell,
six dollars for each unit of B and ten dollars for C.
The demand is at most 300 units per day for A and at most
200 units per day for B and unlimited demand for
C. The supply that we can produce is at most 1000 hours per day.
Each unit of A takes one hour,
each unit of B takes three hours to produce and
each unit of C takes two hours to produce, finally the packaging.
Now we can produce at most 500 units in total per day.
We'll say that A doesn't require any packaging,
B uses one unit of packaging per unit and C takes three units of the packaging per unit.