Let's recap our LP once again.
Our objective function is to maximize x1 plus 6x2 plus 10x3.
Subject to the following seven constraints.
We have the two demand constraints.
We have the supply constraint,
the packaging constraint and finally the non-negativity constraint.
Now, let's take a look at this geometrically.
Now, we have three variables,
so we're going to line three dimensional space.
Now, if we had equality for one of these constraints,
there would be a hyperplane,
a three dimensional hyperplane.
Now, within inequality we're taking one side of that hyperplane.
So that's a half space.
So we're looking at the intersection of these seven half spaces.
This is a geometric view of the feasible region.
The points in this ten polyhedron are the feasible axes.
These are the points which satisfy all seven constraints.
Now, notice this is a convex set,
so it can't go down and then back up.
Convexity is an important property for the algorithms to solve linear programs.
Now, let's take a look at the general formulation of linear programs and then
we'll come back to this example and we'll figure out the optimum for this example.