Let's look at the standard form for linear programs.
We have n variables x1 through xn.
Our objective function is to maximize a linear function of these n variables.
We have these coefficients, c1 through cn,
and we're maximizing this linear function of the n variables.
We're optimizing subject to the m constraints.
The first constraint is specified by a11 through a1n.
These are the coefficients for x1 through xn.
We want that this linear function is at most b1 for a given b1.
This is the first constraint.
There are n constraints.
The mth constraint is specified by am1 through amn,
that specifies the left hand side and we want this to be a most mn.
And finally, we also have the non-negativity constraint.
We want that these n variables are non-negative.
We have m plus n constraints.
We can specify this more compactly using linear algebra.
Let's go ahead and do that.