Now the variables are specified by this column vector x.
The objective function is specified by these coefficients,
this column vector c, and hence
our objective function is to maximize c_transpose times x.
Then we have our constraint matrix.
This is an m by n matrix A.
Finally we have the constraints for the right hand side.
This is specified by this column vector, b1 through bm.
There're m constraints, so this vector has size m. Going back to our Lp formulation,
we have our objective function.
This is subject to the following constraints.
We want those x where A times x is at most b,
and we have the non-negativity constraint, x is non-negative.
Now the last constraint is important, the non-activity constraint,
because if the feasible region is non-empty,
so there are some feasible x,
then we know that the zero vector is a feasible point.
So we can trivially find a feasible point or determine that the feasible region is empty,
and therefore this Lp is infeasible.