Now in general, we have n variables.
So we're going to line n dimensional space.
Now n is large,
so we're in high dimensional space.
Now we m constraints plus the n non-negativity constraints.
So we have a total n plus m constraints.
Now what's our feasible region?
Now, each constraint corresponds to a half space and n dimensions.
Now the feasible region are those points which satisfy all n plus m constraints.
So we want to lie in all n plus m half spaces.
So the feasible region corresponds to the intersection of these n plus m half spaces.
Now this is going to correspond to a convex polyhedron in n dimensional space.
Now the vertices of this polyhedron are the corners of it.
Now how do you get a vertex of this polyhedron?