Now, how do you specify the vertices of the feasible region?
Well, let's take a look back at our simple two dimensional example.
How do I specify this vertex of this polygon?
It satisfies these two lines with equality.
The first line is X1 equals 300 and the second line is X1plus 3X2 equals 700.
Now, satisfying these two constraints with equality specifies this point,
but then I have to check that this point satisfies the other inequalities.
So in general, in n dimensional space,
a vertex of this convex polyhedron is specified
by specifying the end constraints that you satisfy with equality,
and then we have to check that the remaining m constraints are still satisfied.
Now we can get a trivial upper bound on the number of vertices of this convex polyhedron,
we have to specify the constraints that are satisfied with equality.
There are n plus m constraints to choose from.
So the number of vertices is most n plus m, choose n,
this is exponential in n. So in the worst case,
there are a huge number of vertices in this convex polyhedron,
in this feasible region.
Now for a particular vertex,
how many neighbors does it have?
Can we get an upper bound on the number of neighbors for a specific vertex?
Well, neighbor would correspond to swapping out
one constraint with equality with a different constraint.
So we have n choices for which one we swap out,
and then we have m choices for which when we swap in.
So the number of neighbors for a specific vertex is at most, n times m.