Now let's give a quick overview of the type of algorithms for solving linear programs.
Now there are two types of methods which are guaranteed to solve
linear programs in polynomial time in the worst case.
These are the ellipsoid algorithm which was the first example of
a polynomial time algorithm for linear programming and interior point methods.
Now ellipsoids algorithms are more of theoretical interest,
but interior point methods are used quite extensively right now.
Now an important algorithm is the simplex algorithm.
As a disclaimer for the simplex algorithm is
that in the worst case it takes exponential time.
Despite that worst case bound,
simplex algorithm is widely used because the output of
the simplex algorithm first off is guaranteed to be an optimal.
So when the simplex algorithm completes,
it's guaranteed to give an optimal solution to
the linear program and it works quite efficiently,
very fast on a humongous LPs.
There are very fast LP solvers using the simplex algorithm.
We're going to take a look at the high level idea of the simplex algorithm.