In this section, we'll look at the graph problem,
known as the Max-flow problem.
It's a quite useful problem.
We'll first look at basic algorithm for the problem,
known as a Ford Fulkerson Algorithm,
and then we'll prove correctness of the Ford Fulkerson Algorithm.
And along the way,
we'll get the classic result known as the Max-flow- min-cut theorem.
Next, we'll look at the nice application of
the Max-flow problem to computer vision known as the Image Segmentation problem.
We'll also look at a more general version of the problem,
Max-flow with additional demand constraints,
and we'll see how to reduce this more general problem to the original Max-flow problem.
Finally, we'll see a faster Algorithm for the Max-flow problem,
known as the Edmonds-Karp Algorithm.