This lesson is about the max flow problem.
First, we'll focus on algorithms for solving the max flow problem.
We'll start with the Ford-Fulkerson algorithm
and then we'll look at the Edmonds-Karp algorithm.
Both of these algorithms are very simple,
but the analysis of the running time of Edmonds-Karp algorithm is a bit more involved.
After that, we're going to look at the very beautiful and very important theorem
known as the max flow equals min-cut theorem.
Now, this theorem will imply correctness of
the Ford-Fulkerson and Edmonds-Karp algorithms.
It will also be key for several of our applications.
In particular, we'll look at solving
the image segmentation problem using the max flow problem.
Now, in the image segmentation problem,
we're given an image and we want to separate it
into the foreground and background components.
We'll solve this using
the max flow problem and utilizing the max flow equals min- cut theorem.