The general setting is that we're sending supply from
vertex s to vertex t. Now, what does this supply?
The supply might be things like Internet traffic,
or it might be a product.
Now, the network is specified by a directed graph,
and we have a designated start vertex s,
and we have a designated end vertex t. And our goal is to maximize
the amount of supply sent from s to t along the edges of this network,
but we don't want to exceed the capacities of the edges.
So, for each edge we have a capacity of that edge.
If you think of supply as an example such as
Internet traffic then the capacity corresponds to the bandwidth of the link.
If you think of a more physical example such as supply being oil,
then we're maximizing the amount of oil sent from point s to point t in this network.
And then the edges correspond to actual pipes,
and then these numbers correspond to the capacity of these pipes.