Now let's formally state the max flow problem.
The input to the max flow problem is what is called a flow network.
A flow network consists of
a directed graph G. Here's an example of a directed graph again.
Now in this directed graph we have two vertices labeled s and t,
corresponding to the source and the sync for the flow in our problem.
Finally for each edge,
we're given a capacity which is a positive number.
Here are the example capacities from before for this network.
And our goal is to maximize the flow which is sent from s to
t. So the flow originates at s and it ends at
t. Now we use the variable f_sub_e to denote
the flow along edge e. Now these are the variables which we're trying to determine.
So our goal is to specify the flow along
every edge so that we maximize the flow from s to t.