Now, here's a flow of maximum size.
The flow is specified by the green numbers along every edge and their capacities,
once again, are specified by the red numbers along every edge.
Now, notice for every vertex,
the flow in equals the flow out.
For instance, for vertex c,
the flow in is seven and the flow out is seven.
For vertex e, the flow in is one plus one which is two and the flow out is two.
For vertex d, the flow in is seven and the flow out is seven.
And all of the flows along the edges are
upper bounded by the capacities along those edges.
And finally, the total flow size is of size 12.
This is 12 units of flow coming out of s
and there's 12 units of flow coming into t. Now for this example,
why do we know that this is the maximum flow?
What the total capacity of edge is coming into t is 12,
so the maximum amount of flow that can come into t is at
most,12 and we've achieved that therefore,
we've achieved the maximum flow.