Now, one interesting feature of this example,
is that there is a cycle in this graph.
There's a cycle that goes from C to F,
to E, to D and back to C. Now,
this is a cycle in the original input graph in the flow network.
Now, we've seen for some other examples
such a shortest path problem that cycles in the input graph can cause some issues.
In that formulation, it's negative weight cycles which cause problems.
So a natural question is whether cycles are
okay in a flow network for the max flow problem.
Notice that a flow network has a cycle but our flow,
our maximum flow is not utilizing this cycle.
And why is it not utilizing this cycle?
Well, suppose that I had one unit of flow coming into D and then I send one unit flow
along this entire cycle back to T and then send that one unit out of D. Well,
I could just send it right from this edge into D and then out of
D directly without going around the cycle so I could have bypassed the cycle.
So there's no reason to utilize a cycle in a flow network.
Now I may want to utilize part of this cycle and I don't
know a priority which part of the cycle I might want to utilize.
So the main conclusion is that cycles are okay in a flow network.
In fact they simplify the problem in some sense but the problem is
well-defined regardless of whether there are cycles in the flow network or not.