Before we dive into algorithms for the max-flow problem,
let's look at one slight simplification of the input.
Here's an example flow network.
Notice that there are edges from A to B,
and also an edge from B to A.
These are anti-parallel edges, we'll call them.
Now, I'd like to remove these anti-parallel edges.
Why we want to remove these anti-parallel edges will become clear
later when we come up with our algorithms for the max-flow problem.
But for now, let's just say,
we want to simplify the input a little bit.
So I wanted to find an equivalent flow network,
and work with that equivalent flow network,
and in that equivalent flow network,
I don't have any anti-parallel edges.
So let's put some capacities on these edges.
So here are the edge capacities for this flow network.
Now we wanted to find an equivalent flow network,
and I wanted this flow network to not have any anti-parallel edges.
I want to remove this anti-parallel edges here,
and I want the max-flow,
and that equivalent network to be the same as the max-flow here.
This is the new network I want to consider.
So I just split this edge from B to A,
into a path of length two,
and I added one auxiliary vertex,
and the edge capacity stay the same.
This single edge had a capacity of three.
Now it gives both of these edges capacity three,
and notice that these two flow networks are equivalent to each other?
I can easily convert a solution to the max-flow problem on
one network to the other network and vice versa.