Now what are we missing in this graph of available capacities?
Well, if we reverse engineer a little bit and we look at the optimal solution,
we see that we want to augment along this path.
So we'd like to augment the current flow along this path from s to b,
b to a and a to t. In this way,
we want to increase the flow along this edge,
s to b, in this edge,
a to t, to seven.
But what does it mean to augment along this edge from b to a?
There's no such edge in this flow network.
We'll think about this as a pipe.
So when we send flow along this edge,
a to b, we're opening up faucet.
So we're sending more flow along this pipe.
If we send flow from b to a,
it's like we're closing the faucet,
so we're sending less flow from a to b.
The point is that this graph of available capacities is not properly
representing everything that's possible to do from this current flow.
In particular, we want to send an edge from b to a,
and this edge should have available capacity 10. Why 10?
Because the current flow from a to b is 10 units.
So, if we send at most 10 units of flow from b to a,
that corresponds to decreasing the flow from a to b.
Now if we look at this graph,
this is no longer the graph of available capacities.
This graph is called the residual network.
And in this graph, we can find a path from s to t. Namely,
we can find this path that we're looking for,
you go s to b, b to a and a to t. The capacity of this path is seven units.
So we can augment the flow by seven units along this path.
So the flow from s to b will change to seven units,
we'll send seven units from b to a by decreasing the flow from a to b by seven units,
so it will go down from 10 to three.
And from a to t,
the flow will increase by seven units.
And then, we'll be at a Max-flow for this example.
So the key idea is to look at
the residual network instead of the network of available capacities.