Now we can state the Ford-Fulkerson algorithm.
This is going to follow the same basic approach we did before,
but instead of considering the graph of available capacities,
we're instead going to consider the residual network.
We're going to start by initializing the flow to zero everywhere,
then we build the residual network for the current flow.
Initially, the residual network will be the same as the input flow network.
Now we look for a path from s to t in this residual network.
How do we look for the path?
Once again we use DFS or BFS.
If there is no such path the,
n we stop the algorithm and we output the current flow as
our output as the max flow for this graph.
If instead we found such a path,
let's first denote this path by cal P,
now given this path cal P,
let's define the capacity of this path.
This is the minimum capacity along this path in the residual network.
So look at the edges in this path,
look at the capacities of these edges in the residual network.
Finally, we augment the current flow by c(P) units along this path.
What exactly does it mean to augment the flow?
Well, for every forward edge we increase the flow along that edge by this amount.
For every backward edge,
we decrease the flow in the other direction,
in the reverse direction by this amount.
Finally, we'll repeat from step 2,
build the residual network and check for an st-path
and we continue repeating until there is no such st-path.
And then we output the current flow as our solution to the max flow problem.