In this lecture, we're going to look at the PageRank algorithm.
This is an algorithm for assigning the importance of a webpage.
Now, what exactly do we mean by importance?
Well, this is a subjective term,
but we're going to give a precise quantitative interpretation of importance.
Now, the PageRank algorithm is the algorithm devised by
Brin and Page which is at the heart of Google search engine.
Now, the PageRank algorithm itself is fairly simple,
but to fully understand the algorithm,
we have to first understand some basic mathematical tools known as Markov chains.
Now, I'm going to give you a quick primer on Markov chains.
What exactly are Markov chains?
And what are the key properties of Markov chain?
Now, the PageRank algorithm is itself
a Markov chain but Markov chain is come up quite often.
For example, you may have heard of the term MCMC,
That stands for Markov chain Monte Carlo.
Also, you may have heard of simulated annealing,
which is another example of a Markov chain.
Now, we're not going to look at these two examples in detail,
but if you understand Markov chain,
the basics of Markov chains,
then that'll help you understand
these more sophisticated concepts if you decide to delve into them in more detail.
Now, the key concept for Markov chain is the notion of a stationary distribution.
So, I'm going to spend some time explaining to you what
exactly does a stationary distribution mean.
How do we determine what the stationary distribution are and what are
the important properties of a Markov chain which
connect to the notion of a stationary distribution?
Finally, once we understand Markov chains and stationary distributions for Markov chains,
then we will be able to fully appreciate
the PageRank algorithm and the design choices in the design of the PageRank algorithm.
Now, let's go ahead and dive into a Markov chain and look
at a specific example of a Markov chain.