Now if we look at this entry (i,j) , in this matrix P,
this transition matrix P,
corresponding to the way to the adjacency matrix.
This tells me the probability of making the transition from I to J in one step.
So if I'm in state I at time T,
then PIJ is the probability that I'm in State J at time T plus one.
Now what we just saw is that if we look at the square of
the transition matrix, so P squared,
then the entry (i,j) tells me the probability of going
from state I to state J in two steps.
And in general for any non-negative integer K,
P to the K. So the Kth power of this transition matrix
P. This tells me the probability of making a transition in exactly K steps.