Now another pitfall that can happen is if
our underlying graph has multiple strongly connected components,
for example in this graph,
there are three strongly connected components.
Now look, if we start at one of
these three vertices we're only going to reach these three vertices.
If we start at one of these two vertices,
we only reach these two vertices.
So the starting state definitely matters.
What we would like is that the graph has one strongly connected component.
The terminology for this is that P is irreducible.
If the graph has one strongly connected component,
every pair of vertices are strongly connected with each other,
then the transition matrix is irreducible.
Now what's an easy way to assure that the graph is one strongly connected component,
while connect up every pair of vertices.
So make it the complete graph.
For all pairs of states i and j,
we make the entry p (ij) be strictly greater than zero.
So there's a positive probability of going between every pair of vertices.
The matrix P is all positive,
and therefore the graph is fully connected,
so it's one strongly connected component.
This is the easiest way to ensure that the graph is
one strongly connected component and therefore irreducible.