So imagine you're studying for your PhD,
and you're trying to come up with some measure for the importance of web pages.
So you might think of the analogy with academic papers.
What's the importance of an academic paper?
How do you measure the importance of an academic paper?
Well one way that we still use,
is using citation counts.
How many other papers cite your paper?
What does that mean in terms of web pages?
Well might be the number of links,
hyperlinks to your web page.
So our first idea for defining the rank of a page x,
is to define pi of x to be the number of links to the page x,
number of hyperlinks to the web page x.
In terms of the graph, this means we're going to look at the number of in neighbors to x.
How many edges come into x.