So here was our first idea.
We set the rank of a page X to be the number of links into the page X.
So pi of X is the in degree of x.
Now what's the obvious problems with this?
Well, here's a simple example.
Let's suppose that Georgia Tech has a webpage which lists all the faculty,
okay that's probably true,
and the faculty list is probably like a thousand long.
One of those is going to link to my webpage.
So one out of a thousand of these links links to my webpage.
Now let's suppose that Georgia Tech's front page or the COCs front page
has only five links on it and one of those happens to be the kishore's webpage.
Now in the current measure of the rank of a page X,
I get a plus one for this link and Kishore gets a plus one for this link.
So both of those links count the same for us.
Now that doesn't seem so fair.
This is one out of a thousand,
this is one out of five.
So how do we get around it.
Well, the obvious way is to scale it by the number of links.
Now the natural solution to this problem is if
George Tech's webpage has a thousand links and one of them goes to
my webpage then I get one out of a thousand and if
Georgia Tech's front page has five links and one of those is to Kishore,
then Kishore gets one-fifth of a citation.
And in general if a page Y has these many outgoing links,
then each webpage is going to get one over the number of outgoing links of a citation.
So Georgia Tech's faculty list webpage has a thousand links let's say,
so I'm going to get one over thousand of a citation.
This webpage has five links, one to kishore's,
so kishore is going to get one-fifth of a citation.