So we've got a web page X.
We're going to look at the In neighbors.
So these are the web pages Y which have a link to X.
So we're going to sum over these.
The old scheme just counted the number of these In neighbors.
So the old scheme you can view it as a sum over the in
neighbors and we get plus one for each in neighbor.
In the new scheme, we want to scale it by number of
outgoing links from each of these web pages.
So if Y1 has a lot of outgoing links, let's say it has 1000,
then this link is going to give us one over 1000.
And if this web page has only one link to X,
then this one gives us one.
And in general, from a web page Y,
we're going to get one over the number of out links from Y.
And we're going to sum this up over the Ys which have a link to X.