So here's our current proposed solution.
So instead of setting the rank of the page X to be the number of in neighbors,
the number of links into X,
we've scaled each of those links by the number of out neighbors from that page y.
Now there are some obvious problems with this let's look at one example.
Let's suppose that my kids made a web page
and it has only one link on it, to my web page.
So under this count, I get one citation for it and now let's look at CNN web page.
They probably have many links on their web page but perhaps they have an article about
Kishore's awesome new research and they have a link to Kishore's web page.
So if they have 100 links,
Kishore is going to get one over a hundredth of
a citation here whereas I'm going to get one citation.
Now this doesn't seem very fair because CNN's web page is very important.
So we should scale this citation from CNN based on the importance of CNN's web page.
So instead of a web page having one citation to give out
the web pages should have PI it's rank to give out.
So CNN should have Pi of CNN its rank,
that's how many citations it has to give out
or that's the worth of its citations to give out.
Now we can scale each of those citations as we did
before based on how many links CNN has.
So CNN has 1000 links in each of these web pages which has a link from it,
is going to get one over thousands of CNN's worth.
So CNN total citation value is Pi over CNN,
that's its rank and then each web page that has a link from it,
is going to get one over thousands of that worth, the recommendation value.
So a citation from a more important web page,
has more value because it's going to be
proportional to the value the rank of the web page.