Let's look at this problem from a completely different perspective.
So we have the web graph G. The vertices are web pages and the edges are the hyperlinks.
These are directed edges.
Now let's do a random walk on this graph.
What exactly does that mean?
It's just like you're surfing the web.
So you write a web page,
you're going to follow a random hyperlink from that web page,
go to the next web page,
look at it for a second,
hit a random hyperlink and so on.
So we started at some web page say we're currently at web page X.
Then let's choose a random hyperlink,
so uniformly at random from all hyperlinks on this web page X and then we follow
that hyperlink and then we repeat the procedure from the new web page.
This is a random walk on the directed graph.
From a vertex, we're choosing a random outgoing edge.
So this is the Markov chain.
What's the transition matrix for this Markov chain?
Well for Web page Y has a hyperlink to a web page X,
so there's a direct edge from Y to X in this web graph.
Then the weight of this edge or in the transition matrix,
this entry YX is one over the number of out neighbors from Y.
The probability of following this particular link when we're at
web page Y is exactly one over the number of links at web page Y.
So if Y has a thousand links and
the probability of following this particular link is one over X.
And if web page Y doesn't have a link to web page X,
so there's no edge and this transition matrix is zero at that entry,
so this defines the transition matrix for this Markov chain.
Now this is the Markov chain.
So it has a stationary distribution.
What does this stationary distribution look like?