The input to the subset sum problem will consist of 2n plus 2m plus one numbers.
There are n variables and 2n literals,
so we'll have a number for each literal.
There are m clauses, so we'll have two numbers for each clause.
And then we'll have one additional number which is our desired sum.
We'll have V_1 and V_1 prime corresponding to X_1 and X_1 bar,
V_1 and V_2 prime for X_2 and X_2 bar.
And V_n and V_n prime for X_n and X_n bar.
We'll have these two additional numbers for the first clause,
and so on for the m clauses.
And finally, we'll have the desired sum.
Now these numbers are all huge.
They're going to be at most n plus m digits long.
And we're going to work in base 10.
This is so that if we add up any subset of numbers,
there'll be no carries between the digits.
Note these numbers are huge, for instance,
t is on the order of ten to the n plus m. This illustrates
why our order n times t algorithm is a somewhat terrible algorithm.