Now let's take a look at the actual specification of the input to the subset sum problem.
Let's start with these numbers corresponding to the two n literals,
in particular Vi corresponds to Xi.
So we're going to include this number Vi in the subset S,
if and only if the literal Xi is set to true.
Similarly Vi prime corresponds to Xi bar and will include
Vi prime in this subset S if and only if the variable Xi is set to false.
And assignment for the three set formula either sets Xi to true or Xi to false.
Therefore, we need for the subset sum problem that either we include
Vi in S or Vi prime in S. Well,
we can't include both and we can include neither,
because then we don't know how to set Xi.
So we need to ensure that exactly one of Vi or Vi prime is in S. How do we achieve this?
Well, in the Ith digit of these three numbers Vi,
Vi prime and T we put a one.
In all other numbers,
we put a zero in the Ith digit.
Now by using base 10,
we will ensure that there is no carrys between the digits.
So each digit is going to behave independently of each other.
Recall that T is our desire sum,
so the only way to achieve a desired sum that has a one in the Ith digit,
is to include either Vi or Vi prime in S,
but not both and not neither.
So this specification ensures that
our solution to the subset sum problem is going to correspond to an assignment.
Whether it's satisfying or not is another issue,
but for now at least we know that we have an assignment.
So either we're going to correspond to Xi being set to true or Xi being set.