What we've sketched so far and what we'll formally prove
now is that the subset sum instance that we constructed
has a solution if and only if the original 3SAT input is satisfiable.
It's going to prove that we did a value reduction.
Let's start with the forward direction.
Let's take a solution S to this subset sum instance.
So we know that if we sum up the numbers in S,
it sums up to exactly T. Let's first look at the first N digits.
These correspond to the N variables X1 through Xn.
We know that T has a one in digit I.
In order to get a one in digit I,
we have to include Vi or Vi prime in our subset S, but not both.
If we include both we get a two n digit i.
And if we include neither,
we get a sum of zero in digit i.
So the only way to get a sum of exactly 1 in digit
i is to include exactly one of Vi and Vi prime.
If we include Vi in our subset S,
then we set the variable Xi to true.
If we include Vi prime in our subset S then we set the variable Xi to false.
So from this solution to the subset sum problem, we get an assignment.
We get a true false assignment for the variables.
Why is this a satisfying assignment?
Well, to see that we'll look at the remaining digits.