Let's prove the reverse implication that a satisfying assignment for
the 3SAT formula corresponds to a solution to the subset-sum instance.
So let's take a satisfying assignment for f,
and we'll construct a solution to the subset-sum instance in the following manner.
In our satisfying assignment,
if we set the variable X to the ith to true,
then we add the number V to the ith to the solution S.
And if we set the variable X to the ith to false in our satisfying assignment,
then we add the number of V to the ith prime to our solution S. We're
adding exactly one of V to the ith and V to the ith prime to S. This means,
in the ith digit, we get exactly one.
So the ith digit of T is correct.
Now let's look at the jth clause.
We started from a satisfying assignment, therefore,
at least one of the literals in this clause is satisfied.
The numbers corresponding to these literals give us a sum of one, two,
or three in the digit n plus j. T has three in digit n plus j.
So how do we achieve a sum of three digit n plus j?
Well, using the numbers corresponding to these literals,
we get a sum of one, two, or three,
and then we can use S to the jth and/or S to the jth prime to get up to a sum of three.
This ensures that digit n plus j is correct and therefore,
the last m digits are correct and the first digits are correct.
And therefore, we have a solution to the subset-sum instance.
So we've proved this equivalence and we've proved that our reduction is correct.