Our first topic is dynamic programming.
This is one of my favorite topics to teach because it is extremely useful.
Students often have some trouble with it initially,
but with enough practice it will sink in and actually,
they will seem quite easy once you get the hang of it.
I'll do my best to show you how I solve dynamic programming problems.
And, from there the key to really mastering
dynamic programming is to do lots and lots of practice problems.
The homework is just a start.
Do additional problems from the textbook,
and from other algorithms textbooks,
and from other courses you can find on the web.
We'll start with the toy example,
computing Fibonacci numbers, to illustrate the basic idea of dynamic programming.
Then, we'll dive into a variety of
example problems to get a feel for the different styles of
DP algorithms;- Longest increasing subs sequence (LIS),
longest common subsequence (LCS) the classic Knapsack Problem,
chain matrix multiplication and finally,
we'll look at a few shortest path algorithms using DP.