Given an integer n, we're going to look at
an algorithm for generating the n Fibonacci number.
This will be a very simple algorithm,
but it will illustrate the idea of dynamic programming and then,
we'll look at dynamic programming in general;
the techniques for designing
a dynamic programming algorithm and we'll look at some more sophisticated examples.
Recall the Fibonacci numbers are the following sequence, 0, 1, 1,
2, 3, 5, 8,13,
21, 34 and so on.
There's a simple recursive formula that defines the Fibonacci numbers.
The first two numbers in the sequence are zero and one,
and then the n Fibonacci number is the sum of the previous two Fibonacci numbers.
We're going to take as input and non-negative integer n
and our goal is to output the nth Fibonacci number.
We want an efficient algorithm and therefore we're aiming
for a running time which is polynomial in n. Now,
the Fibonacci numbers are defined by this simple recursive formula.
Therefore, we might think a recursive algorithm is a natural algorithm for this problem.
Let's look at that natural algorithm,
that natural recursive algorithm and when then we'll