Let's take a look now, at the case when the last characters are different.
This the situation in our original example,
Xi is not equal to Yi, A is not equal to B.
Now in this case, when Xi is not equal to Yi,
the last character of the longest common subsequence can either be A or B,
or neither. Certainly, cannot be both.
Now suppose it's A. For example,
suppose this is the last character in The Long common subsequence.
And what we know about Yi B,
for B has nothing left to match with an X.
Therefore, we know the LCS does not include B Yi.
Similarly, if the last character is B says match with this B.
Then the LCS cannot include A,
because it has nothing left to match within Y.
The key point is that the longest common subsequence for this prefix of length i,
either does not include Xi or it does not include Yi or both.
So either Xi is dropped or Yi is dropped or both of them are dropped.
Now let's consider the three cases.
If both of them are dropped,
then we can simply take the longest common subsequence in this prefix of L(i-1).
So it's similar to the equal case except we don't get this plus one here.
Now what happens if just Xi is dropped?.
Well then we have a prefix of L(i-1) in X and a prefix of L(i) in Y.
So we have no way of looking this up in our table.
The solution to this sub problem is not in our table,
because the prefixes are of different length in X and Y.
And notice, even if we knew how Yi is matched up with an X, for instance,
if we knew this B was match with this B,
then we have a prefix of Length 3 and X and we have a prefix of length 6 and y.
So there's still a different length.
And similarly, if Yi is not included,
So we dropped this last character from Y then we have prefix of
length 7 in X and a prefix of length 6 in Y.
So the prefixes are of different length in X and Y.
And once again, the solution to this sub problem is not
in our table because these prefixes are on a different length.
So for this case where where Yi is dropped,
we need to look up the longest common subsequence in
the prefix of L(i) in X with the prefix of L(i-1) in Y.
Now this isn't in our table presently and similarly when we try to solve this problem,
well then we might chop off the last character from
Y and then we get even shorter prefixes in length Y.
So for this sub problem definition,
we are unable to define a recurrence.
We are unable to express L(i) in terms of smaller sub problems,
but we got some insight about what is a valid.
What is a good sub problem definition.
The difficulty here was that the prefixes are of the same length for x and y,
but we need to allow them to be of different lengths.
So how do we achieve that?.
We're going to change from a single parameter i to a pair of parameters i and j. I
will correspond to the length of
the prefix X and j will correspond to the length of the prefix Y.
And, our table will now be a two dimensional table.
So L(i) J will be the length of the longest common subsequence in
X1 through Xi with Y1 through Yj.
And then, we're going to try all possibilities for i and j.