So let's recap our recurrence for the case where X_i equals Y_j,
the last characters are the same and the two prefixes.
Here, we have three possibilities
and we're going to take the best of the three, therefore, we take the max.
We have L of i minus one j,
which corresponds to dropping X_i, L of i,
j minus one which corresponds to dropping Y_j or we include X_i,
Y_j the common character at the end and we get a plus one for that,
and then we take the optimal solution to this smaller sub problem L of i minus one,
j minus one, we take the max of these three.
Some of you may have noticed that in fact,
the recurrence, in this case,
can be simplified even further.
We only need to consider the last case,
where we append on X_i,
Y_j the common character onto the end.
Let me give you some brief intuition about why that's the case.
Notice, if this solution doesn't include either of these characters,
then we can just add them on and we get a longer.
So, therefore, it wasn't optimal length.
So it's got to include either X_i or Y_j.
Now, it may be the case that X_i
is matched with some earlier recurrence of that character.
In this case, it's Y_1,
but any solution which we obtain by
matching X_i with an earlier recurrence of that character,
we could have obtained Y instead matching X_i with this latter solution.
Any sub sequence which occurs in that smaller prefix of Y,
also is a sub sequence in this larger prefix of Y, okay?
It's a super sign of it.
Therefore, we only need to consider this case and we get
this simpler recurrence for this case where they're equal, okay?
And this completes our definition of the recurrence.