Finally, let's take a look at the running time of our algorithm.
The two base cases are each order one per
step and then they are in order n sized for loop.
Therefore, they take order n total time.
Then we have a for loop of size order n and a nested for loop
of a size order n and inside it takes order one time.
So the total time is order n square with these nested for
loops and the total run time of our algorithm is dominated by the order n square,
so we get order n square total time.
This completes the dynamic programming algorithm
for the longest common subsequence problem.
The interesting thing that arose in this solution was that we
needed to use a two dimensional table.
This came about because we needed to consider prefixes
of x of different length than prefixes of y.