The input to this problem is a_1 through a_n.
Our goal is to find the contiguous sub-sequence.
Noticed, that a contiguous subsequence is the same as a substring,
and we want to find the substring with maximum sum.
Now, the first step is to define the subproblem in words.
I'm going to try the same problem on a prefix of the input.
So, we have a parameter i,
which is the length of the prefix.
So, we have an i, and this is going to vary between zero and n. And now,
I'm going to find s of i,
in words, first off.
It's going to be the max sum that I can obtain.
The same format as the original problem.
But, instead of considering the whole input,
and I'm going to consider the first i numbers.
So, it's a max sum from a substring of a_1 through a_i.
So it's the first i characters of the input.
Now, we want to try to find a recurrence relation,
we want to express s of i in terms of s_1 through s_i minus one, smallest subproblems.
Let's take s of i minus one,
is the max sum that we can obtain from a substring of a_1 through a_i minus one.
So, let's take that sum.
Now, there's two possibilities that I would consider.
Either, or add on, a_i on to the end of it or not.
First off, can I add on a_i on to the end of this solution?
Well, I have to maintain that it's a substring, that is contiguous.
I don't know where this one ends, so,
I don't know whether I can add on a_i unto the end of this solution.
So, I need to know where this one ends.
With this current definition, there's no way,
I don't know how to express s of i in terms of the smaller subproblems.
But I notice, that if I knew where this solution ended at,
so, if it included a of i minus one,
then, I know that if it includes
a_i minus one then I can add on a_i and maintain that it's a substring.
So, I have to go back and strengthen my subproblem definition.