In this lecture we're going to talk about hashing and we're
going to describe a popular technique called bloom filters.
Before we get into hashing,
we're going to talk about a toy problem, balls into bins.
We are going to throw balls randomly into a set of bins.
We'll do some simple probabilistic analysis of
this problem and this will give us some intuition about the design of hashing schemes.
One of the neat ideas we're going to see with the balls and bin's problems,
is the power of two choices.
This is going to motivate some of our more sophisticated hashing schemes.
After we look at the toy problem balls into bins,
then we'll look at the traditional hashing scheme; chain hashing.
And then we'll look at our more sophisticated scheme, bloom filters.
So let's dive into the balls into bins.