For this toy problem,
we have n balls,
which are identical to each other,
and we have n bins,
which we'll label B1, B2, up through Bn.
Each ball is thrown into a random bin,
and this is done independent of the other bins.
Now, what we're going to do for this toy problem,
is we're going to throw each ball into a random bin.
Now, the process for each ball is independent of what happened for the other balls.
We want to look at the number of balls that are assigned to each bin.
Therefore, we look at the random variable load_of_i,
which is the number of balls assigned to bin i.
What we're interested in is the maximum load.
This is the maximum number of balls in any particular bin.
In other words, the max load is the max_over_i of the load of bin i.
How large can the max load get?
Well, in the worst case,
all of the balls might get assigned to the same bin.
But, what's the chance of that? It's quite small.
I mean, what's the chance of all n balls being assigned to bin B1, let's say.
The probability of one particular ball being assigned to bin B1 is one_over_n.
What's the chance that all n balls get assigned to this particular bin?
It's one_over_n_to_the_n.
This is really tiny,
so this is very unlikely.
In the worst case, the max load could be n because of such a scenario.
But what is the typical scenario?
How large is the max load typically?
That's what we want to analyze now.
We want to make a statement such as,
with high probability, the max load is,
some quantity, such as square root n,
log n, order one.
So, let's dive in and see what the max load is in a typical scenario.