Now, the solution is one_over_n_to_the_log_n.
Why is that? Let's look at it more closely.
Take a particular ball j.
What is the probability that this ball is assigned to this particular bin Bi?
Well, the ball is going to a randomly chosen bin,
so the chance of going to any particular bin is one_over_n.
Therefore, the first ball has probability one_over_n of being assigned to bin Bi.
The second ball, same,
has a probability one_over_n of being assigned to bin Bi,
and so on for all these log_n balls.
So the probability that all of them are assigned to bin Bi
is the product of one_over_n, for each.
So, the total probability is one_over_n raised to the power log.