Now, let's look at the following twist on the balls and bins problem.
This is going to be a better approach,
better in the sense that it's going to reduce the max load.
Now, in the previous balls and bins problem,
each ball was going to a random bin and it was
independent of the assignment for the other balls.
Therefore, we could have assigned all the balls simultaneously, in parallel.
They could have all been assigned to bins at the same time,
or we could assign them one by one, sort of sequentially.
So, we could have taken ball one and assigned it to a random bin,
take ball two, assign to a random bin,
and so on, up to ball n. That's what we're going to do here.
We're going to assign the balls sequentially,
and we're going to look at a slight twist of the other scheme.
So, let's go through the balls from one through n,
index i will correspond to the current ball that we're considering.
In the old scheme, we choose one random bin say j,
and we assigned the i ball to bin bj.
Now, in the new scheme what we're going to do is,
we're going to choose two random bins,
say j and k. Now,
which bin are we going to assign the ith ball?
Well we're going to assign it to the better of these two bins.
What exactly do we mean?
We mean the one which has smaller load.
So, let load of j and load of k
denote the current load in these particular bins bj and bk,
and we're going to assign this ith ball to the least loaded of these two.
So if the load of bj is structurally smaller than the load of bk,
then we assign the ith ball to bin bj.
And in the other case, we assign the ith ball to bin bk.
So, the ith ball is going to the least loaded of these two bins.