what we're gonna do now is instead of
using a single hash function we're going
to choose a pair of hash functions H 1
and H 2 each of these hash tables Maps
elements of U of our possible passwords
into our hash table of size n now we're
assume that these hash functions are
random so each element acts in the
universe of possible passwords maps to a
random element of the hash table H 1 of
X is random in each two of X are random
and these are independent of each other
and independent of the other hash values
the first question is how do we insert
an element a possible password into our
dictionary of unacceptable passwords in
the traditional scheme this is quite
straightforward what we do is we look at
our hash function and we look at H of X
that tells us the hash value and now we
looked at the linked list at H of X and
we add element acts onto that linked
list but now we have two hash functions
H 1 and H 2 so how do we do this
insertion into our dictionary in this
scenario when we have two hash functions
this is a bit of an open-ended question
but why don't you think about how you
would insert an element into our
dictionary using two hash functions