let's go ahead and look at how we do
this insertion we want to insert this
element X into our dictionary of
unacceptable passwords first thing we do
is compute these two hash values so we
compute H 1 of X and H 2 of X think of
our balls and bins analogy we have this
ball ax and what we've done is we've
chosen two random bins H 1 of X and H 2
of X which bin do we add the ball ax
into we added into the least loaded at
all of these two bins what is the load
of the bin it's the size of the linked
list we can maintain the size of each of
these linked lists so that we can
quickly determine which of these two is
least loaded and then we can add in X
into that appropriate linked list and
then we can increment the size of that
linked list so this can all be done in
order one time for an insertion next
question is how do we do a query how do
we check whether an element Y up
proposed password Y is in our dictionary
of unacceptable passwords we start off
the same as an assertion we compute the
two hash values H one of Y and H 2 of Y
these are the two possible locations for
Y we have no way of determining which of
these two locations it might be in if at
all because we have no way of
determining what the dictionary looked
like at the time that we inserted Y if
we did insert Y so what do we do we
check both bins we check the linked list
at h1 of Y and we check the linked list
at h2 of Y and we look for Y in both of
these linked lists so we check the
linked list at H of H 1 of Y and we
check the linked list at H of H 2 of Y
and we look in both of these linked
lists for the element Y if it's in
either of these linked lists then we
know that Y is in the dictionary
if it's in either of these linked lists
then we know that Y was never inserted
into a dictionary of unacceptable
passwords so how long does it take to do
a query or the query time now depends on
the load at this location and the load
at this location so if we have an upper
bound on the maximum load then the query
time is twice the maximum load now if M
equals n so the size of our date
dictionary of unacceptable passwords and
the size of our hash table are the same
then what we know from our balls and
pinion analogy is that the query time
the max
load is gonna be order log log and in
this scenario so just changing from one
hash function to a pair of hash
functions and using this scheme then our
query time goes down dramatically from
order log n to order log log n and
there's no extra cost in terms of the
space though there is a question about
how we maintain this hash function H
especially if it's a truly random hash
function in practice we can't store a
truly random hash function instead we
use pseudo random hash functions so we
use a hash function which we obtain from
a library such as ran or D ran 48 but
for the purposes as an analysis it's
convenient to consider a truly random
hash function so that we can do this
nice analysis such as how we obtain the
order log and max load for the M equals
n case for the simple case of one hash
function we skipped the analysis for the
case of the balls and bins example where
we did the two choices where we had each
ball going to the best of two random
bins in that case we we claimed that the
max load is order log log n that
analysis is reasonable to do but it's
much more complicated so we skipped it
in this lecture