What are the basic operations that our data structure is going to support?
First operation is insert x.
So given a possible password X,
we want to add this password into our dictionary of unacceptable passwords.
The second operation is a query on X,
is this proposed password in our dictionary of unacceptable passwords?
If this proposed password is in our dictionary of unacceptable passwords,
then we're always going to output YES,
so we're always correct in this case.
The problem is that, when this proposed password is not in our dictionary,
so it is an acceptable password,
we usually output NO and we have to bound what we mean by usually.
But occasionally, we're going to output YES.
So when in this proposed password is acceptable,
occasionally we're going to have a false positive and say
YES it is in the dictionary of unacceptable passwords,
so this password is not allowed.
So we have false positives with
some small rate and we have to bound that rate and see what it looks like.