So now we have k hash functions instead of just one,
h1, h2, up to hk.
We're going to initialize our hash table at H,
capital H to all zeroes.
So all of the bits, the n bits of H are set to zero.
How do we do an insertion?
How do we add an element X?
A possible password into our dictionary S of unacceptable passwords.
Previously we computed this hash value H of X and we set that bit to 1.
What are we going to do now?
Now we compute the K hash values and we set all of those K bits to 1.
So we go through the hash functions 1 through K,
and then we compute it's I'th hash value,
and we set this bit to 1.
It might already be 1 as before,
but we always change bits from 0 to 1 just like before. How do we do a query?
How do we check whether an element X was inserted into our dictionary S?
Well, we compute it's K hash values and we check
whether all of those K bits are set to 1 or not.
If all of those K bits are set to 1,
then our best guess is that X was inserted into
the database S. If any of those are still 0,
then we're guaranteed that X was not inserted into the database.
So let's write that out more precisely.
If for all of those K hash values
the hash function at those K bits is set to 1, then we output yes.
We believe that this element X is in the database S.
If any of these K bits is still 0,
then we're guaranteed that this element X is not in the database. So we output no.